Forty meters down. Forty-five to go.
With half a body length lead, Araki's in good form
as he comes up on the fifty meter turn.
Huh? Wasn't this guy fencing a minute ago?
Why's he swimming?
It's the modern pentathlon.
Shooting, fencing, swimming, equestrian,
and running. Five events in all.
"Penta" means five.
The triathlon is swimming, cycling, and marathon, right?
The one I don't get is biathlon.
What's in that one again?
Skiing and shooting.
What's not to get?
In a triathlon, all the events
have one general theme: speed.
In the modern pentathlon, it's like
you're fighting with your gun and your sword,
and getting around the battlefield
by running, swimming and horse-riding.
It's kind of a bloody event
when you think about it.
But it's easy to imagine.
I see what you mean.
With two events, you can do whatever.
It's a Winter Olympics event,
so you've got to keep skiing,
but why not pair it with playing cards,
or frisbee, or snuggling in the warmth?
Do you want them to fall asleep?
On Knight Scoop the other day,
they combined shogi with boxing.
Wow, sounds hard.
But think about it.
If you cut shooting from the biathlon,
they're going to have to run to make up for it.
That is to say, if you try and fail to bring down a bear,
you'd better be ready to run.
We're being watched...
A bear's stalking us!
They weren't there last episode!
Wh-Who forgot to put the hina dolls away?!
We'll be cursed to spinsterhood!
What the hell have you guys done?!
If you forget to put away the dolls...
You're cursed to hypothermic doom!
Do you want to die on a mountain somewhere?
No, it's "to die an old bride".
Marry late? That's hardly any different!
We're done for...
We're never gonna get married,
and freeze to death all alone!
We don't stand a snowball's chance in hell!
C'mon, guys. Let's just think it over calmly over some tea.
I'll go prepare some!
Cursed to be an *ld maid forever!
I knew we had some matcha powder here.
M*ld maid.
Is that a real thing?
Of course not!
It's her!
The M*ld Maid!
She really does exist!
No! This is just matcha powder!
Stay back before she infects
you with spinsterhood!
Meanie!
O Gods, protect me from this horror!
I'll turn you into one of us!
Our adorable Kigu's been possessed!
We've all been infected!
We really are done for now!
We're done for!
Wait. There's still a way out.
We have to all become delinquents.
Huh? Why?
Isn't it obvious?
They get married early, without exception.
Without. Exception.
You're right!
Bad kids get married early!
My neighbour, Ku, is a real bad sort,
and she got married at fifteen!
Even though you can't get married until sixteen?
She's the real deal.
You mean...
Yes, exactly.
The M*ld Maid infection and
the delinquency cancel each other out.
I see!
But you can't just become
a delinquent out of nowhere!
Marii!
We beg of you.
Please!
Teach us your ways!
Why me?!
I ain't no bloody delinquent and I never have been!
Just be our boss!
B-Boss?
That has a certain wonderful ring to it...
Marii had always liked the sound of the word "boss".
Boss.
Boss...
Boss!
What?!
She's into it now.
Well, what do you do? For starters,
c'mere and squat down, you bunch of lowlifes.
We're already here!
How are we going to become delinquents?
We'll start with your looks!
We really look the part!
Look!
Omelet... and rice?
Oh, right. They love using fancy typography to spell stuff.
Yup, and we've already made it.
Check it out.
Marii Buratei.
Tetora Bouhatei.
Gankyou Kuurubiyuutei.
Kigurumi Haroukitei.
Kukuru Anrakutei.
And that's only the beginning.
From now on, we'll only be using
fancy fonts and styling when speaking.
In that case, forget words and focus on action.
We'll go to school at night and clean the windows!
Clean the windows?
Delinquents clean windows!
We don't only do bad.
I was wondering, are there
any legends among delinquents?
Legends?
Yes! Delinquents have lots of legends!
She's into it again.
Legends as cool as the Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time?
Or the Legend of the Galactic Heroes?
They're not gonna be that awesome.
Delinquents aren't really on the "galactic" level.
More like the "local" level.
What about Lunar Legend Tsukihime?
Or the legend of King Arthuria?
These people exist in opposition
to the forces of crazy fandoms.
Their legends don't hold a candle to ours.
Right, I'm gonna create the Legend of Marii!
Long ago, there was a cross-dressing boy called Gold Marii.
Gold Marii spent every day lying around and doing nothing.
Fin.
That's folktale!
Folktales and fairy tales can get a little surreal sometimes.
That was more than surreal!
No story, no punchline, no point.
Legends are legends,
and folktales are a collection of legends.
You're looking for delinquent-style legends, right?
What about this?
At your part-time job, you and a friend quietly...
No! That's out of line!
My blog would blow up!
I'd get doxxed!
They'd call the school about it!
Even if we become delinquents,
there's no guarantee we'll get married early.
Think of it another way.
This room is a box.
So the dolls are already put away.
Wow. You're smart.
So we've been put away too.
We're kept women!
Kept women?
Marii liked the sound of being a kept woman.
Phew, that time already?
Time to go home.
We missed the last train.
Marii, you staying here?
Kept women don't leave their humble abodes.
Oh. I see.
Don't just barge in!
At least knock!
Marii, a kept woman and a shut-in
are not the same thing.
It's like a surreal take on a hina doll.
Still no Emperor doll to go with her, though.
Tsukiji fish market!
Fish!
Tuna!
She certainly is cheerful.
We artists are late risers.
Early mornings don't agree with me.
Help! Kukuru isn't breathing!
So... tired...
If you fall asleep, you'll die!
If sleeping means death, keep your eyes open!
Live tuna! Live tuna!
I wanna eat live tuna!
Marii, a bluefin tuna weighs at least four hundred kilos.
And costs at least a million yen.
Then I'll rip it apart with my bare hands! Live on stage!
Ocean-caught fish are flash-frozen at minus sixty degrees.
Catchy catchy fishy fishy!
The more you catch the cheaper it gets!
She's annoying.
As annoying as those foreign tourists who barge into
the fish auctions, mess with the wares, and take pictures.
Yeah, that really gets my goat.
I wanna go at them with a t*na cleaver.
If there were any justice,
they'd get the Tsesarevich-Otsu treatment.
That'd cause an international incident!
Woohoo! Come to mama, tuna!
Has Marii even slept since yesterday?
So that's why she's so highly strung.
But rules are rules!
These auctions are what the market's all about.
The old guys have such hoarse voices.
One of the top three gravelly voices.
Three? What are the other two?
It's obvious!
Ticket scalpers
and His Excellency Rozen!
Note:
Former Prime Minister Taro Aso,
who was reportedly seen reading
"Rozen Maiden" at an airport.
Really? Unbelievable!
Their gestures are pretty cool, too.
One of the top three gestures.
What are the other two?
Rappers
and old men offering to buy their colleagues a drink at a bar.
Yeah, the older guys who work here are kind of cool.
Look! An electric truck!
Awesome!
Watch out!
Don't fall in love!
Don't let it lead you astray
or give you the wrong idea!
Winter ski slopes, summer beaches,
school uniforms, and electric trucks!
Indeed. She's right.
When you come back to the drab old city,
that guy never looks as hot as he did
on the slopes or at the beach.
Or when he changes out of his uniform
and his normal clothes are beyond unfashionable.
Or when he steps off the electric truck
and he's just some old guy.
He's still some old guy even on the truck.
There's no doubt about that.
Those trucks are great. I understand wanting to ride one.
You need a full license to drive one.
What, surely a scooter license is enough?
Not for 50cc's!
I'd love to drive something like
a Lamborghini Countach LP 500S,
or maybe a De Tomaso Panthera
or a Porsche Carrera 2 Turbo.
There's something about supercars.
I'd prefer one of those lifting hoists.
Laughing ghosts?
A crane like they use to build apartment blocks.
You'd get chills up there.
Oh, right.
Yeah, I bet the breeze is really refreshing!
I'd get chills thinking about what
they'd do if I dropped an iron bar on them.
Th-That's chilly...
More like cold.
What about you, Kigu?
Me? I wanna drive a Merc!
I want to go to a theme park and pay
a hundred yen to ride the panda bear!
Cutie-pie!
That's our Kigu!
Ugh, I'm sick of playing into their expectations of me.
Apparently a thousand grams of bonito flakes
costs seven thousand yen.
That's why people come here.
You wouldn't normally buy one kilogram
of bonito flakes. You couldn't!
Hup, there we go.
But she is.
Hm? Don't think you're getting any.
How many cats do you own?
They just looked good. I couldn't help myself.
Big changes are coming to the Outer Market.
Oh, because of the move to Toyosu?
I'm way too used to "Tsukiji Market".
"Toyosu Market" just sounds weird.
The big fish market wasn't in Tsukiji originally.
It was at Nihonbashi.
It moved due to the Great Kanto Earthquake.
Last time was tectonics, this time it's politics.
Ah! A T-shirt with "Tuna" on it!
The kanji for that is written with "fish" and "exist".
Maybe that's to show how important it is...
Yeah! Like, you'd never have a word
with "fish" and "doesn't exist," right?
But you could use that to mean
"glass catfish", couldn't you?
What's that?
An aquarium fish that's completely
transparent apart from its bones.
If you use "illusion", it should mean "baby eel".
Where they're born is a long-standing mystery.
Apparently, they've even caught them
in the Mariana Trench.
Aristotle wrote that they're born spontaneously from mud.
Then they should use the symbol for "mud"!
I've no idea why eel uses "wide".
What about just writing out "blue".
That's how Mister explained the kanji for "mackerel".
Note:
Shigeo Nagashima, a very famous
baseball player and manager.
Blue?! In English?!
Japanese not good enough, eh?
Well, that's Mister's shtick.
You could combine "person"
and "strange" to get "Mister".
Or "person" and "super"!
"Exceed" would work too.
Marii would be "person" and "butt".
What're you trying to say?!
"Person" and "thin skin"? "Delinquent"?
Both of those suck!
Kigu, you'd be "person" and "pure".
Oh, yay!
I think "cutie" would work too.
I'm so happy! I'll work hard to be pure and cute!
Ugh, I'm so sick of playing into their expectations of me.
Kukuru would be "person" and...
"Pain" for sure.
Huh?
That's cool!
Born into a poor family, abused, neglected,
sent out to pick pockets on the street,
protective custody, drop out,
teenage pregnancy, get married,
domestic violence, poisoning, arrest, divorce, illness!
Talk about a sob story!
It's like you're trying to win a TV talent show!
Do me, do me! "Circle"?
What about "eight"?
"Person" plus "eight"?
"Person" plus eight. The numeral.
Just because of the glasses?
Even better, an infinity symbol!
That's just eight on its side!
What about me, I wonder?
You're pretty neutral...
"Person" plus a square.
A square?
Then you can put whatever you like in it.
Like "rose", "azure", or "azalea".
Seems a bit unfinished.
Forget unfinished, I'm famished!
Let's get some lunch.
What do you fancy? Sushi?
Or some kind of set menu?
When you come to Tsukiji, it's gotta be Yoshinoya!
Huh? Beef bowl? Not fish?
The first Yoshinoya was established here in Tsukiji.
Sounds good to me.
Look! The promised land!
Hey, wait for me!
What's wrong, Kukuru?
The manager just chewed me out.
He said the electricity bill for the backstage room
was unbelievably high last month.
Are there even that many appliances
in here that eat up electricity?
Well, maybe there are, but I don't get why
he'd suddenly care about it now.
Save electricity, okay?
There's no excuse for wasting it!
It's unkind to Mother Earth!
We're gonna search high and low to find the cause!
That reminds me, I was thinking...
Isn't the floor strangely warm?
Now that you mention it...
It's gotta be underfloor heating!
Leaving it on all the time is bad!
Even though they're tatami mats?
Only one way to find out!
No underfloor heating, then.
Nope.
Nothing unusual there.
Um... I have the feeling there actually
was something unusual down there.
Something that uses electricity?
Uh, no, but...
Then there was nothing unusual.
Um, but...
Stop fussing about trivial things!
We gotta focus on the electricity bill!
Yeah! That's what's important!
Otherwise it'll be rolling blackouts!
Price increases! Shareholder lawsuits!
Oh, I see.
That reminds me, there have been
voices coming from the walls recently.
From the walls?
Voices?
Oh! There must be speakers hidden in the walls!
Like JBL or Tannoy?
Leaving music on all the time is bad!
Only one way to find out!
No speakers, then.
Nope.
Nothing unusual there.
Um, didn't you notice anything unusual there?
Something that uses electricity?
No, nothing that uses electricity, but...
Right, then there was nothing unusual.
Uh, um, I mean—
Can't these guys see anything
but what they're focused on?
That reminds me.
The ceiling's been shaking recently.
Shaking?
Maybe someone's using a massage chair on the other side.
These days, massage chairs massage everything,
from your shoulders to your back,
from your calves to your arms.
So they use a lot of electricity.
Only one way to find out!
No massage chair, then.
Nope.
Nothing unusual there.
I feel like there might have been
a mortal danger lurking in the ceiling...
Something that uses electricity?
Uh, no, but...
Right, then there was nothing unusual.
Um, but...
So there weren't any electrical appliances
under the floor, in the walls, or in the ceiling.
Then that means the problem must be in the room.
Which means...
Your glasses!
What's wrong with 'em?
They act like a scouter, consuming a
supercomputer's worth of electricity, right?
Don't be stupid!
Why would I need a scouter to confirm
that your power level is basically zero?
When it comes to saving electricity,
every little bit helps.
How is that even relevant?
By the way, guys.
Don't you reckon saving electricity is a bit unambitious?
Rather than cutting down how much we use,
shouldn't we instead focus on generating more?
It's a human-powered generator!
Who's gonna ride it?
Marii, right?
Definitely Marii.
It was Marii's idea.
Oh, fine! I'll do it!
You miss one hundred percent of the volts you don't make!
Is this really producing electricity?
There's a socket...
It's weaker than a bicycle light.
Less power than an AA battery.
Saw that coming.
Agh... that hurt...
Crap!
If we don't patch this up,
the manager'll be even angrier with us!
Um... Wasn't that some kinda human-shaped thing there?
What's that got to do with generating electricity?
Your method isn't enough for modern times.
There are more efficient and high-tech solutions.
Solar and wind aren't working at all.
Well, ofcourse. We're inside.
The sun's out of the question,
but can't we get some wind going?
Wind makes me think of...
At that moment, the wind blew.
They say the wind blows when
fated lovers meet for the first time!
Yeah!
And that's not all!
They say that when you have
an instant connection with someone...
there's electricity!
Yeah!
So to create electricity,
we need to create encounters.
Welcome!
Come in, come in! We have lots of pretty girls!
It's working! I can practically
feel the electricity in the air!
Police! Nobody move!
We received a tip-off that there were
unlicensed indecent activities going on here!
Indecent? We're just trying to
make a little electricity here!
You're digging yourself deeper!
Stop being so obstinate!
Wh-What on earth...
So it was you who used all that electricity, Kigu.
But... what?
It feels good to solve that mystery.
Yeah. I'm glad.
Hopefully the manager won't get mad at us again.
But...
It was just the robot.
At that moment, the real Kigu was asleep
at home, dreaming of electric sheep.
Two's enough... please understand...
Kukuru Anrakutei here.
Summer is the season of love,
and fall is the season of sports.
What kind of season would you say winter is?
It's the season of broken hearts and injuries.
Better to stay indoors and stay safe.
Winter is the season of hibernation.
Rakugo Girls episode 8 includes:
"Bag of Gold", "Unsteady", and "Is It Over Yet?"