"Teddy, where were you?"
"I took a puzzle and sat on the street waiting for you."
"What? I told you to wait with the bamboo seller!"
"Oh, I thought you said 'with a bamboozler'."
Thanks for your continued appreciation.
Have...
a good...
year...
everybo...
...dy.
It's a running gag at this point,
so I'll just keep quiet.
Thanks.
You'd better not pull this crap at Valentine's.
Happy new year!
So, what was everyone's first dream of the year?
Don't ask such dull—
Don't ask such horrible questions!
I just wanted to relive the good old times, and yet...
What's horrible about it?
I haven't had one yet.
I haven't been able to sleep since New Year's Eve.
I haven't had a New Year's dream yet!
Oh, really?
You go ahead and discuss your dreams!
Leave me out because I didn't have one!
Oh yeah, I bet you all had breathtaking dreams!
I didn't realise she had such an inferiority complex.
Maybe 'cuz she hasn't slept.
A-All right then, Kukuru.
Why don't you sleep here?
Okay, just close your eyes...
We'll sing you a lullaby.
Go to sleep... go to sleep...
I feel like I'm being cursed.
Sorry! We'll stop.
Here's a life hack for ya!
You count one lamb, two lambs, three lambs...
Surely "sheep" would work a lot better for that.
"Sheep" and "sleep" sound very similar,
so it's like you're hypnotising yourself to sleep.
Okay then, just say "sheep one, sheep two".
Shouldn't they be plural?
What's the plural of sheep?
To make something plural in English,
you just slap on an s at the end.
The plural of "sheep" is "sheep".
For freaking real?
Sheep are treated as a flock,
so the noun is uncountable.
Have they never seen a sheep on its own?
I can't sleep with all this noise.
O-Okay, we'll try to keep it down.
I may not be able to sleep, but I see
that isn't stopping you all from having fun.
I-I'm sorry...
You early dreamers go ahead and enjoy yourselves.
The only thing I get to have is this unending torment!
As the year turned, the old stray that
used to visit every day stopped coming by.
My father suddenly announced that he
was going to get a licence for dealing antiques,
seemingly convinced he was
going to be laid off from his company.
My grandmother started wearing more
and more make-up, often leaving the house.
It wasn't uncommon for her to stay out all night.
In the end, a white Republican man who claimed to
have been an acquaintance of my mother's
invited us to go live with him in Oregon.
The start of the year brings nothing but pain!
I just want to dream!
Is that so much to ask?
That's enough drama for one of those cellphone novels.
Whatever happened to those?
Don't worry! Even people with insomnia
don't go that long without sleeping.
Really?
You get people who say they haven't slept in five days,
but usually they dozed off a little without realising it.
You're right.
If your insomnia persists, things get hazy
and you stop being able to tell
where dreams end and reality begins.
I wish it had all been a dream!
The cat, my father, my grandmother, and Oregon!
Geez. This is getting tiresome.
What if this is all a dream?
Being backstage, being turned into an anime...
It could be, you know!
Now that you mention it, that bamboo ornament
that crashed through the wall was too big to be realistic.
Right?
Hey now, this is definitely reality.
If you say stuff like that,
you're setting yourself up for—
I've got an idea!
We'll give Kukuru her first dream of the year!
I suddenly feel like this might be a dream!
She's no longer able to tell
the difference between dreams and reality.
We can make sure she has a wonderful dream!
This is definitely a dream!
Now's our chance!
We're going to put on a dream play.
We're backstage now.
A backstage inside the backstage.
Like a dream within a dream!
Let's act out an amazing New Year's dream
and make Kukuru happy again!
What makes a good New Year's dream?
They say the three luckiest things to see in your dreams are,
in order: Mt. Fuji, a hawk, and an eggplant.
This is so lucky.
This is so lucky!
S-Scary... So scary!
I've never had such a terrifying dream in my whole life!
Terrifying?!
These are all really good omens!
We've got Mt. Fuji, a hawk, an eggplant...
But...
Even in a dream, it's too unrealistic for Mt. Fuji,
a hawk, and an eggplant to appear together!
I see...
...what you mean.
Intermission!
What are we gonna do?
She's right. She was never gonna buy that
all three would appear in a dream at once.
I've never had a New Year's dream
with those three things in it!
I doubt anybody has.
If there are only three signs, you could go
your whole life without having a lucky dream.
So what's the plan?
We should start at fourth place
and do the top ten!
What could possibly be worse than an eggplant?
There's only one thing it can be.
Time for the second act!
Continuing from number three, eggplant...
Four: green pepper!
Five: carrot!
Six: broccoli!
This is just a list of all the veggies you hate!
Grow up, you toddler!
I thought it went fan, tobacco, blind masseur...
Oh, really?
A fan spreads out wide, and the smoke
from tobacco rises up like your fortunes.
And the blind masseur?
Because he has no hair, not a hair
on your head will be harmed.
Oh.
So what are we going to do next?
We went from animals to plants,
so next we need something even lower than that.
What the hell?!
I'm just gonna borrow your belt!
Nooo!
Following on from broccoli...
Seven: chloroplasts!
Eight: mitochondria!
Nine: nuclei!
Ten: Golgi apparatus!
This is so lucky! So lucky!
This is scary!
I feel like I'm going to get sick!
Then what should we do?
Below a cell comes...
Eleven: vanadium!
Twelve: calcium!
Thirteen: potassium!
Ah, this seems really nice and healthy!
Fourteen: caesium!
Fifteen: strontium!
Sixteen: plutonium!
You wanna see
what comes after sixteen?
Please stop...
What are you up to, Marii?
N-Nothing...
In you go, then. Into Almond!
It's so pink, though. It's embarrassing!
What are you talking about?
You can't come to Roppongi
and not go to Almond!
The pink symbolises colour blooming
in the heart of the barren city!
That's why they chose it!
Is... Is that true?
I mean, maybe.
Almond was the first place in Japan
to give out warm towels to customers.
Precisely! This is the birthplace of
one of Japan's greatest dining traditions!
Amen.
Can we just go in already?
Oh, sure.
Sorry we're late!
We're all here. Shall we head out?
After all that, we're not going in?!
What's that?!
It's huge!
Ten metres tall.
It's a spider?
She's got a name, you know.
She does?
She's called Maman.
Maman?
Stand directly underneath her.
She's carrying eggs in that sac beneath her abdomen.
This is a famous Roppongi meeting place,
like Hachiko in Shibuya.
Meeting beneath Maman's egg sac...
That's horrifying...
I couldn't do it.
Waiting for someone under that? No way.
If you waited an hour, maybe the eggs
would hatch on top of you!
Honestly, you lot. It's art! Art!
Isn't there anything prettier?
This is huge, too!
This one is five metres tall.
It's a rose, right?
This rose is a symbol of
the love and beauty of 66 Plaza.
Looks more lethal than beautiful.
Looks like it might attack at any moment.
Reminds me of Little Shop of Horrors.
Feed me!
Argh! It's art!
I wish they'd put up some nice art.
At the very least, something not terrifying.
This is "Counter Void".
It's just numbers. Not scary at all.
Four, four, four, four, four, four!
We're done four!
I changed my mind!
I thought four stood for "fourtunate"!
Roppongi Hills turned out to be pretty terrifying.
It was a lot to take in.
Like that building over there.
Who knows what horrors it sees every day!
All that happens is that
a work of art watches over the area.
Is this a mushroom?
Looks more like some kinda fruit.
Or the head of a really big person.
This is the Guardian Stone.
Guardian Stone?
A watchman who safeguards Roppongi Hills.
Doesn't look like it's guarding anything.
I don't think Roppongi Hills is very well-protected.
Well, thanks to this stone,
TV Asahi became the most-viewed TV station.
Doubt that stone's the reason.
Phew, at last we stopped somewhere relaxing.
Look, rice fish!
They're extraterrestrial life forms.
What the hell are you talking about?
They're space rice fish.
Huh?
They're descended from rice fish
that were born in space
as part of experiments carried out on board
the space shuttle Columbia by Mukai Chiaki.
Rice fish born in space?
Oh yeah, they were the first vertebrates
to give birth in space.
Yep, and then they were released into
this lake by the astronaut Mohri.
Look! Cute!
So they have spot-billed ducks here, too.
It's so peaceful here.
Unfortunately, the spot-bills tend to eat the rice fish.
It's apparently taken quite a toll on their numbers.
The ducks eat the space fish...
B-But the ducks have to care for their ducklings...
And it looks like the crows prey upon those ducklings.
Talk about the law of the jungle!
I knew Roppongi Hills was scary!
Tokyo recently passed city ordinance
to exterminate the crows.
So the top of the food chain is city ordinance?!
City ordinance is scary!
Since they built Roppongi Hills,
and Midtown,
Roppongi's changed beyond recognition.
This is where Velfarre used to be.
Now it's called "Nicofarre".
Wow! Sooner or later, Roppongi Hills
will be called Nico Hills!
They should build a theatre called Nicohirotei, too.
They say the name Velfarre comes from
a mix of Versace, Ferrari, and Armani.
Ah, the days of the Economic Bubble.
I wonder what it was like!
I bet you'd have been all over it
if you'd been in your twenties back then, Marii.
Probably.
I kinda wanna go back to those bubbly days.
"Take me back to the bubble age!", huh? Okay then.
N-Now hold on a sec!
It's a time machine!
Hoichoi Productions use it to wind the clock back.
Put on this swimsuit and get inside!
Who am I, Hirosue Ryouko?!
See you soon, Marii!
Go dancing for us!
Good luck!
To the Bubble!
I'm gonna go bald!
Ow...
This is... the Bubble Era!
It's pumping! The whole club is pumping!
Dance like nobody's watching! Hoo hah!
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
This is the Giroppon life!
Fetch me more pink Dom Pérignon!
I refuse to stay anywhere but the Akasaka Prince!
Everyone is just bubbles...
Thought we'd lost you for a second there, Marii!
Where am I?
Roppongi! Don't you remember?
Roppongi... in the present?
Huh, what's this? More art?
Yep. The title of this piece of public art is "Day Tripper".
Day Tripper...
So it was all a bubble-like dream.
I guess all bubbles have to burst eventually.
Boris Vian, who wrote
"Froth on the Daydream", once said:
"There are only two things:
Love, all sorts of love, with pretty girls,"
"and the music of New Orleans or Duke Ellington.
Everything else ought to go,"
"because everything else is ugly."
Shall we go on a pilgrimage
before we head home?
It'll be a bit of a walk.
A pilgrimage?
An Ebi** pilgrimage!
Ah, that building!
Let's go drink tequila from ashtrays!
I'm pretty sure we'll become national treasures like him.
"That ninja fella over there looks pretty hot."
"I went over there just now to ask him somethin'."
"What didja ask him?"
"I asked if he's shuriken handle this heat!"
Thanks for your continued appreciation.
This isn't "Cool Biz"-themed, it's ninja-themed!
That's right! Backstage,
we're already playing at being ninjas!
Didn't get me!
Calm down! It's too hot for this!
Stop this dumb ninja game!
Hey.
I told you to stop it!
The iron rings, beloved of kunoichi!
Indeed.
Though the true weapon of the kunoichi is—
Hey, are you okay?
Our feminine wiles!
I-I let my guard down...
Stop this bullshit already!
But...
You can't make us do Cool Biz
and then also stop us from playing ninja!
Do you think anybody would guess
we were Cool Biz rakugo performers?
You could survey one hundred dudes at Shinbashi
and they'd all say we were ninjas!
It doesn't matter how much we talk
about saving electricity or Cool Biz.
The fact remains that performing
on stage like this is weird.
As rakugo performers, we should use
our stories to bring chills to people.
Oh.
Ah!
Ghost stories!
Yes.
We'll use spine-tingling tales
to bring chills to our audience.
Ghost stories... Ghost stories, you say...
I wonder if ghosts are enough
to scare audiences nowadays.
They're so scary!
Sure they are, but nowadays
I'd wager reality is even scarier.
Take a look at this.
It's the beach!
I wish that was me!
Is that...
Exactly.
In the background, a pale figure is staring at her.
Agh! Is it a ghost?!
That's super creepy!
It'd be scary if it was a ghost,
but take a closer look.
It's nothing more than a person wearing a white outfit.
Phew!
It's human!
That's even worse!
Yes.
It's creepy to catch a ghost on camera,
but it's even creepier to catch a human dressed in white.
That's true. A ghost you can see is less terrifying
than radioactive materials you can't.
Ghosts are still scary, though!
Do you know the story of
the red-roofed apartment on 3rd Street?
Yes, the one nobody can move into?
She never leaves...
No matter how much they exorcise the place,
the sitting ghost never leaves, bound to that spot!
Isn't that scary?
Bound spirits are pretty scary,
but look at this photograph.
A spirit bound to an old house?
Look closer.
Looks like a monster that'd
show up in the Cthulhu Mythos.
Look even closer.
It's actually the politician
that everyone says looks like a fish.
Ugh, that guy.
How can one person mess up so much?!
By the way, this isn't a house. It's parliament.
A politician who raises consumption tax
is more terrifying than any ghost could ever be, right?
They are! They can't even compare!
It's scarier because it hurts everyone in the country.
I still think ghosts are scarier!
Did something happen to you?
The other day, when I was walking down
the corridor to the dressing room...
A sudden, unearthly rapping!
It scared me to death!
There's nothing scary about that.
What's this?
Forget a sudden, unearthly rapping.
This is far scarier: ubiquitous, un-Japanese pop.
But music from that country is really popular.
Has anyone here actually bought a CD from there?
No.
Nope.
Me neither.
Not at all.
Terrifying!
How can it be popular if nobody's buying CDs?!
Let's try a visual approach.
If we paint the room blue, it'll feel cooler in here.
We can experiment in here, and if it works,
we can paint the whole theatre.
I'll help!
Me too.
Hey, I don't think they'll let us—
The dragonfly's glasses are as blue as the sky...
Mariiemon!
She crashed like an Osprey!
She looks more like a member of the Blue Man Group.
The Blue Man Group has three members!
I wonder if this'll pull in more guests.
Probably.
I do think it feels a little cooler now.
But now we're used to it...
I'm hot again...
We just need more blue stuff.
Let's all dye our hair blue!
What are we, an anime from the 80s?
I'm not Konata!
I'm not Ayanami!
I'm not Lord Aoshi!
I'm not Soldier Blue!
I'm really feeling that generation gap here.
Well, there are remakes and re-runs.
Let's just give it a go.
Lining our blue heads up like this
makes things feel a little fresher in here.
It works much better than I expected.
They should stop re-airing Touch during summer break
and only show anime with blue-haired characters!
But...
It's hot again now that we're used to it.
Maybe we should wear blue kimono.
Yes! Everyone wear blue!
Ooh, this kinda works!
Right?
I just had another great idea!
Ghosts!
What was that about?
His wife's way scarier than any ghosts.
I've already grown used to this, too. It's so hot.
Something else! We need more blue!
I know what!
Now that's refreshing!
The perfect thing for summer.
Marii's Mongolian Spot is so blue!
At least my butt is cool!
Bouhatei Tetora here!
Anrakutei Kukuru here.
Kuurubiyuutei Gankyou here.
Haroukitei Kigurumi here!
Buratei Marii here!
The conversations in this anime...
...are written to be as inoffensive as possible...
...so as not to interfere with your enjoyment...
...of viewing cute gi...
...rls.
The splendid beauty of the thirteenth episode contains:
"Character Assassination".
"Akihabubble".
And "A Little Ex..."
"...tra".
Hey, wait a sec! Why do I always
get stuck with the very end?!