This title is likely a reference to the rakugo play, Yadoya no Tomi
(Tomi at the Inn). In Osaka, this is also known as Takatsu no Tomi
(Tomi of the Takatsu (Shrine)). The story revolves around a
guest at an inn who wins a lottery ticket.
This title is likely a reference to the rakugo play, Yadoya no Tomi
(Tomi at the Inn). In Osaka, this is also known as Takatsu no Tomi
(Tomi of the Takatsu (Shrine)). The story revolves around a
guest at an inn who wins a lottery ticket.
This is a parody of DREAM JUMPO, a lottery held in June each year.
The design represents the 560th edition, which corresponds to the
2009 lottery (the year the manga came out). The word "Specimen"
in the original indicates it's a sample ticket.
This is a parody of DREAM JUMPO, a lottery held in June each year.
The design represents the 560th edition, which corresponds to the
2009 lottery (the year the manga came out). The word "Specimen"
in the original indicates it's a sample ticket.
The symbols in the background are all money signs.
Youguretto, yogurt-flavoured
and tablet-shaped candy.
Ronald McDonald, the McDonalds mascot. The jingle
is a parody of the McDonalds "I'm lovin' it" jingle, with
the last note removed on purpose.
Ronald McDonald, the McDonalds mascot. The jingle
is a parody of the McDonalds "I'm lovin' it" jingle, with
the last note removed on purpose.
Parody on LOOK JTB, a travel agency.
"[DameDesuYo] Koe no Katachi", a fansub release infamous for being stalled for
7 or so years. Finally saw release in June of 2023, but not without its drama.
Just a little bit of fansubber fun.
"[DameDesuYo] Koe no Katachi", a fansub release infamous for being stalled for
7 or so years. Finally saw release in June of 2023, but not without its drama.
Just a little bit of fansubber fun.
The original movie named is "BRAVE HEARTS: Sea Monkey".
The censor sounds are monkey sounds because sea monkeys.
The English word is a political term referring to rich political donors.
Stems from the essay, "Fat Cats and Free Rides", and in modern use
often refers to wealthy people who don't deserve the money.
The English word is a political term referring to rich political donors.
Stems from the essay, "Fat Cats and Free Rides", and in modern use
often refers to wealthy people who don't deserve the money.
Sutairu sounds like it means "fashion style", but it's actually a wasei-eigo term
(i.e. loanword) that means something closer to "a good figure". Even the destroyer
of anime himself has memed on how often people mistranslate this..
Sutairu sounds like it means "fashion style", but it's actually a wasei-eigo term
(i.e. loanword) that means something closer to "a good figure". Even the destroyer
of anime himself has memed on how often people mistranslate this..
Plays on the idea that rich people don't argue because they
only stand to lose money and reputation by doing so.
An old-fashioned expression used in classical Japanese
literature such as Sei Shonagon's The Pillow Book.
The original line is a mix-up of similar lines from Kindaichi Case Files,
Columbo, and TRICK. The translation is a reference to Watson from
Sherlock Holmes.
The original line is a mix-up of similar lines from Kindaichi Case Files,
Columbo, and TRICK. The translation is a reference to Watson from
Sherlock Holmes.
Jehovah's Witnesses, a denomination of Christianity
known for their door-to-door preaching.
Since you can see the Tokyo Shiodome building
this is likely the west view from Tokyo Tower.
Skytree was opened on May 22nd, 2012,
the year this anime aired.
A number pun. 6-3-4 = Mu-sa-shi, and Ko-ji-rou = 5-10-6.
Tokyo Tower is located in what used to be the Musashi province,
and as you'd expect, this pun was part of their marketing strategy.
A number pun. 6-3-4 = Mu-sa-shi, and Ko-ji-rou = 5-10-6.
Tokyo Tower is located in what used to be the Musashi province,
and as you'd expect, this pun was part of their marketing strategy.
Miyamoto Musashi and Sasaki Kojirou were famous Japanese
sword fighters, known for their legendary duel. Though real talk,
if you know them, it's because of the Fate series.
Miyamoto Musashi and Sasaki Kojirou were famous Japanese
sword fighters, known for their legendary duel. Though real talk,
if you know them, it's because of the Fate series.
There were actually plans to make it 666 metres (twice the height of
Tokyo Tower), however due to structural limitations they were
ultimately unable to make it that tall.
There were actually plans to make it 666 metres (twice the height of
Tokyo Tower), however due to structural limitations they were
ultimately unable to make it that tall.
666 is the Number of the Beast mentioned in
Revelation 13:18 of the New Testament Bible.
Toei is an entertainment company. The wave sound effect is
a parody of the wave image that play before their films.
Mother Farm was founded by Hisakichi Maeda (1893-1986)
to secure land for the construction of the Tokyo Tower.
From their website: "Mother Farm is located on Mt. Kanozan, from where you can
enjoy the magnificent views of the mountains of the Boso Peninsula, Tokyo Bay,
and Mt. Fuji." So, in reality, you might be able to see Tokyo Tower from there.
From their website: "Mother Farm is located on Mt. Kanozan, from where you can
enjoy the magnificent views of the mountains of the Boso Peninsula, Tokyo Bay,
and Mt. Fuji." So, in reality, you might be able to see Tokyo Tower from there.
The Tokyo Tower's, tear-shaped twin mascot characters.
The older brother wears blue, and the younger wears red.
A 195m high radio tower located in Nishi-Tokyo City,
operated by the "Tanashi Tower" company.
Following the merging of Tanashi City and Hoya City into Nishi-Tokyo City,
the name was changed. Locals still call it the Tanashi Tower, however.
http://www.skytower195.com/blog/soraponprofile.pdf
You can see the Kasumigaseki Common Gate and the Metropolitan Police
Department in this shot, which are north of Tokyo Tower. Mt. Fuji is to
the south-west, so Kigurumi physically cannot see Mt. Fuji from here.
You can see the Kasumigaseki Common Gate and the Metropolitan Police
Department in this shot, which are north of Tokyo Tower. Mt. Fuji is to
the south-west, so Kigurumi physically cannot see Mt. Fuji from here.
She's talking about Korea. Japan has had a tumultuous relationship
with both North and South Korea to put it mildly.
Right-wing (conservatism, etc.) vs. left-wing (progressivism, etc.).
Centrism is supposed to technically not be biased to either side,
but they sure love to up-hold and prolong the status quo...
Right-wing (conservatism, etc.) vs. left-wing (progressivism, etc.).
Centrism is supposed to technically not be biased to either side,
but they sure love to up-hold and prolong the status quo...
The Lookdown Window, famous for its thrilling look down to the ground.
It's even a topic on a lot of variety shows and specials, including
but not limited to Milky Holmes Extracurricular Class.
The Lookdown Window, famous for its thrilling look down to the ground.
It's even a topic on a lot of variety shows and specials, including
but not limited to Milky Holmes Extracurricular Class.
The Russian and Fiji embassies are in Azabudai, the Afghanistan embassy
is in Azabu 2-chome, and the Dutch embassy is in Toranomon 5-chome.
Likely a holdover from British table-side manners.
They would put mashed potatoes on the back side
of their fork. Nobody does this nowadays.
Likely a holdover from British table-side manners.
They would put mashed potatoes on the back side
of their fork. Nobody does this nowadays.
The Fujiya mascot characters, Peko-chan and her boyfriend,
Poko-chan. Peko is often seen sticking her tongue out.
Peko-chan and Poko-chan were born in 1950 and 1951.
The dog was introduced in 1995, and is called "Dog" (in English).
Pettanko, slang for female characters,
especially in anime, who are flat-chested.
A line from Wild Chrysanthemum Grave (1906),
a novel by Sachio Ito.
This title is a reference to the rakugo play, "Fire Son".
When a pawnshop is hit by a fire, the owner sees his missing
son he had disowned standing among the firefighters.
This title is a reference to the rakugo play, "Fire Son".
When a pawnshop is hit by a fire, the owner sees his missing
son he had disowned standing among the firefighters.
Shounen Jump, a magazine for manga aimed at young male teens.
Very well known for a lot of long-running manga, like One Piece,
Hajime no Ippo, Doraemon, Naruto, Bleach, Gintama, etc. etc.
Shounen Jump, a magazine for manga aimed at young male teens.
Very well known for a lot of long-running manga, like One Piece,
Hajime no Ippo, Doraemon, Naruto, Bleach, Gintama, etc. etc.
A "cour" refers to the episodes of an anime that roughly aired
in a TV season. This usually ranges from 9-14 episodes.
This exact phrase was also used in the radio commercial
for Vol. 1 of the Rakugo Girls blu-rays.
On average, 90% of blu-rays and DVD sales happen in the first week.
If neither sell well, there's a snowball's chance in Hell that's gonna change.
Nakayoshi, a monthly magazine aimed at young female teens published
by Kodansha, the same publisher as the Rakugo Girls manga. Literally
translates to "Good Friends".
Nakayoshi, a monthly magazine aimed at young female teens published
by Kodansha, the same publisher as the Rakugo Girls manga. Literally
translates to "Good Friends".
During the original screening of Polyester, some movie theatres distributed
special cards that emit specific scenes when rubbed during screening.
The Rakugo Girls anime voice acting cast is completely different from
the Drama CD's cast, except for Kukuru's voice actor, Saori Gotou.
The phone on the right is the TZ-802, the first mobile phone when NTT
started mobile phone service in 1987 , and weighs about 900g.
The laptop on the left is the Macintosh PowerBook 100, Apple's first
practical laptop released in 1991, and weighs approximately 2.3 kg.
It wasn't until 2003 that cameras became commonplace on Japanese phones.
Reference to vending machines that accept "e-wallets". They
even featured facial recognition to give recommendations!
Of course, nowadays mobile wallets are the norm.
Tough luck, Gankyou.
Reference to vending machines that accept "e-wallets". They
even featured facial recognition to give recommendations!
Of course, nowadays mobile wallets are the norm.
Tough luck, Gankyou.
Yoshiro Nakamatsu, Japanese inventor and media personality
who often goes by the title, "Doctor Nakamatsu". Also known
for running for a number of elections, including the Tokyo
gubernatorial election
Yoshiro Nakamatsu, Japanese inventor and media personality
who often goes by the title, "Doctor Nakamatsu". Also known
for running for a number of elections, including the Tokyo
gubernatorial election
Katsuya Takasu, Japanese plastic surgeon and media personality, known for
undergoing a continuous rejuvenation process to make himself look younger.
Also famous for his rather ??? commercials where he flies over the Middle East
in a helicopter.
Katsuya Takasu, Japanese plastic surgeon and media personality, known for
undergoing a continuous rejuvenation process to make himself look younger.
Also famous for his rather ??? commercials where he flies over the Middle East
in a helicopter.
Rika Kayama, the penname of a Japanese psychiatrist and
media personality. The name is derived from the real name
of the Licca-chan doll.
Rika Kayama, the penname of a Japanese psychiatrist and
media personality. The name is derived from the real name
of the Licca-chan doll.
Yuri Zhivago, fictional physician from the book, Doctro Zhivago (1957).
Julius No, fictional villain from the 1962 James Bond film, Dr. No (1962).
Dr. Moreau, a fictional mad scientist from the novel, The Island of Doctor Moreau (1896).
Black Jack, fictional medical mercenary from the manga series, Black Jack (1973).
They're all dressed as characters from Black Jack.
Dr. Kiriko
Dr. Black Jack
Pinoko
Noriko Sakai, also known as Nori-P, former actress/singer
who was arrested in 2009 for drug possession.
Kazuo Teranishi, a.k.a. Macky. The nickname became well-known due to a drug-related
incident in 1999 when he was arrested for the possession and use of illegal drugs.
Manabu Oshio, former actor/singer, who was arrested in 2009 for drug possession and
not rendering aid to a hostess that he had been taking drugs with, which led to her death.
Gankyou's referring to MDMA, a.k.a. ecstasy.
White storks have been the deliverers of babies for centuries in European folklore,
and was further popularised by Hans Christian Andersen's "The Storks" (1839).
Reference to Shoko Asahara, founder of the doomsday cult Aum Shinrikyo,
who claimed he could levitate once he reached a state of nirvana.
She asks for something "suppai" (sour). Naturally, it's way easier
to come up with puns for the similar-sounding "spicy".
007: From Russia with Love. To be specific, this is
the "Ultimate Edition 2 Disc Set" packaging.
Kukuru is humming the Opening Theme from the
American TV drama, Operation Spy (1966).
The song is "Moe x 2 Kyun x 2", a copyright-free song from the Nash Music Library. It was also
the BGM of the variety show, Idol-chin, where Momoiro Clover Z, a group who have also
performed a number of anime songs,  performed it.
The song is "Moe x 2 Kyun x 2", a copyright-free song from the Nash Music Library. It was also
the BGM of the variety show, Idol-chin, where Momoiro Clover Z, a group who have also
performed a number of anime songs,  performed it.
Reference to the Pretty Cure anime series.
These are references to Detective Opera Milky Holmes, Pokémon,
and Horizon in the Middle of Nowhere.
Lyrics of the Edo Lullaby, used to hush children to sleep.
There's an urban legend in Japan where yellow ambulances are said
to transport mentally ill people to a hospital with iron bars.
The exact model of this car is the Nissan Elgrand E51.
There's an urban legend in Japan where yellow ambulances are said
to transport mentally ill people to a hospital with iron bars.
The exact model of this car is the Nissan Elgrand E51.
Bunch of references in the background. Some of the more interesting ones:
____- Sho-tei Ii Tomo (reference to the Fuji TV variety show, Waratte Iitomo)
____- Oki-tei Yabairi (lit. "Breaking the rules")
____- Yuki Yuki-tei Shingun (reference to a documentary called Yuki Yukite, Kamigun by Kazuo Hara)
____- Ii-tei Gouhou Hoko (from the movie, E.T. (1982))
____- Giru-tei Kurai (reference to Guilty Crown)
____- Humpty Dumpty
____- Cutie Honey
Bunch of references in the background. Some of the more interesting ones:
____- Sho-tei Ii Tomo (reference to the Fuji TV variety show, Waratte Iitomo)
____- Oki-tei Yabairi (lit. "Breaking the rules")
____- Yuki Yuki-tei Shingun (reference to a documentary called Yuki Yukite, Kamigun by Kazuo Hara)
____- Ii-tei Gouhou Hoko (from the movie, E.T. (1982))
____- Giru-tei Kurai (reference to Guilty Crown)
____- Humpty Dumpty
____- Cutie Honey