Thank you kindly for your attention
oato ga mata yoroshikute
I hope to have it again and again
osaki mo mae mo yoroshiku ne
Twing-twang twing-twang-twong
chin-ton chin-ton-shan
The theater's full
jounai manjou
Mysteries are fun
nazotoki dokidoki shinan
Tricks are fun as well
shikake ga ariari desu
We can solve girly problems by throwing dice
joshiteki onayami wa sugoroku sai wo futte
(really?)
(hai hai)
It's not one nor six, but nine
ichi de mo roku de mo nain
(really?)
(sou kai)
The stakes are high, but you can get a sign
ichi kake bachi ka de sain
(really?)
(sou kai)
I don't really see how that's related
hanashi no tsunagari ga miemasen ne
See, this looks like it's gonna be fun
oya omoshiroku narisou na yokan wa
(see, see?)
(oya oya desu)
Or am I just seeing things?
me no sakkaku desu ka
I don't even care
iya soredemo kamawanai
Come on, everyone
hai minna
Let's spin!
mawatte
Front and back, let's just turn it around
omote mo ura uragaeshite
You can turn the story upside down too
dondengaeshi mo yoshiyoshi
Let's go on, ladies first
osaki ni ikou saa douzo
I hope to see you around again and again
osaki mo mae mo yoroshiku ne
The backstage is the main stage
ura butai ga hare butai de
That's where we can chat idly
muda uchibanashi mo yokayoka
Thank you kindly for your attention
oato ga mata yoroshikute
I hope it was a good comedy
osaki mo shiroki gokuraku da
A comedy, a comedy
gokuraku da gokuraku da
A comedy from the comedy heaven
arayotto gokuraku joudo ringu
Twing-twang twing-twang-twong
chin-ton chin-ton-shan
"Oh please, that sounds like the school's alarm."
Thank you kindly for your attention.
A
Backstage Riches
Um...
Don't ask stupid questions!
But...
She didn't even say anything.
Oh, sorry.
You were saying?
If you won the lottery, what would you do with the money?
That's the kind of stupid I was talking about!
A
This anime is
full of ordinary dialogue
so that viewers can fully
enjoy how cute the girls are.
Oh please, this is a no-brainer.
I'd sa—
I'd hate to become someone who saves all their money.
Yeah, that's so lame. Those people have no dreams.
I'd hate to become someone like that.
If you asked those people what kind of animal
they'd like to be reincarnated as,
Hum—
they'd just mindlessly answer "human," wouldn't they?
What's wrong, Marii?
Ah, nothing.
So what would you do with it?
Me? I'd...
Pay back my debts.
That's as unambitious as saving money!
The difference is that in one situation you're saving,
and in the other you're paying!
No, the difference is how serious the situations are.
It's all about being stingy!
Three hundred million.
If I had three hundred million...
I would look for my missing mother.
Um...  Oh, I see.
If I won, I'd be sure to find the culprit!
What culprit?!
It'd be nice if you found him.
Good luck.
What the hell are you girls doing off-screen?!
Debts? Missing mother? Find the culprit?
Do you girls really have no dreams?!
When you buy a lottery ticket, you buy a dream!
Three hundred yen per ticket is the price of the delusion!
What's the point of paying for the delusion
if you have no dreams?!
Kigu, what would you do with the money?
I wanna know!
What?
What would you do?
T-These expectations...
I love Yoglets! I'd build a house out of them!
That's totally something you'd do.
How cute!
Like hell I would.
I've had it with your expectations.
Um, mind if I point out something fundamental?
Even if you were to win the lottery,
you wouldn't tell anyone about it.
Yeah, I wouldn't tell anyone.
That's true. Neither would I.
Could it be...
that there's...
a winner among us?!
But which...
one of us...
could it be?
Laugh
Come to think of it, you got a brand new kimono recently!
It would seem that someone has
a few extra coins jingling around in her pocket.
W-What are you getting at?!
Maybe you won the lottery?
Look who's talking! You came here by taxi!
A taxi?!
How suspicious.
I live within basic fare distance!
And I can point fingers too! Guess what I saw?!
You were eating at McDonald's without any coupons!
Not using coupons...
At McDonald's...
You wouldn't be able to afford
such a luxury unless you won the lottery!
But... she has a foreign travel catalog in her bag!
That's for my granny!
And who gave you permission to look in my bag?!
Obviously we should look inside everyone's bags!
W-What are you doing?!
Look at this!
She bought a movie ticket
even though it's not ladies' discount day!
And it's for this weird show called Br*ve H**rts Um**aru!
You can't watch stuff like this
unless you don't care about wasting money!
Please, stop!
Stop hurting each other!
Rich people aren't supposed to fight!
That's true. The rich don't care about small details.
They're more laid back.
So we really are poor?
But they also say that the rich are stingy.
Why are you looking at me?
They say rich people are fat.
Quit staring at me!
I just eat a lot of snacks!
First off, aren't rich people supposed to have good self-control?
So wouldn't they have nice figures?
Oh...
"Oh" what?! Stop acting as if you just solved a crime!
They say that the rich don't fight,
but don't you wonder what it's like when they do fight?
I assume they go all snobbish.
Simpletons who are unable to support themselves
on minimum wage lack the brainpower to comprehend this.
Extremely refined.
You don't say? What might you be impa-pa-plying?
Deary me. You should regain your compo-po-posure.
Why not insert one's apex into one's own hindquarters?
Is that supposed to mean...
Stick your head up your ass?
When you're wealthy, it shows in other ways
that can't be measured with money.
What do you mean?
You can tell someone won the lottery based on how they speak.
Which reminds me, what was it that you said?
Huh?
The people I respect the most are my parents!
No one can emotionally afford to stay stuff like that!
Not without having a 300 million yen safety net!
That was just...
In the name of my woman back home,
this mystery is like totally solved!
It's elementary! You're the culprit!
I'm not!
She's not the culprit, just a winner.
Seriously, who is it?! Admit it already!
Wait a moment.
I've heard that even if a lottery winner keeps a low profile,
the pros can still sniff out the money.
Pros?
Relatives you've never seen before.
Someone from a different class at your old school.
Those are just leeches!
And—
We have come to spread the word of God!
See, here they are. Real pros.
Pros would definitely know which one of us has money.
Which one of us do you want to convert the most?
Who's the winner?
The most?
She who lacks the most faith,
and is most in danger of demonic possession is...
You!
I didn't win!
Give me a break!
You shouldn't resort to violence!
A blackout?
But we have a rich person here!
The light's back.
You're going
to Hell!
Revenge?
There's a believer among us!
But who...
did that...
to Marii?
What an amazing view!
I'm glad the weather is so good.
You can see so far!
Good thing we came.
So... why are we here?
What do you mean... Why?
Why did we go to the Tokyo Tower?
A
Three Towers and a Vow
Isn't the Sky Tree hip these days?
But the Sky Tree isn't a tower! It's a tree!
It's the Tokyo Tower or nothing.
The widening base is good for luck.
The Sky Tree is tapered as well.
The Tokyo Tower is 333 meters high.
It's a beautiful number.
In contrast, the Sky Tree is 634 meters.
Is that Musashi's number? Where's Kojirou then?
At least make it 666.
That's the number of the Beast!
By the way, Toei and the Mother Farm
are big shareholders of the Tokyo Tower.
Well, Toei is at least connected to TV broadcasting...
But the Mother Farm? Sheep can't climb the tower!
I know! When they get lost on the farm, they use it for directions!
But the Mother Farm is in Chiba.
They can't even see it from there.
The Tokyo Tower mascots, the red and blue Noppons,
are brothers and not lovers.
Seriously?
Anyway! Who cares about trees and towers?
Remember how people think of the Tanashi Tower!
By the way, it's official name is Western Tokyo Sky Tower.
This is its mascot, Sorapon.
"Western Tokyo" is already a big stretch, but "Sky Tower"?
It's like they just mixed words.
But you don't have to go all the way
to the Sky Tree or the Tanashi Tower.
Just look at the scenery from here...
Doesn't this give you a sense of serenity?
I really like the sight to the north.
It seems to sparkle in the sunlight.
I can see Mount Fuji over there!
To the south there's Haneda airport.
Where's the Rainbow Bridge? Is that east or west?
Do you prefer north or south?
North... or south? Which?
North, I guess.
I see. Why?
No reason.
No reason, huh?
Can you just pick north on a whim?
Isn't the south better?
But...
You need determination for the north.
Can you live without ever returning south?
We're talking about the scenery, right?
Of course. The scenery.
It's hard to remember compass directions, right?
North is up, south is down.
Then east is right and west is left.
That's how I remember it.
Isn't it difficult to remember left and right to begin with?
I hold chopsticks in my right hand and the bowl in the left.
Say...
Do you prefer left or right?
But that's not something...
If you had to choose, would you lean right or left?
Neither.
A centrist?
Well... Well...
You keep asking these questions, but which do you prefer?
Me? I prefer...
Down.
I like to look down.
Isn't that the Russian embassy?
The Netherlands, Fiji and Afghanistan...
There are many embassies around here, aren't there?
How do foreigners remember left and right?
Fork side and knife side?
But sometimes you take the fork in the other hand.
For example, if you already cut up a steak beforehand,
you just eat with the fork in your right hand.
Or when you eat rice.
Why would someone put rice on a fork?
Do they put it into the curve or on the back?
They don't even have white rice!
I heard that was originally how you ate cooked beans.
So it's not wrong!
But if you try to pick it up it'll fall down,
so you use the knife to keep it on the back of the fork.
The back? Of the fork?
The domed side is its back.
So the curved side is its stomach?
But shouldn't its stomach be domed?
The side that sticks out is the domed one.
Who sticks it out?
Peko sticks it out. Poko doesn't.
Really!
They even got a dog? How impudent.
They're kids. What's the big deal?
So forks are kids?
They aren't curved where they're supposed to be.
True. Nothing sticks out the front.
Marii is like a fork!
What?! Care to say that again?!
You don't really stick out.
True, I can blend in well.
Someone whose front and back could be switched.
Wait, are you praising me or not? Which is it?!
What a lovely picture.
Look, the Imperial Palace!
Hey!
But I hardly ate anything!
That's because it's easy as pie.
Thank you kindly for your attention.
A
Cold Girl
What's wrong with you?
I have no idea what you're saying.
Isn't it obvious?! I said, "Don't make us say stupid things!"
A
So that viewers can
fully enjoy how cute the girls are,
they have removed their masks.
This new strain of influenza is pretty scary...
Yeah, about that. How long are you gonna call it "new"?
It showed up last winter, but it's already summer!
How long are you gonna act as if it's new?
If you called a manga that had been running
for half a year a "new serial," you'd make a fool of yourself!
In Jump it'd be over already!
Even one-cour anime would be over,
doomed to slowly sink into the swamp
of obscurity after the DVDs were released!
Do you seriously think it'd sell? Speed is essential!
The numbers won't grow any higher!
Then should I claim the title of "new"?
Wait a moment.
Say hello to the new me!
A brand new me!
So what exactly is new about you?
Um...
The new one's nipples smell better.
Get up close to the TV and try rubbing the screen right here.
It'll smell good!
Was that included with "Good Friends" magazine?
Friends don't rub each other's nipples.
That's more like John Waters' Polyester.
But it looks like someone rubbed it!
Who could have done that?
Who's the culprit?
But before that, what's the difference
between "new" and "old"?
Well, sometimes they call the same product "new"
when all they did was change the packaging.
Really?
Or they just switch up the roles and
then market it as if it were a whole new cast.
Really!
Old stuff tends to be heavy.
Not to mention lacking in cameras!
Wait, do you really need those built-in cameras?
Not at all!
It's not like we run into celebrities on the street every day.
There's no need to always tell others where you are.
Pay with money. Your phone isn't meant to replace your wallet.
But then we don't need new stuff at all.
Not at all!
What were we talking about again?
In the end it doesn't matter if it's old or new.
Laugh
That's right. But we shouldn't treat the subject so flippantly.
Even as we speak there are people
who've come down with the flu.
That's right. Everyone should just get the vaccine!
Have you all got it?
Not yet.
We're low on the priority list, too.
Who's on the priority list?
I think...
Doctors are the first in line.
Laugh
That makes sense. They stand on
the front lines to fight epidemics, after all.
Wait, does that include Dr Naka**tsu?
And is that plastic surgeon Ta**su at the front of the line too,
along with Ka**ma R**a?
Then even Dr Zhivago and Dr No
and Dr Moreau must be ahead of us...
No, it only applies to licensed doctors
who engage directly in flu treatment.
But then...
Does that mean Dr B**ck J*ck can't
get vaccinated because he's got no license?
He'd save the most patients!
But he'd charge a hefty fee. Plus, he doesn't exist.
But I'm sure it's not just the doctors.
I'm sure there are people who get vaccinated quickly
even though they're not on the list.
Right?
No**pi would've gotten vaccinated already for sure!
Not to mention Mistress E**ka!
And I'm certain O***o Ma**bu has had his shots!
He must've been ecstatic.
I guess celebrities would pull all the strings
they could for faster access.
But we've got no chance.
We're neither famous nor rich.
There's still a way.
Those next on the list after doctors are...
Pregnant women.
Are you saying we should get pregnant?!
There's no other way to get vaccinated quickly.
Kigu, do you know where babies come from?
T-These expectations again...
The stork brings you one if you kiss the boy you like!
Aww, how cute. That's right.
You don't need to know, okay?
I've had it with your expectations.
But actually getting pregnant?
That's not so easy to do.
There's still a way.
False pregnancy.
It doesn't say anywhere that false pregnancy isn't accepted!
Be it psychological or real, pregnancy is pregnancy!
We can trick the eyes of the law!
Let's imagine it, then.
Imagine...
Imagine the beginning of a new life...
The steps of evolution...
She's being creepy! Her grin's so dirty!
That's not it! I wasn't imagining the process or anything!
You were, weren't you?
I can't conceive like this! I can't imagine it!
Then let's start from the beginning: imaginary dating.
It all begins with a matchmaking party.
Then comes a date with just the two of you!
Then?
You start going out...
Oh no, we're having a fight about him leaving the toilet seat up!
Make up!
We're fighting again! He threw an ashtray at me!
Try to make up with him!
He's talking about his problems to another girl.
He just told me I'll be fine on my own!
We just broke up, out of nowhere! How could he?!
An imaginary fight...
Look...
She's completely shut out all sounds from the outside.
As if she were floating, undisturbed, on an imaginary sea.
Wait, she really is floating!
Morning sickness?!
I'm craving something spicy!
Yessir!
I brought you pickled sea squirt!
It stinks.
I brought you a spy movie!
That's not funny.
I brought you all these limes!
Put them down over there.
I felt a kick!
Her mind has overcome her body!
Is she really going to give birth?
I think my belly's gotten bigger too.
I'd say you just had too much for lunch.
Music.
Music? Music for the baby?
Get something good!
Here!
Don't make the baby listen to anime songs!
Who knows how that could distort its mind?
I've decided to name her Pret Tycure!
A
Pret Tycure
Mil Key could work, too.
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
Or Hori Zon.
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
A
Mil Key    Pika Chu
Hori Zon     An Us
It's time!
It's time already?!
Quickly, warm some water!
Why do we have to play along with this?
What?! Pregnant women have top priority!
At first, that sounded kind of inspiring...
But it was based on an incorrect assumption.
She's not even pregnant.
It's coming!
Hey, what's wrong?
She passed out.
Okay, it's over!
Withdraw troops!
What was all that about?
She woke up.
Where is my baby?!
A
Charm
Hush-a-bye... baby...
A
Charm
Baby... baby...
W-Wait a moment...
Excuse us!
In the end, she got priority treatment after all.
It wasn't for the flu, though.
A
Live long, live long and prosper
jugemu jugemu gokou no surikire
May great wealth await you wherever you go
kaijari suigyo no suigyou matsu
Even in different lands and under different skies
unrai matsu fuurai matsu
May you always have your daily bread
kuuneru tokoro ni sumu tokoro
And always be brimming full of life
yaburakouji no burakouji
Like the long-lived king Shuringan
paipo paipo paipo no shuuringan
And his dear wife Gurindai
shuuringan no guurindai
And their children Ponpokopi and Ponpokona
guurindai no ponpokopi no ponpokona no
Live a long and blessed life
choukyuumei chousuke
Let me have a bit of your time
choi to jikan itadakimasu
Please listen closely
goseichou kudasai
A
We're ready
totonoimashita
You write it "laughing"
warau koto to kakemashite
You read it "let's party"
omatsuri yarou zo tokemasu
And the point of it is, the point of it is...
sono kokoro wa sono kokoro wa
That everyone will be happy!
dochira mo happi ni naru deshou
Thank you kindly for your attention
oato ga yoroshii you de
Laugh, laugh, hey, let's laugh
waraou waraou sa waraimashou
Life may be hard, but let's laugh
konna jidai koso waraimashou
Laugh (yeah yeah)
waraou (soiya soiya)
If you cry, you lose
naitara make da
So just laugh until your sides ache
yakekuso waraimashou
Life may have its ups and downs,
haranbanjou sui mo amai mo
But great Japanese can get over it
norikoeta appare nipponjin
Laugh, whatever time may bring
waraou donna toki de mo
Laugh until you run out of breath
nanikuso waraimashou
Who cares where you are? Just laugh
kuuki nante yomazu ni warattoke
Smile (smile), smile (smile)
egao (egao) egao (egao)
Smile and the world will smile back at you
warau kado ni wa fuku kitaru
I'm Anrakutei Kukuru.
A
Preview
Today really is the bath...
In fact, it's so good I feel like I might evaporate,
even though everything should vanish.
Or rather, I want to erase everything myself.
Coming up next is Joshiraku's miraculous third performance:
A
A Bath Beyond
Visit to Asakusa
Sanada Monk-ey
A Bath Beyond, Visit to Asakusa, and Sanada Monk-ey.
Well then, please take good care of your bodies.