"No, you idiot. Military drills!"
Thanks for your continued appreciation!
Um—
Don't ask such dull questions!
Uh, nobody asked anything.
My bad.
So, what were you saying?
What would you buy if you won the lottery?
See, I knew it'd be something dull!
Oh, please. That's an easy one.
I'd save it a—
Anything to avoid being the kind of person
who'd put all the money into savings.
Ugh, yeah. It's like, c'mon, dream big!
I can't think of anything worse.
The kind of person who, if you ask them
what animal they'd want to come back as,
would always say "human".
Hum—
Hm, what's up, Marii?
Oh, n-nothing.
So what would you buy, then?
Me? I guess...
I'd pay off my debts.
Your dreams are awfully small
for someone that spouted all that!
Paying it back is no different to saving it up!
It's a lot more urgent...
Oh, spare me the sob story!
Three hundred million yen?
If I had three hundred million yen, I'd...
I would track down my missing mother.
Um, really...?
If I won the lottery, I'd use the money
to hunt down the true culprit.
What the hell are you talking about?
It'd be great if you could catch them.
Good luck!
Thanks!
What's with the private conversation, guys?!
Debt? Lost moms? True culprits?
Is that all you can come up with?
The lottery lets you buy whatever your heart desires!
One ticket costs three hundred yen.
That's crazy money!
You can't fork out crazy money if your plan is
to spend your winnings on boring crap!
Kigu! What would you buy if you won?
I wanna know!
Tell us!
What would you do?
Th-This is a lot of pressure...
I'd build a house out of my favourite candy!
That's so you!
You cutie.
As if.
I'm getting sick of playing into
everyone's expectations of me.
One thing is for sure, though.
If I won the lottery, I wouldn't tell anyone about it.
Yeah, me neither.
Definitely not.
Could it be?
Has one of us...
Already...
Won?!
But...
Who...
Is it?!
You did get a new kimono recently!
Come into a little money, did we?
Wh-What're you getting at?
Hit the nail on the head, I'd say.
What about you? Didn't you arrive in a taxi today?
A taxi?
Highly suspicious.
It only cost the base fare!
I-If we're pointing fingers, I saw you, y'know!
You bought McD's without using a coupon!
McD...
Without using a coupon...
There's no way you'd do something so
extravagant if you hadn't won the lottery!
What about her?
She's got a holiday brochure in her purse!
It's for my grandma!
Don't mess about with other people's purses!
Let's see what everyone's got in theirs, shall we?
What are you doing?
Look! She's been seeing films without using the Ladies' Day discount!
And she went to see [DDY] KimiKoe!
There's no explanation for
this kind of reckless spending!
Agh! Stop it!
Stop all this senseless fighting!
You know what they say,
there's no money in squabbling!
That's right.
Rich people don't bother themselves with
the petty concerns of regular people.
They're above that.
In other words, that means that
everyone here must be totally broke.
But they also say "as stingy as a millionaire".
Why are you looking at me?
Fat cat!
C-Cut it out! Stop looking at me!
I just like snacking!
Wouldn't you expect a rich person to have
more self-control and a really good body?
I ain't talking about you, big-heads!
If rich people don't squabble,
what do they do when they have a disagreement?
They do argue, just in a more refined way.
I simply do not understand these
economically impaired people.
How very sophisticated of you.
I say, good madam, perchance wherefore
what are you enspeakenestening about?
I think you should perhaps mollify
your obstrepepeperous tendencies.
Please ingest a portion of defecation.
Is that...
"Eat shit"?
I reckon that when someone's wealthy,
it shows in intangible ways.
What do you mean?
For instance, after someone won the lottery,
I'd expect them to change as a person.
Starting with the things they say.
You! Do you remember what you said the other day?
What? I—
I respect my parents more than anyone!
Nobody says that kind of stuff
unless they're completely carefree!
Could it be that you're carefree
to the tune of three hundred million yen?!
I'm not sure what you—
It's elementary, my dear Marii.
I've deduced the solution to this mystery.
You're the culprit!
No way!
Culprit? I think she means "winner".
Who is it?! Just step forward already!
Wait.
I heard something once.
They say that even if lottery winners
keep a low profile,
pros will be able to smell
the scent of money on them.
Pros?
Relatives you've never met before.
Schoolmates from different classes.
Those are just parasites!
And...
Have you got a moment to talk about the Lord?
Here's a pro, right on schedule.
She's sure to know which one of us is the rich one.
Which one of us do you want to convert the most?
Who is the lottery winner?
Who do I want to convert the most?
The young lady most at risk
of falling into Satan's clutches is...
Her!
It ain't me!
Shut your damn mouth!
There's no need for violence!
The power was cut?
You'd think a millionaire would
be able to pay our bills on time.
Oh, it's back on.
Retaliation?
One of us is a convert...
Who...
Attacked...
Marii?
Wow! Talk about a panoramic view!
We're lucky it's so clear.
I can see for miles!
I'm so glad we came.
Hey.
What are we doing here?
What do you mean, what are we doing here?
Why are we at Tokyo Tower?
Doesn't everyone go to Skytree these days?
Skytree isn't a tower, yeah? It's a tree.
Huh?
Tokyo Tower all the way.
Its fan-like design is very auspicious.
Skytree is too skinny.
Tokyo Tower is 333 metres tall.
Isn't that a beautiful number?
By comparison, Tokyo Skytree is 634 metres.
Are they trying to make it sound like "Musashi"?
Where's Kojirou's tower then?
Note:
The Japanese numbers 634 can be pronounced
like the name of the famous swordsman "Musashi".
Kojirou is another swordsman who was famously
defeated by Musashi.
They should have just gone for 666.
That's the mark of the devil!
Tokyo Tower's major shareholders are
the Toei film company and Mother Farm.
I prefer Toei because of the film connection.
Why Mother Farm? Sheep can't climb towers.
Oh, I got it!
When they're lost on the farm,
they can use the tower to guide them home!
Uh, no. Mother Farm's in Chiba.
You can't see it from there.
The tower's red and blue mascots,
the Noppons, are brothers. Not lovers.
Seriously?!
Whatever. Tree, tower, it doesn't matter.
You're all forgetting about Tanashi Tower!
The official name is "Skytower West Tokyo".
This is their mascot, Sorapon.
"West Tokyo" is bad enough, but "Skytower"?
It's like a perfect blend of the other two.
Anyway, I don't think there's any need for us
to trek out to Skytree or Tanashi Tower.
Isn't it enough to stand here and take in this scenery?
The view to the north is amazing.
The light hits it just right and you can see everything.
I can see Mt. Fuji!
That's Haneda Airport to the south.
Where is it you can see
the Rainbow Bridge? West? East?
Hey. Which do you like better, north or south?
North. South. Which one is your favourite?
North, I think.
Hm, I see. Why is that?
I just went with my gut.
Oh?
That's so vague. It's not really a reason.
Isn't the south better?
What are you—
Are you ready to choose the North?
Are you prepared to never return to the South?
You're t-talking about scenery, right?
Just talking about scenery.
It's kind of hard to keep north,
south, east, and west straight.
I just remember that north is up, south is down,
right is east, and left is west.
Isn't left vs. right just as hard to remember?
Right is the chopstick hand.
Left is where I hold my rice bowl.
Hey. Which do you like better, right or left?
I don't really know...
Do you lean to the right? Or the left?
Neither...
You prefer the centre?
Uh... uh...
Why don't you tell us which one you like best?
Me? I like...
Down.
I like looking down.
L-Look, the Russian Embassy!
The Netherlands, Fiji, Afghanistan...
There's a lot of embassies 'round here!
How do you think non-Japanese people
remember their left and right?
Fork side and knife side?
But don't you sometimes switch
your fork to the other hand?
Like when you cut steak up first and then
swap your fork to their right hand to eat it.
And when you eat rice.
By the way, what's up with people
who put rice on the top of their fork?
Do you say "top" or "reverse"?
Do they even eat rice overseas?
I heard it was a holdover from table manners
when eating boiled beans.
So it's not wrong per se.
If you just scoop them up, they fall all over the place,
so you're meant to help them onto
the back of your fork using your knife.
Back? Of a fork?
The raised bit is called the back.
So the concave bit is the tummy?
You'd expect the bit that
sticks out to be the tummy.
The back sticks out like Peko.
Peko? The Fujiya mascot?
Yeah. Her tongue is sticking out.
So it is.
When did they get a dog? They're so cheeky.
Ah, they're just kids. It's fine.
So a fork is the opposite of a kid?
Because it doesn't stick out where it should.
Oh, I see what you mean.
Marii is like a fork, then.
Oi!
What's that supposed to mean?!
Straight and narrow.
Oh, I guess you're right. I'm a very honest person.
Completely straight up and down.
Hold on, are you complimenting me
or insulting me? I can't tell!
It really is a lovely view.
I can see the Imperial Palace!
Hey!
"But how did you eat the whole dessert?"
"It was a piece of cake!"
Thank you for your continued appreciation.
What are you guys doing?
I have absolutely no idea what you're trying to say.
Can't you tell?
Don't make us explain such dull things!
Man, this new type of flu is scary.
That's true, but hey.
How long do we get to keep calling it a "new type"?
It started in winter and it's already summer.
Are we just going to keep pretending it's new?
If a manga had been out that long
and they called it a new release,
they'd be a laughing stock!
A Shounen Jump series would
already be finished by now!
If it was an anime then the first cour would be over
and the DVD would already have come out!
Worst-case, everyone would have
already forgotten about it!
Just accept that nobody's buying it!
First impressions are everything!
Your numbers aren't going to improve!
I'm going to try something.
One moment, please.
I'm New-Type Kukuru!
The new me!
What exactly do you mean by "new type"?
Uh, well...
She now emits pleasing scents from her nipples!
What?
Just give the screen a rub here.
It smells great!
Friendship perks?
Rubbing nipples has nothing to do with being friends.
It sounds more like that John Waters film "Polyester".
Looks like you've been rubbed already.
Who's been rubbing Kukuru?
Show yourself, culprit!
Anyway, what's the difference between
"new type" and "old type"?
Sometimes they don't change anything but
the packaging, then slap a "new" label on it.
They do?
Sometimes they bring on substitute idol group members
and tout the performance as a whole new cast.
They do!
Old types are heavy.
They don't even have cameras and stuff.
Wait. Do you really need there to be a camera?
I guess you don't really!
You don't meet celebs in town that often.
There's no need to keep people
updated on your every movement.
Pay with cash.
A wallet is a wallet, a phone is a phone.
Do we even need new types of things?
Nope!
What were we talking about again?
New type, old type... Maybe it doesn't really matter.
Yeah. We probably shouldn't be getting so worked up.
There are people laid up in bed with the flu right now.
Yep, we should be trying not to catch it.
Is everyone vaccinated?
Not yet. We're not that high a priority.
Is there an order?
Let's see...
Doctors are the first priority, I think.
Yeah, they're the first line of defence against infection.
Note: An inventor.
Wait. Does that include Dr. N*k*m*tsu?
Note: A plastic surgeon.
What about Dr. T*k*su?
Note: A psychiatrist.
Or Dr. K*y*m*?
We probably come after Dr. Zhivago,
Dr. No and Dr. Moreau...
No, this is only for proper doctors
who deal directly with the flu.
Does that mean that Bl*ck J*ck won't get
vaccinated because he's not licensed?
He's the one most likely to cure the outbreak!
No. For one thing, it'd be expensive.
Secondly, he's not real.
But there must be people who aren't doctors
who've taken the vaccination drugs.
Note: Japanese celebs with widely rumoured drug problems.
N*ri-P definitely took the drugs!
M*rcy definitely took the drugs!
Osh*o M*n*bu probably injected them with the drugs!
I think it was a pill.
Celebrities probably have secret ways to get
priority vaccinations, but I suppose we're out of luck.
We're neither rich nor famous.
There's one way.
Next on the list after doctors are...
Pregnant women.
Ack! You're saying we should get pregnant?
It's the only way to ensure
you get priority vaccinations.
Kigu, do you know where babies come from?
Th-The pressure...
If you smooch the boy you like,
Mr. Stork brings you a baby!
That's right, you little cutie-pie.
It's fine that you don't know.
Tch. I'm getting sick of playing into
everyone's expectations of me.
Hm, but getting pregnant...
It's not as simple as that.
There's one way.
They call it "false pregnancy".
There's nothing in the rules against false pregnancy!
Virtual or real, it's pregnancy just the same!
It's a loophole in the law!
Okay, time to visualise it.
Imagine...
Contemplate the mysteries of life.
The path of evolution.
Look at that smile...
What are you imagining, you weirdo?
H-Hey! I wasn't thinking about
the process or anything of the kind!
She definitely was.
It's no use! False pregnancy isn't
going to work. I can't imagine it at all!
Why don't you start with a false relationship?
Start with your first meeting.
It's at a group blind date.
He asks you to meet up with him one-on-one.
And then?
Your relationship grows!
Ah, we're fighting!
He won't put the toilet seat down
when he's done using it!
But you make up—
We're fighting again!
He's throwing an ashtray against the wall!
But you make up again!
He confides in one of his female friends...
Next thing I know, he's telling me
"you'll be alright on your own".
This is all so sudden! I'm so hurt!
Self-inflicted wounds.
Um...
Uh, um...
She's completely shut out all noise.
She's floating on a sea of imagination...
She's literally floating!
Morning sickness?!
I'm craving something spicy!
Sure thing!
I brought you some curried seafood!
That smells gross!
I bought you something spy-cy!
That was terrible.
I brought you a pile of lemons!
Just put them down there.
It moved!
Her mind has complete control over her body.
Are we sure she's not
actually gonna give birth?
My stomach somehow feels bigger.
I think you just ate too much at lunch.
Music.
Music?
Antenatal care?
Play something suitable!
Right away!
The fetus doesn't want to listen to anime trash!
Who knows what that'll do to it?!
By the way, I've decided to call her Pree T Cure.
Or maybe Milky.
Or Horizon—
Sh-She's coming!
I-It's time!
Fetch some hot water!
Come on. Why are we going along with this?
How dare you! The mother-to-be
comes before everything!
I mean, that's an admirable sentiment, but—
There's a fundamental flaw.
She's not actually pregnant.
She's coming...
A-Are you okay?
She passed out.
Okay, show's over, guys.
Nothing to see here.
I wonder what was going on.
Oh, she's awake!
Where's my baby?!
Hush little one, go to sleep...
My baby...
W-Wait just a sec—
Pardon me, ladies!
Well, I guess she got priority treatment in the end.
I'm not sure it's the kind of treatment she had in mind.
Kukuru Anrakutei here.
Today's outlook is:
Good.
So good it might go up in flames.
I wish everything would just disappear.
No, I wish I could just disappear.
Here's the miraculous third episode of Rakugo Girls:
"Bath of Last Resort", "Asakusa Visit",
and "A Stroke of Raku".
Until then, look after your bodies.
Stay healthy.