"Don't worry, sir. I'm very aware of that."
"But if you know how much this plate is worth,
why are you using it to feed a cat?"
"Well, if I do this, sometimes I can sell
the cat to a sucker for two ryo."
Thank you for your continued patronage.
Man, that's a lotta rain.
It must suck when your glasses fog up.
They don't, but thanks.
Really? I thought glasses fogged up in the rain.
It's really pouring out there.
Your glasses must steam up something awful.
They don't!
Really?
Whew, it's pissin' down out there.
Must be tough when your glasses fog up!
They don't!
What's gotten you so steamed all of a sudden?!
Nothing sudden about it.
I held back for as long as I could, sorry.
Phew, it's raining cats and dogs!
Your glasses must be totally foggy.
That was Kigu! Why'd you hit me?
Shut up.
If we're going to talk about glasses,
we must follow tradition.
Face Sabae,
and bow!
Thank you!
Sabae is Japan's leading producer of glasses.
All right! You bespectacled bully!
You've punched me twice now!
It's time for you to say your pr—
She's strong!
I must've been overestimating when
I thought you had improved since last time.
Bloody hell!
Glasses-wielders aren't meant to be bruisers.
It doesn't suit your kind!
Nothing equips you for violence as well as glasses do.
What did you say?
When people are about to punch someone wearing glasses,
there's always a moment of hesitation.
"If I break their glasses, it might hurt them."
"It might hurt me."
"It might cost a lot to replace them."
"Is this morally right?"
All sorts of thoughts flash through their mind,
delaying their punch for a mere moment.
I see. So that's why my punch
was a fraction of a second too slow!
It's time for you to say your pr—
A fraction? That was a whole second.
So that's why Ushijima is so strong?
Would you slather someone in honey
and leave them in the woods like he does?
Of course not!
People that wear glasses shouldn't be violent.
Maybe I need glasses because I just don't see it!
Well, what would convince you?
The trope is that when girls take
their glasses off, they're super cute.
Take 'em off, Gankyou!
Where did your eyes go?!
Jab, jab, hook, straight!
The finisher...
Uppercut!
Your power level increases
when you're not wearing glasses!
The glasses were suppressing her power all along.
Best keep them on, for all our sakes.
That's enough already!
No more of this Bespectacled Bully character.
I'm not wearing glasses just to play a character.
Why don't we all try wearing glasses?
Will that help anything?
Which pair do you want?
Wow, she looks clever.
Very intelligent!
You look like you're up to something!
Very sinister.
A good little minion.
Very not-protagonist material.
Huh?
Don't copy my style!
I swear. Glasses aren't toys!
Not pulling any punches, are ya?
Please stop it!
We call Gan the Bespectacled Bully,
but she's really the most considerate person around.
Teto, you don't need to do this.
Please.
I must!
When Gan's at an offline meet-up where
more than half the attendees are wearing glasses,
she'll remove hers to help balance it out!
Yeah, but isn't it weird when eighty percent
of people are wearing glasses?
To be considerate enough to create
a glasses equilibrium for your surroundings...
Doesn't this move you?
Not especially?
Isn't it usual for offline meet-ups
to have lots of people wearing glasses?
I don't think it needs balancing.
Hmm, what if I put it like this?
Isn't it kind of irritating when the comedy teams
Ogi Yahagi and Tokyo 03 are on TV together?
I see what you mean. Too many glasses.
I feel like one of Tokyo 03's members should take his off.
Right?
Manga where all the brothers
wear glasses are also irritating.
Totally, totally.
Huh?
Imagine if the server at one of
those meet-ups also wore glasses.
It'd be awful.
You wouldn't be able to order hotpot.
Hotpot?
I win!
Aight!
They won't steam up!
Trying to steam them up on purpose is a bit mean.
That's right!
Foggy glasses are the ultimate humiliation
for people that wear glasses!
And you'd know because?
And just think about it!
If a celebrity's glasses fogged up, it'd be a travesty!
Even that one actor with
the enchanting smile wouldn't be safe!
What a dated reference!
If his glasses fogged up, he'd just look
like some nerd shopping for doujinshi!
That's not all.
I can imagine an even worse scenario.
Nipple tag!
Gotcha!
It'd be the end of the world!
Nope.
This is probably a bit much.
They finally steamed up!
They're... not...
They are!
Okay, now...
Nipple tag!
For real?!
How amusing.
Even with foggy glasses, my aim is unerring!
There!
Bullseye!
How are you so accurate?
I can sense a slight disturbance
in the flow of chi caused by a small bump.
That's my target!
I missed!
I won!
Looks like I escaped by the skin of my teeth.
Argh! I can't believe my aim was off!
Here?
Not even close.
Marii...
She doesn't realise she's the one being toyed with.
Right?
"The Black-Headed Gull" is a weird name for a train.
The proper name is the
"Tokyo Waterfront New Transit Waterfront Line".
Awfully long.
Is a Black-Headed Gull one with a lot of pimples?
Birds don't get pimples!
Probably because they moisturise.
It's a real bird.
Order: Charadriiformes, Family: Laridae,
Genus: Chroicocephalus, Species: C. ridibundus
Riding band?
Motorcycle gangs have been on the decrease recently.
It's hard to buy a bike in a recession.
Not to mention the upkeep costs.
The sea!
I wanna take a trip.
Isn't that exactly what we're doing right now?
She means someplace far away.
Planning to stow away?
No!
Being on a train reminds me of
when we were starting out.
Yeah, before they let us perform on stage.
Remember how they used to make us
practice our routines on the train?
Really puts the "train" in training.
The worst for me was practising while doing sit-ups.
Carrying Master's bag...
Cleaning Master's house...
Wiping Master's bum because he couldn't—
What was he, a sumo wrestler?
The worst for me was doing rakugo
while bungee jumping off the Rainbow Bridge.
That never happened!
I wonder what lies somewhere
over the Rainbow Bridge...
What's with this bend?
That's a ridiculous curve.
What's up, Kukuru?
I feel sick...
Sick?!
Do you get motion sick?
Not really, but that took me by surprise.
Want some water?
No...
Need some snacks?
That crap'll just make her feel worse!
When times are tough, sweets are always
there to put a smile on your face!
If she eats while feeling carsick, she'll throw up.
...or even if she doesn't eat.
You can do it, Kukuru!
You giving her permission?
No!
Just hang in there!
What's it they say?
Draw a person on your hand
and pretend to swallow him?
Unfortunately, that's barely half a person.
Whoops, silly me.
Go back to elementary school!
What'd you do that for?
It sounds cute.
"Berson".
Herson.
Whose son?!
Silly.
Writing it out gives a different feeling from drawing it.
Gestaltzerball!
Gestaltzerfall!
Got it. Look.
Why criticise her now?!
It's fine! Just swallow it, Kukuru!
Persona non grata will have to do!
Is this really fine? It's not what you'd normally do that for.
This is actually to stop you getting nervous, y'know.
Really?
So what should we do?
I heard something once!
If you train your inner-ear canals,
it's supposed to stop you getting sick.
How do you train those, though?
Do they even have muscles?
Apparently, a backwards roll is enough.
Like this, and...
A roll worthy of Mitsuko Mori!
Nobody would be able to tell that you
used to be scared of doing rakugo on the train!
You've come so far, Teto!
You're amazing... doing a backwards roll
on the train like it's nothing!
I guess I have come a long way.
All right, big-head!
Meanwhile, Kukuru's situation got even worse!
A great conflict is brewing inside her body.
What kind of conflict?
An argument between
her stomach and oesophagus?
Between her food and her stomach acid?
To return or not to return? That is the question.
You might feel better if you
look out of the window at the scenery!
Good idea!
Look! You can see the Statue of Liberty.
It's so big!
That's freedom for ya.
It's eleven metres tall and weighs nine tons.
Over there's the Odaiba Fuji TV building.
That's a big Ferris wheel!
This is bad. Her contents are about to breach!
Nothing for it. We may as well join her!
What are we gonna do if you get sick too?
It's... no use...
I'm so, so sorry...
I tried... but it was no good...
Should we get off? We should, right?
Yeah.
Are you okay?
Getting off fixed it!
That was quick!
Phew, that's good!
Um... where are we?
Let's go home.
Yup.
"That little scamp stole the boss's moonflakes?
What a cheeky blighter!"
"What happened next?"
"They turned into pieces of the moon."
Thank you for your continued patronage.
Beautiful.
Remind me, why are we watching this
in the dressing room?
Because it was too cloudy outside.
You can't really see much out there right now.
It's the 15th. It's meant to be a full moon.
Anybody got a pane of glass I can smash?
Why?
I'm gonna stick it to The Man!
Marii.
"The 15th" and the rock song
"A Night at 15" are unrelated.
You've gotta be kidding me!
Sometimes I feel like I never want to grow up.
Let's get back to watching the moon.
I don't see the rabbit.
There's meant to be a bunny in the moon!
Yeah, I don't see it either.
This is what rabbits look like.
That's so scary!
Bunnies don't look like that!
They're cute, like this li'l guy.
Moon viewing parties are really
just an excuse to eat sweets.
Not particularly thrilling.
I mean, you can eat anything associated with the moon.
What about ra-moon noodles?
This isn't very exciting!
What's that? Gonna tie us up?
Nope.
In southern Kyushu and Okinawa,
they play tug-of-war to celebrate the full moon.
This isn't exciting either.
In that case...
Let's praise the moon?
Don doko-doko-doko don doko-doko-doko...
Mighty moon!
You're amazing!
Glory to thee, mighty moon!
Don doko-doko-doko don doko-doko-doko...
Shut up!
You can watch without all that buzz!
Still doesn't look like a bunny.
I guess if you don't see it, you don't see it.
Apparently, people in other countries
see different things.
An old woman with a book?!
A girl with a bucket?!
To me, it looks like a shut-in whose mom
bought him the latest edition of Shounen Jump.
I don't... see it!
Ooh, now that you mention it, I think I see it.
Right?
There are no shut-ins on the moon!
I see...
A pervert sniffing someone's butt
at an impossible angle.
I see it, I see it.
I don't... see it!
Everybody sees different things.
What does this look like to you?
Don't Rorschach Test me!
Everybody's got their own way of seeing things.
I guess that's the instigator behind war.
We could achieve world peace if everybody tried
their best to understand other countries.
Yeah.
Even the countries who see a pervert
sniffing someone's butt.
That's not a country, that's just you!
There are some things you just can't help sniffing.
Yeah. Like glasses just after you take them off.
Your hairbrush after brushing.
Between a stuffed toy's legs.
Talk about perverted!
Shut up!
It must be a pretty big rabbit.
How many metres tall must it be to be visible from earth?
Metres? More like kilometres.
The diameter of the moon is 3,474 kilometres.
I can't imagine how big the rabbit would be.
The diameter of Tokyo Dome is 244 metres, so...
Hello?
Why is it always Tokyo Dome when people
are making size comparisons?
I guess it's easy to understand.
But what if you've never been there?
What is it?
Master's lost his rabbit.
He asked us to keep an eye out for it.
His rabbit?
Unbelievable.
Master's rabbit!
Humongous!
A r-rabbit!
No doubt about it, a rabbit!
A rabbit!
A pervert sniffing someone's butt
at an impossible angle.
Holy crap!
We have to calm this bunny lord down somehow!
A feast! Let's hold a feast!
What the hell is this?
Master's gotta be inside.
How are we gonna get it to go home?
Let's sing a song that'll make it homesick!
That mountain where we chased rabbits
That river where we caught-
Why?!
I guess it didn't like the rabbit chasing.
As punishment, we'll all do ten bunny hops!
That just fuelled its anger!
What would make the bunny lord happy?
I've got it! Rabbits die if they get too lonely!
Let's all be bunnies!
Here you go, Lord Bunny.
How's that feel?
Are you hot?
Let me scratch that.
How was that?
Why?
Does this rabbit die if it's not left alone?
The only way to fight it is as its natural enemy: a tortoise!
That was useless.
Brutes like this only respond to authority.
Grovel at the feet of Princess Kaguya,
the moon's most powerful denizen!
It carried her off.
That's Princess Kaguya for you.
Off they go, back to the moon.
Hey, look at the moon.
It looks like Marii's getting her butt sniffed.
Buratei Marii here.
How have you been, esteemed guests?
The whaddyacallems, cumulonimbus clouds?
When I see them piling up and up and up,
I know it's summer.
I wonder if Laputa's hidden inside?
Here's what's in the fifth episode of Joshiraku:
"Praise the Girl", "Trendy Town",
and "A Farewell to Glasses".