Parody on the magazine, Hanako, a publication by Magazine House.
which features the Ebisu-Daikanyama-Nakameguro areas. Its
target demographic is woman in their twenties.
Parody on the magazine, Hanako, a publication by Magazine House.
which features the Ebisu-Daikanyama-Nakameguro areas. Its
target demographic is woman in their twenties.
The "Destroyed music that pops uselessly" was also featured on
the advertisements for the A Certain Scientific Railgun OVA in
2010, which was done by the same studio as Rakugo Girls.
The "Destroyed music that pops uselessly" was also featured on
the advertisements for the A Certain Scientific Railgun OVA in
2010, which was done by the same studio as Rakugo Girls.
The chapter this section adapts came out
on February 9th 2010, so they had to
change the dates around a tiny bit.
The chapter this section adapts came out
on February 9th 2010, so they had to
change the dates around a tiny bit.
Ichikawa Danjuurou, the 11th person to hold the Ebizou title.
His name and many escapades get brought up often in this show.
In 2006, The Telegraph newspaper went as far as to label
him the Brad Pitt of kabuki. Additionally, he gained some
notoriety for a brawl incident in 2010.
In 2006, The Telegraph newspaper went as far as to label
him the Brad Pitt of kabuki. Additionally, he gained some
notoriety for a brawl incident in 2010.
The elephant censor bleeps help confirm it's Ebizou,
as "elephant" in Japanese is zou.
In Japan, it's customary for boys to give girls chocolate
for Valentine's, and girls to give boys a different gift on
White Day the following month. Not the other way around.
In Japan, it's customary for boys to give girls chocolate
for Valentine's, and girls to give boys a different gift on
White Day the following month. Not the other way around.
S was slang in all-girls' schools in the Taisho and Showa
periods and refers to same-sex love. It stands for
Sister. It's not the S for sadist, though they certainly
dominated the hearts of many young maidens.
S was slang in all-girls' schools in the Taisho and Showa
periods and refers to same-sex love. It stands for
Sister. It's not the S for sadist, though they certainly
dominated the hearts of many young maidens.
Prince was often used to refer to more tomboyish female
students, and may have been inspired by Takarazuka Revue,
a Japanese all-female musical theatre troupe.
Prince was often used to refer to more tomboyish female
students, and may have been inspired by Takarazuka Revue,
a Japanese all-female musical theatre troupe.
Otoko no ko, as used by Marii here, refers to a man who looks very feminine.
In English, the common way to call them nowadays is femboys.
Cross-dressing is the act of dressing as
the opposite gender they identify as.
Reference to a line spoken by Optimus Prime
in the Japanese dub of Transformers. This is
usually a death flag, however.
Reference to a line spoken by Optimus Prime
in the Japanese dub of Transformers. This is
usually a death flag, however.
Parody of Time Bokan, where the narrator
uses this same turn of phrase.
Pun on saibou (sewing) and the chant "say ho",
often found in hip-hop and similar genres.
She mentions Shinbashi, an area in Tokyo's business district.
It's a common place for interviewers to ask for the "honest
opinions of workers" for TV programmes.
She mentions Shinbashi, an area in Tokyo's business district.
It's a common place for interviewers to ask for the "honest
opinions of workers" for TV programmes.
André from The Rose of Versailles. However,
Marii is making it sound like she's Oscar
from the same anime.
André from The Rose of Versailles. However,
Marii is making it sound like she's Oscar
from the same anime.
Notice how she's walking pigeon-toed
to appear more feminine?
Asakusa has been an entertainment district since the Edo period,
and has been a mecca for movies and popular entertainment since
the Meiji period.
Asakusa has been an entertainment district since the Edo period,
and has been a mecca for movies and popular entertainment since
the Meiji period.
There used to be many vaudeville theatres as well,
but as the number of visitors decreased post-war,
they gradually went out of business.
There used to be many vaudeville theatres as well,
but as the number of visitors decreased post-war,
they gradually went out of business.
The "Thunder Gate", the main gate of the Sensoji Temple.
It features the Wind God and Thunder God on its sides,
and a large lantern hanging from the centre. Large parts
of it were damaged in the fire of 1865.
The "Thunder Gate", the main gate of the Sensoji Temple.
It features the Wind God and Thunder God on its sides,
and a large lantern hanging from the centre. Large parts
of it were damaged in the fire of 1865.
When Konosuke Matsushita, the founder of Matsushita
Electric Industrial Co. Ltd. (now Panasonic), fell ill in
1960, he visited Sensoji Temple and made a personal
donation. After his recovery, Kaminarimon was
reconstructed for the first time in 95 years.
When Konosuke Matsushita, the founder of Matsushita
Electric Industrial Co. Ltd. (now Panasonic), fell ill in
1960, he visited Sensoji Temple and made a personal
donation. After his recovery, Kaminarimon was
reconstructed for the first time in 95 years.
Walter Spies, a German painter who moved to Bali.
An Italian liqueur, originally coloured with carmine dye,
which was derived from crushed cochineal.
Inspired by the Arch of Titus in Rome, Napoleon Bonaparte,
following the Roman tradition, ordered the construction of
the Arc de Triomphe in celebration of his victory in the
Battle of Austerlitz in 1805.
Inspired by the Arch of Titus in Rome, Napoleon Bonaparte,
following the Roman tradition, ordered the construction of
the Arc de Triomphe in celebration of his victory in the
Battle of Austerlitz in 1805.
The gate was commissioned by King Frederick William II of
Prussia as a sign of peace and built between 1788 and 1791.
Japanese sports festivals have their roots in the Naval Academy's 1874
athletic meet (known as the Kyotogyo), guided by British instructors. By
1883, similar events were held at the University of Tokyo, prompting the
Ministry of Education to advocate for sports festivals in schools nationwide.
Japanese sports festivals have their roots in the Naval Academy's 1874
athletic meet (known as the Kyotogyo), guided by British instructors. By
1883, similar events were held at the University of Tokyo, prompting the
Ministry of Education to advocate for sports festivals in schools nationwide.
The sports festival march, Alte Kameraden, is a German military
march and has become a standard tune for such occasions.
This sign to the left says Annual Toothpick Purification
and Flavour Offerings Ceremony: Rai Mountain, and is an
annual event held on June 18th at Sensoji Temple.
This sign to the left says Annual Toothpick Purification
and Flavour Offerings Ceremony: Rai Mountain, and is an
annual event held on June 18th at Sensoji Temple.
This line shows up in the Dragon Quest games when
a monster wants to be recruited into your party.
In Asakusa, visitors partake in a ritual at Senso-ji Temple,
where they purify themselves with incense, write wishes,
make offerings, and ring bells to seek divine favour.
In Asakusa, visitors partake in a ritual at Senso-ji Temple,
where they purify themselves with incense, write wishes,
make offerings, and ring bells to seek divine favour.
Only Kigurumi is drinking a non-alcoholic beverage.
This is because she's actually underage.
That said, in the rakugo community, only Seconds and
above are allowed to drink, even in private. So Tetora
and Kururu should not be drinking.
That said, in the rakugo community, only Seconds and
above are allowed to drink, even in private. So Tetora
and Kururu should not be drinking.
They're drinking Hoppy, a low-alcohol beverage
originating from Kamiya Bar in Asakusa in 1948.
Go-honzon, the main subject of worship at a temple.
The Asahi Flame, claimed to represent the "burning heart of Asahi beer".
It's often colloquially coined the "golden turd", and in turn the Asahi
Beer Hall itself is called the "poo building".
The Asahi Flame, claimed to represent the "burning heart of Asahi beer".
It's often colloquially coined the "golden turd", and in turn the Asahi
Beer Hall itself is called the "poo building".
The joke here is that Marii was asking for un (luck),
but she was blessed by the unko (turd).
This title is a reference to the rakugo play, "Sanada Kozo".
"ZOO" is from the group of the same name,
who sang the original Choo Choo TRAIN song
used as the punchline in this episode.
"ZOO" is from the group of the same name,
who sang the original Choo Choo TRAIN song
used as the punchline in this episode.
The translation focuses more on Tetora's luck.
"Raku" is how "Luck" is be pronounced with a
thick Japanese accent.
The translation focuses more on Tetora's luck.
"Raku" is how "Luck" is be pronounced with a
thick Japanese accent.