Thank you kindly for your attention
oato ga mata yoroshikute
I hope to have it again and again
osaki mo mae mo yoroshiku ne
Twing-twang twing-twang-twong
chin-ton chin-ton-shan
The theater's full
jounai manjou
Mysteries are fun
nazotoki dokidoki shinan
Tricks are fun as well
shikake ga ariari desu
We can solve girly problems by throwing dice
joshiteki onayami wa sugoroku sai wo futte
(really?)
(hai hai)
It's not one nor six, but nine
ichi de mo roku de mo nain
(really?)
(sou kai)
The stakes are high, but you can get a sign
ichi kake bachi ka de sain
(really?)
(sou kai)
I don't really see how that's related
hanashi no tsunagari ga miemasen ne
See, this looks like it's gonna be fun
oya omoshiroku narisou na yokan wa
(see, see?)
(oya oya desu)
Or am I just seeing things?
me no sakkaku desu ka
I don't even care
iya soredemo kamawanai
Come on, everyone
hai minna
Let's spin!
mawatte
Front and back, let's just turn it around
omote mo ura uragaeshite
You can turn the story upside down too
dondengaeshi mo yoshiyoshi
Let's go on, ladies first
osaki ni ikou saa douzo
I hope to see you around again and again
osaki mo mae mo yoroshiku ne
The backstage is the main stage
ura butai ga hare butai de
That's where we can chat idly
muda uchibanashi mo yokayoka
Thank you kindly for your attention
oato ga mata yoroshikute
I hope it was a good comedy
osaki mo shiroki gokuraku da
A comedy, a comedy
gokuraku da gokuraku da
A comedy from the comedy heaven
arayotto gokuraku joudo ringu
Twing-twang twing-twang-twong
chin-ton chin-ton-shan
"Dear, it's started snowing again."
"I see."
"Then it's time to open my bottle of snow-watching sake."
A
A Bath Beyond
Say, girls.
Who would you give chocolate to on Valentine's?
On Valentine's?
It's right around the corner.
Only... six months away.
That's like 20 corners away!
So, who would you give chocolate?
I'd give it to E**zou.
E**zou.
Oh? Figures we'd all pick E**zou.
At least try to lie!
He's a kabuki actor. I can't get enough of him.
Why are you talking about giving chocolate anyway?
Huh?
You're supposed to receive it!
Huh?!
Ms. Marii! A delivery!
Hmm, Marii really is the type who would get chocolate from girls.
There's a Marii at every girl's high school.
She's the S. The Prince S, that is.
Aren't you going a bit too far?
It's just not right for a girl.
Maybe she's actually a boy?
Suddenly, we've all started to doubt him.
Don't be stupid!
Just look at me. What's boyish about me?
That's right! It's mean of you to say that she might be a boy!
Kigu...
She might be a boy dressed up as a girl!
That's true.
Sorry for saying you might be a boy.
Hold on a minute!
It's one thing to call a girl a boy,
but it's another thing to say she's a crossdressing boy!
I'm no boy! And I'm definitely not a crossdresser!
But it'd all make sense if she was a boy.
His speech is so unrefined...
This is just the standard rough Tokyoite dialect!
Goddammit!
Marii is from Tokushima.
Limes
Whirling
Lake
Awa dance
Is he acting like a Tokyoite to
disguise being a crossdressing boy?
Whirling
Lake
It's not an act!
Limes
Awa dance
Whirling
Lake
Awa dance
Whirling
Lake
Awa dance
Whirling
Lake
Awa dance
Whirling
Lake
Awa dance
Whirling
Lake
Awa dance
Girls, you're being mean!
Tetora...
Even if Marii is a boy, I'll treat him how I've always treated him.
Marii is still the same Marii.
Hey...
You're right.
We're sorry, Marii.
Let's stay friends.
Our friendship is eternal.
That's not what you're supposed to apologize for!
I'm not a boy and I'm not a crossdresser either!
I'm a real, live girl!
They're backing away.
I'm telling you, I'm a woman!
You don't really doubt me, do you?
I don't doubt you.
Of course not.
Not at all.
They totally doubt me!
We don't doubt you.
If you're gonna be like that, then I'll prove to you I'm a woman!
Look!
What a manly, bold way to bare your chest!
Yeah, a girl wouldn't do that.
Then how am I supposed to prove that I'm a woman?!
Why not do something feminine?
Something... feminine?
What's feminine?
Well... For example sit like a girl?
You can do it!
Even you can sit like a girl!
Yeah...
See, I did it! Now can you accept I'm a girl?
I heard the pigeon-toed position
can really spring you into action.
It's because you did it so suddenly.
Sitting like a girl isn't easy for a beginner.
How about you just try standing pigeon-toed first?
Close your knees, open your ankles and turn your feet inwards.
See, you did it!
Now someone else flew away!
One more time! Let me try just one more time!
No more! You endanger the people around you!
Please! I can stand pigeon-toed!
At least practice in an open area!
Wait a moment.
I have a good idea how to make Marii stand pigeon-toed.
Let me explain.
Here we have Marii, who can't stand pigeon-toed,
sitting on the shoulders of someone who can.
The two of them together make a whole Marii.
This is a logical but revolutionary idea.
It's really pigeon-toed!
Pigeon-toed it is!
Hey!
It really looks like you're standing pigeon-toed, Marii!
I'm so happy for you, Marii!
Cheers!
Why are you having celebratory drinks?
The essential problem still remains!
Um, what were we talking about again?
About how could Marii prove that he's a woman.
It's one thing to do it from the outside,
but you could just display femininity from the inside.
Cry a lot?
Cooking?
Great!
I eat punks like you for breakfast!
Sewing?
Hey, ho!
Say win!
Stop! This is getting even less feminine!
What the hell do you girls think I am?!
Well, women talk about old grudges a lot.
That I can do.
Something happened!
Long ago...
Here we go!
Back in 3rd grade,
Hisamochi put eraser dust in my curry during lunch. I'll never let that go.
Yeah, like that!
Back in kindergarten,
I finally managed to memorize my lines as the fairy for the school play,
but I came down with a fever on the day of the play and couldn't go.
It's always like that. Fate's always so cruel to me!
I really wanted to be the fairy!
This is more like a drunk old man than feminine.
Yeah, she does bring up old grudges,
but it sounds like some old fart from Shinbashi.
A
Deliberation
It's all society's fault! They just don't understand!
A
End of
meeting
It's a close call, but we decided that counts as feminine.
Please continue.
When I was three, Maman blamed me for a vase that the cat broke.
She wouldn't listen to me no matter what I said.
I'm surprised you remember that...
Three days after I was born, the nurse picked me up,
looked around carefully, and switched me with another baby!
Damn you, Marquis! How dare you do this to Pierre?!
You will pay for this!
People! Follow me!
We are going to storm the Bastille!
Now she started talking about her previous life!
This might in fact actually be feminine!
But who are you?!
I am the captain of the French Imperial Guard from 18th century Paris!
You were a man in your previous life.
Why not just do something unmanly?
For example?
What would be manly? Drinking, gambling, and spending?
Drinking, gambling, and spending?
Fits perfectly.
You're so cool, Marii!
So I'm supposed to do the opposite, right?
What's the opposite?
Eating, saving, and selling?
Well, this isn't unnatural.
But it isn't exactly feminine either.
It's human at least.
We're running out of options.
Marii, let's take a bath together.
Then we'll be able to prove it.
A
This anime is
full of ordinary dialogue
so that viewers can fully
enjoy how cute the girls are.
You know what?
This isn't a matter of her being a man or a woman.
She's just a child.
A
Haroukitei Kigurumi
Here we are in Asakusa!
On lantern: "Kaminari Gate"
That lantern is so huge!
I can almost feel the gods blessing me!
The current Kaminari Gate and its lantern
were constructed in 1960 and financed by Matsushita Kounosuke's donation.
A
Visit To Asakusa
Kaminari Gate
There are so many foreigners.
This is something typical of Japan after all.
The Balinese Kecak was promoted by a German.
I really like the red of the gate!
Kaminari Gate
The Campari's red imitates that of a bug.
Why are you saying random stuff that I can't respond to?!
Learning is the shame of a moment,
ignorance the loss of a lifetime.
That's useless knowledge if there ever was such a thing.
Anyway, the Kaminari gate had been around for a long time before it looked like this.
Let's just drop it.
In we go!
Kaminari Gate
Clearly the Kaminari Gate is the king of gates.
Wouldn't it be the Arch of Triumph, globally speaking?
Très bien!
Don't forget the Brandenburg Gate in Berlin.
Prosit!
I guess the Kaminari Gate might be losing after all.
Speaking of gates, don't they have to lead up to a building?
What's behind the Arch of Triumph or that Brandy-whatever Gate?
Umm...
The Kaminari Gate leads to Sensou Temple.
The Arch of Triumph isn't really a gate. It's more of a castle or a monument.
A monument?
Wasn't it originally there to allow the army to pass under it
after they'd returned from war
to celebrate their victory and for anniversaries and such?
Does going through a gate make you happy?
They were just walking through it, right?
Perhaps it's like that arch at athletics competitions where you enter and exit.
A
55th Elementary School No. 3 Sports Tournament
So basically it's a checkpoint of sorts?
A
55th Elementary School No. 3 Sports Tournament
I guess so.
A
55th Elementary School No. 3 Sports Tournament
That's kind of a letdown.
It's a subjective thing.
Oh, right! Let's take a picture together!
Yes! Let's! Let's!
Why do they put themselves in the smoke?
Because they say that the smoke will cure you.
Cure me, huh?
Then I don't need it! There's nothing to cure here!
Your foul mouth could use curing.
Your bust as well.
Your fashion sense needs to be cured too.
What?!
And your social skills.
I see some awkwardness right now that needs curing.
Fine! I get it!
I just need to get some smoke on myself, right?!
By the way, do you read it Sensou Temple or Asakusa Temple?
Sensou Temple.
But the station is read Asakusa. Shouldn't it be the same?
And it's Kaminari Gate and not Rai Gate.
They should decide which character reading to use and stick with it.
Temples usually use the on readings.
Akihabara and Akibahara is annoying too.
You know, long ago it was called Akibahara.
Even now you abbreviate it Akiba.
Kichijouji is a complicated one.
The first two characters would read "Kisshou,"
but everything combined makes "Kichijouji."
Kokubunji would be just Kokubu without the last character,
but if you add it, you get "Kokubunji."
They should just be Kisshou and Kokubu!
Just decide which!
I hate it when people don't make things clear!
Then how about we make it clear?
A
Fortune
Number 64!
Misfortune?!
What did you get?
Little luck.
And you?
Misfortune.
And you, Kukuru?
Great misfortune.
There was such a thing?
"Waiting in vain."
"Relationship failure."
"What is lost is lost forever."
"Sickness prolonged."
"Bad business."
"Travel postponed."
"Eventual disaster."
Don't worry about it.
Sensou Temple is famous for its many fortunes with bad luck.
But isn't it wrong to make people feel bad?
Look at it in a different light.
It's more like they're warning you to beware of mistakes.
I see...
And what did you get, Teto?
Great fortune?!
That's not fair!
That's right! She's always been like that!
She has the devil's luck!
"All wishes come true."
"Business prospers."
"Short waiting times."
"Victory in all conflicts."
It's your reward for being a good person. It's not absolute.
Then how about you split your great fortune with us?
Cheers!
It tastes even better when someone else pays!
That's just so typical of you, Marii.
So by "splitting my great fortune," you meant I should treat you?
No sweat for you! Business will prosper!
I hope all your wishes come true as well, then.
Oh please, you know it doesn't work like that!
Here's your stew and cucumber!
You got it!
It's not a person, but it is something we've been waiting for.
Is this yours by chance?
I've found something I lost!
That's great fortune for you!
I've got a great idea! Be our patron goddess!
Oh, please...
Venerable Goddess! Please grant me luck!
Come on, how could I grant you luck?
Well, it looks like you've already got it on you.
A
Bouhatei Tetora
Indeed. As if protected by tetrapods to her front,
she always emerges unscathed.
How did it come to this?
A
Sanada Monk-ey
Damn, I'm so itchy.
You got crotch rot or something?
The hell are you doing?!
Sorry, mosquito.
What?!
Someone left the window open.
Sorry, mosquito.
A feint?!
I don't care if this place is infested with mosquitoes!
No one gets away with hitting me!
She's improved.
There are no openings in her defense.
Whoever moves first gets done.
Itchy!
"Whoever moves first gets done," my ass!
We're all done for, aren't we?!
Those meanies ate me alive while I was sleeping!
Why are you the only one who didn't get bitten?
I wonder...
A draft?
The air flows differently there.
So even if a mosquito tried to get close to her, it'd get blown away.
And that's why she's the only one who didn't get bitten?
She's always been like that.
First falls the snow, snow.
Then comes the hail, hail.
The mor—
Even if everyone else around her got into a mess...
She alone would always emerge unscathed.
Ah, we'll be late!
Due to a signaling malfunction, train operations are suspended indefinitely.
She always has the best possible luck.
It's not like that!
A tea stem!
That was just by chance.
You got a 500 yen bill?
It's worth the same as those coins...
This is ridiculous! Since when do walls just come crashing down?!
Ah, sorry!
We're installing soundproof panels, so this is just a temporary measure...
How is she so favored by the gods?
Maybe we're favored by the demons.
Could it have something to do with my daily routine?
Daily routine?
What's this? Pictures by a stalker?
I'm no stalker! I just took pictures of Tetora's routine!
Let's use these to shamelessly rip off the way she acts!
You mean, follow her example.
But she isn't doing anything particularly good either...
She must be, to be favored by the gods like that!
I think this picture's the most significant.
Isn't she just watching TV?
But it's quite an old analog one.
Everyone watches digital terrestrial these days.
Terrestrielk and Analocub are no use anymore.
Not that Analocub was ever any use to begin with.
Terrestrielk had it rough, always having to wear that yellow swimsuit and then undress.
The undressing part was someone else.
But it's not even about digital terrestrial anymore.
The point is she treasured her TV so much she even put up with its old analog tuner.
In other words, we must treasure our stuff!
Isn't that a good deed?
I see.
And that TV is right here.
You stole it?!
That's such a mean accusation.
I asked for her permission to take it.
My TV? Sure, it doesn't have much longer anyway.
So if we watch this, we can earn the gods' favor!
What the bloody Mary?!
Where are your gods now?!
Oh, so it broke after all?
It'd been making this weird noise since last week...
And you friggin' brought it here?!
I tried to stop her.
Wait a moment!
So it was going to explode in Tetora's room?
Her ability to avoid danger is truly incredible!
I'm gonna follow Teto around!
If I follow you and copy everything you do, I'll be safe!
What are you saying?!
Me too.
Then me too.
Guess I've got no choice.
I'll be the tailblazer.
This is so weird...
Teto moved!
Gotta copy what she did!
Kigu moved after Teto!
Gan moved after Kigu after Tetora!
Gotta copy what she did!
Kukuru moved after Gankyou after Kigu after Tetora!
Copy what she did!
This is...
Miura Toshihiro
Born in 1970. Graduate of M University.
He is a famously  shrewd producer who
has brought the world great songs like
"Ah, Our Goddess", "It's Love!" and "Onward!
Attack of the Titans".
...new!
Breakdance rakugo is totally new!
A
First Dance Rakugo in the world!
hitotsu norikireba atarashii jibun ga ugokidasu yo
If you can overcome this, you can find your new self
A
Edo Exile
tabidachi no reeru nara sugu me no mae ni aru
The train to the future is right before your eyes
kesshite nakusenai yume ga aru mamoritsuzukete ikou
This dream mustn't be lost, so let's protect it together
togirenai monogatari kimi dake no mono
An endless tale that's only yours
oh yeah
Oh yeah!
Fuck this shit!
We want rakugo!
I'm too young to die...
This is tough.
Why isn't Tetora here?!
Her train broke down, then when she tried to take a taxi, the highway was jammed.
Her ability to avoid danger is truly incredible!
Indeed.
She always emerges unscathed.
As if protected by tetrapods to her front.
Sorry, girls!
I bought you a watermelon to say sorry for not making it on time.
A watermelon!
It's imported, but it was cheap!
Just a sec, I'll go get a knife.
A
Live long, live long and prosper
jugemu jugemu gokou no surikire
May great wealth await you wherever you go
kaijari suigyo no suigyou matsu
Even in different lands and under different skies
unrai matsu fuurai matsu
May you always have your daily bread
kuuneru tokoro ni sumu tokoro
And always be brimming full of life
yaburakouji no burakouji
Like the long-lived king Shuringan
paipo paipo paipo no shuuringan
And his dear wife Gurindai
shuuringan no guurindai
And their children Ponpokopi and Ponpokona
guurindai no ponpokopi no ponpokona no
Live a long and blessed life
choukyuumei chousuke
Let me have a bit of your time
choi to jikan itadakimasu
Please listen closely
goseichou kudasai
A
We're ready
totonoimashita
You write it "laughing"
warau koto to kakemashite
You read it "let's party"
omatsuri yarou zo tokemasu
And the point of it is, the point of it is...
sono kokoro wa sono kokoro wa
That everyone will be happy!
dochira mo happi ni naru deshou
Thank you kindly for your attention
oato ga yoroshii you de
Laugh, laugh, hey, let's laugh
waraou waraou sa waraimashou
Life may be hard, but let's laugh
konna jidai koso waraimashou
Laugh (yeah yeah)
waraou (soiya soiya)
If you cry, you lose
naitara make da
So just laugh until your sides ache
yakekuso waraimashou
Life may have its ups and downs,
haranbanjou sui mo amai mo
But great Japanese can get over it
norikoeta appare nipponjin
Laugh, whatever time may bring
waraou donna toki de mo
Laugh until you run out of breath
nanikuso waraimashou
Who cares where you are? Just laugh
kuuki nante yomazu ni warattoke
Smile (smile), smile (smile)
egao (egao) egao (egao)
Smile and the world will smile back at you
warau kado ni wa fuku kitaru
A
Preview
I am Kuurubiyuutei Gankyou.
Thank you very much for your continued appreciation.
To be honest, having to speak in a situation like this makes me nervous.
I can hardly understand people who have no trouble speaking in front of others.
They must have nerves of steel.
That said, we have made it to the fourth performance of Joshiraku.
Glasses Girl, Nausea at Sea and Eye of the Rabbit will be aired.
A
Glasses Girl
Nausea at Sea
Eye of the Rabbit