"Oh look, dear. It's snowing."
"That's okay. I've drunk so much sake,
I'm wearing a sa-cape."
Hey, everyone.
Who will you be giving Valentine's chocolate to?
Valentine's?
It's not long now.
About... another six months?
Your bar for "not long" is way off!
So, who are you going to give chocolate to?
Me? Ebi***.
Ebi***.
Oh, looks like we're all going for Ebi***.
Y'all are full of bull!
Kabuki? More like ka-bae-ki, am I right?
You guys are such idiots, y'know.
Giving away chocolate?
Chocolate is for receiving.
Huh?
Delivery for you, Miss Marii!
Marii's the type of woman who
gets chocolate from other women.
There's a Marii at every all-girls school.
I dunno if you'd call them dominant
or tomboys or what.
That doesn't account for getting
so many gifts, though.
Maybe we're making an incorrect assumption.
Could Marii secretly be a guy?
Sounds like everyone's getting suspicious.
D-D-Don't be so ridiculous!
Just look at me! What part of me looks like a boy?
Yeah, Marii doesn't look like a boy at all!
Aw, Kigu!
He's obviously taken a lot of care with his disguise.
She's right.
We shouldn't have said Marii looks like a boy.
Wait just a moment!
I'd rather you thought I was a boy than
you thought I was a boy dressed as a girl!
I'm not a dude, and I'm not a cross-dresser!
Once you realise he's a boy,
it all starts to make sense.
The way he speaks is so aggressive.
This is just how Tokyoites talk!
You jerk!
Marii is from Tokushima.
Did you don this Tokyoite act
to bolster your disguise?
I didn't don anything!
Aren't we being a little cruel?
Aw, Tetora!
Even if Marii is a boy, that doesn't mean
I'm going to treat him any differently.
Marii is still Marii. That hasn't changed.
Ugh, come on.
You're right.
We're sorry, Marii.
Let's keep being friends.
We're BFFs forever!
That's not what you need to apologise for!
I'm neither a boy nor am I cross-dressing!
I'm a bloody girl!
Oh, they're scared.
I'm a girl!
You guys don't actually doubt me, do you?
We don't doubt you.
We don't doubt you at all.
You lot totally doubt me!
We don't doubt you.
If that's all you have to say,
you've left me no choice.
I'll prove once and for all that I'm a girl!
Behold!
Undressing like that is pretty masculine.
Yeah, a lady would never undress
out of the blue like that.
Then what's it gonna take to prove
to you that I'm a woman?
How about showing us some ladylike behaviour?
Ladylike behaviour?
What kind of behaviour counts as ladylike?
Hmm... For example...
How about sitting like a lady?
You can do it!
Even you can sit in a ladylike way!
I-I know I can!
There, I did it!
Will you just admit I'm a girl already?
The inner thigh contains
a great deal of potential energy.
Seems like that was a little much.
Maybe sitting like a lady was
too high for the first hurdle?
Why don't we start with standing like a lady?
Knees together, heels apart.
Big toes pointing inward.
There! That's it.
This time the energy was transferred
to the surrounding area!
O-One more time!
You gotta let me try one more time!
No way! It could cause untold damage!
Please! I can do the standing thing, I swear!
At least practice somewhere with open spaces.
Hold it.
I've just had a great idea.
Allow me to explain:
Marii, who can't stand in a ladylike way,
supplies only the top half,
while the bottom half is provided by
someone with the ability she lacks.
Together, they form one ladylike Marii.
It's out-of-the-box but completely logical.
He's doing it!
He really is.
Shaddup!
You look so ladylike, Marii!
You did it! You really did it!
Cheers!
What are y'all celebrating for?
We haven't solved the original problem!
Which was... what again, exactly?
We were wondering how he can prove he's a girl.
Oh, that's right.
Forget about the outside. Why don't you
show us how feminine you are on the inside?
Like being quick to cry.
Cooking!
Piece o' cake!
I'll stir up somethin' up for y'all scumbags!
Entertaining guests.
Say "ho"!
This is no good! You're slipping further
and further from femininity!
Say "ho"!
What the hell kinda ideas
do you have about me?!
One thing girls often do
is harp on about past incidents.
Okay, okay. That I can do.
Something's happening!
A long time ago...
He's got something!
...in the third year of elementary school,
Hisamochi put eraser shavings in my school lunch.
I'll never forgive him.
That's it! Keep going!
When I was in kindergarten,
I was cast as a fairy in the school play.
But on the day of the performance,
I had a fever and had to stay home.
Always the same story.
Always a victim of bad luck.
I wanted to be a fairy, dammit!
This is less like feminine complaining
and more like drunken muttering.
He's harping on about past incidents alright,
but he seems more like an old guy in a pub.
Everyone is so rude.
Nobody understands me.
I judge the defendant just about ladylike.
Please continue.
When I was three years old, my mom blamed me
for breaking a vase when it was the cat's fault.
No matter what I said, she wouldn't listen.
Y-You've got a good memory.
Three days after I was born!
While holding me, the nurse surreptitiously
switched me for the baby next to me.
Swine of a duke! How dare you, Pierre!
This is unforgivable!
Everyone, after me!
To the Bastille!
Marii's regressed to a former life!
Maybe this is ladylike.
Who are you?
Captain of the Imperial Guard,
living in 18th century Paris!
So you were a guy in your past life? Figures.
What about trying the complete
opposite of manly behaviour?
Meaning?
Hmm, they say the manly pursuits
are drinking, spending, and partying.
Drinking, spending, and partying?
That suits Marii to a T.
Pretty cool!
Hey! Aren't I supposed to do the exact opposite?
By "opposite", you mean...
Eating, scrounging, and working?
This suits Marii to a T as well.
Sure, but I wouldn't really call it ladylike.
Some ladies live like that, too.
There's only one option.
Marii, let's take a bath.
That'll get us all the proof we need.
I have to say...
In the end, I'd say neither "man" nor "woman" fits you.
But "child" is perfect.
It's Asakusa!
Now that's a big-ass lantern.
I feel like this is gonna be a blessed day.
The Kaminarimon gate and the lantern
were donated in 1960 by Konosuke Matsushita.
There sure are a lot of foreigners here.
I guess this is a sight you can only see in Japan.
The Balinese Kecak dance was developed by a German.
Huh?
Anyway, I love how red this thing is.
The red of Campari originally came from crushed insects.
Why do you keep answering with
vaguely related facts that are hard to respond to?
Finding out is a moment of embarrassment,
but never knowing is a lifetime of shame.
I'd be perfectly fine with never knowing these things.
Yeah, but Kaminarimon's been around for ages,
even if it hasn't always looked like this.
So it's all good. Let's go!
Kaminarimon really is the ideal gate.
Isn't the Arc de Triomphe more popular worldwide?
Très bien!
There's also the Brandenburg Gate in Berlin.
Prost!
Poor old Kaminarimon.
Yeah, but a gate has to lead into a building.
That's what they're for!
Where do you end up if you go through
the Arc de Triomphe and the Brandenblah Gate?
Um...
Kaminarimon leads to Sensouji Temple...
The Arc de Triomphe isn't so much in front of
something as behind or after something.
After?
Originally, after winning a victory,
armies would march through the gate as
a celebration or to mark the anniversary.
So... that was enough to make them happy?
Just... passing through the gate?
It reminds me of those gates they have
to enter and exit a sports festival.
In other words, it makes you feel like
you're done and you can have a rest?
Yes, I suppose so.
It sounds kind of anticlimactic.
Well, I guess it depends on how you're feeling.
Oh, hey. Shall we take a photo together?
Yeah, good idea!
Why are people covering themselves in smoke?
They say that the smoke will help fix your bad points.
Bad points, eh?
Then I don't need to do it.
There ain't nothing wrong with me.
Saying that is a sign of a bad character.
The way you said it leaves a lot to be desired, too.
And you have poor fashion sense.
What the—
I don't think—
Plus your timing is terrible.
She's watching us very awkwardly.
I get it, I get it! I'll put my head in the stupid smoke!
So how do you pronounce it?
Sensouji or Asakusa Temple?
Which is right?
Sensouji.
But the station is called Asakusa. Isn't that confusing?
And it's Kaminarimon when you'd expect it to be Raimon.
It's like, sort your pronunciation out.
Temples are almost always "ji", though.
Akihabara and Akibahara are confusing, too.
Akibahara is actually the original pronunciation.
Nowadays people shorten it to Akiba.
Kichijouji is also kind of complicated.
If you remove the last character, it'd be "kisshou",
but for some reason, if you add "ji" it becomes "kichijou".
Likewise, if you remove the last character
from Kokubunji, it would be "kokubu".
But you add "ji" and suddenly it's "kokubun".
Kisshou and Kokubun are just fine!
They should make up their damn minds!
I hate it when things aren't clear.
Shall we go make things clear?
Number 64!
Unlucky?!
How'd you guys do?
I got a slighty lucky!
What about you?
Unlucky.
What about you, Kukuru?
Very unlucky.
Oh, no!
"The person you await will never arrive",
"Your engagement will be broken off",
"Lost items will never be found",
"Illness will persist",
"Business will be poor",
"Travel will be postponed"...
Everything's going to go poorly!
Don't sweat it!
Sensouji is famous for giving out
a lot of unlucky fortunes.
Isn't making people feel crappy
the opposite of what a temple should do?
It's not so much that as helping people
be careful before they make any mistakes.
I see...
What did you get, Teto?
Very lucky?!
No fair!
Typical! She's always been like that!
Her luck is impossibly good!
"Your wishes will come true",
"Business will thrive",
"The person you await will arrive soon",
"You will overcome any conflict"...
You won't get the luck if you don't work hard for it.
So it's not a sure thing!
Fine, then why don't you share
some of that good luck around?
Cheers!
Ah! Tastes so much better when it's free!
That was a very Marii thing to say.
So sharing good luck means treating you to a drink?
Don't sweat it! "Your business will thrive", y'know!
I hope all your other predictions come true, too.
No way! I'm sure they won't!
Here are your tripe stew and miso cucumber!
It came true!
It's not an awaited person, but it's definitely
something we were waiting for.
I think you dropped this, miss.
The lost item!
That's "very lucky" for you!
And it seems to have transferred to you!
Wow!
O Lucky One, grant me good fortune!
I don't think it works like that!
But... it does look like you've been blessed from above.
It's as if she were a shoreline protected by tetrapods.
She always comes out of any situation unscathed.
What's her secret?
Gah, so itchy.
What's up? Got crabs?
What was that for?!
Mosquito.
Mosquito?!
Someone left the window open.
Mosquito.
Ah, now—
A feint, huh?
I dunno if this is still 'bout mosquitoes or what,
but nobody smacks me around
and gets away with it.
Her skills have much improved
since last time. This won't be easy.
The first to make a move will lose.
That itches!
"The first to make a move will lose", my ass!
We both lost in the end!
No fair! It bit me while I was sleeping!
How come only one of us was spared?
Hmm? Oh, I wonder!
A draft?
The airflow is different over there.
Even if a mosquito tried to make its way over there,
the draft would push it somewhere else.
So that's why she wasn't bitten?
It's always been like this.
Fall, fall, snow, snow!
Fall, fall, hail, hail!
Even if everyone else around her suffered,
she'd somehow always come out unscathed.
Ah, we're gonna be late!
Due to a signal failure, we are temporarily
suspending service on this line.
One way or another, she's always
been blessed with good fortune.
Don't be so silly!
Look! It's vertical!
That's just superstition!
Five hundred yen notes are rare!
Everyone's got five hundred yen all the same!
I don't believe this!
The wall just suddenly falling?
'Scuse me, ladies!
There'll be some disruption
while I put up the soundproofin'.
Why do the gods love her so much?
I think it's just that the devil loves us.
Maybe it's just that my usual behaviour is so good.
Usual behaviour?
What's this? You some stalker or something?
Hey, who are you calling a stalker?!
These are pics I took of Tetora
going about her business.
If we study these, we'll be able to ape
whatever worthy behaviour she's doing.
Use her as a model, you mean?
But she's not really doing any
particularly good deeds in these pics.
I don't buy it, not for a second! She's gotta be doing
something to have the gods on her side!
Take this for example!
She's just watching TV.
Nope. Look closer. It's an old analogue TV.
Everyone in the world's switched to digital.
Chidejika and Analoguma have been relieved of duty.
Analoguma didn't really do his duty, though.
Chidejika must have gotten tired of
getting in and out of that swimsuit he wears.
You're thinking of someone else.
Okay. Forget all this digital talk.
The key here is the disposition that
allows her to put up with this old analogue tuner.
In other words, we must treasure what we have.
Isn't that worthy behaviour?
Hmm. I see.
I've got that TV here.
You stole it?!
Is my reputation that bad?
I got permission, don't you worry.
My TV? Sure! It probably doesn't
have much longer anyway.
Now we just watch this and
wait for the divine blessings to roll in.
What the hell?!
I don't feel very blessed!
So it finally broke, huh?
About a week ago it started making
this weird buzzing sound.
Who in their right mind would bring that 'ere?!
I tried to stop her.
Wait.
So... by all rights, it should have
blown up at Tetora's place?
What kind of abnormal ability is this?
I'm sticking with you from now on.
Right behind you is the safest place to be.
Are you serious?
I'll follow suit, then.
Me too.
Fine, guess I'm the butt.
Weirdos.
Oh! Teto moved!
I've gotta do the same.
Kigu, who's standing behind Tetora, moved.
Gan, who's standing behind Kigu,
who's standing behind Tetora, moved.
I've gotta do the same.
Kukuru, who's standing behind Gankyou, who's standing
behind Kigu, who's standing behind Tetora, moved.
I've gotta do the same.
Gotta do the same!
Wh-What?
This is so fresh!
Rakugo breakdancing! It's something new!
This is crap!
Do some bloody rakugo!
They hate it...
This is terrible.
Where the hell is Tetora?
Apparently, her train broke down, so she got a taxi,
but the road was closed because of a sinkhole.
What kind of abnormal ability is this?!
See? She always comes out unscathed.
Just as if she were protected by tetrapods.
I'm so sorry I couldn't make it!
I brought a watermelon as an apology.
Watermelon!
I got an imported one because it was cheaper.
I'll go fetch a knife.
Gankyou Kuurubiyuutei here.
You have our eternal gratitude
for your continued patronage.
Formal announcements always make me nervous.
I don't understand people who can just
blabber away in front of strangers all day!
They must have nerves of steel.
At any rate, here's what's in
the fourth episode of Rakugo Girls:
"Glasses Girl", "A Good Day to Daiba",
and "Eye of the Bunny".