"Y'know, Teddy, did you ever consider
that the reason you're so stupid"
"is because you go on vacation all the time?"
"Oi, Yassan! I know I ain't the sharpest tool in the shed,
but what's that got to do with vacation?"
"Vacation means something's vacant."
"And vacant means empty."
"Much like your thick skull."
Thanks for your continued appreciation.
I knew it was too good to be true.
Say cheese!
Look! It's like you're on vacation abroad!
Maybe I should send it to my friends.
You got friends?
I'm sorry, Kigu!
Thanks for the text, Kigu!
That's cold. Stop.
Sorry, Kigu! Splash me some more!
My body cooled down again...
Want a top-up?
I don't know how you manage all those cold drinks, Gan.
Why do tropical drinks always come with two straws?
So couples can drink them together!
One day I wanna go on a fancy vacation with a boyfriend!
You mean to the dressing room?
Stop crushing her dreams, Marii.
You can't call it a fancy vacation...
if you're wearing a boring-ass swimsuit!
Yours is the most boring one, though.
Isn't that a school swimsuit?
Everybody knows
that school swimsuits are the most exciting of all!
There are people who think that, I'm sure...
School swimsuits always look so samey.
Are there specific regulations?
Like, "It has to be such-and-such".
Probably, but I think it's best to stay away from
anyone who knows too much about that subject.
Unless you have hours to waste.
"The old designs were much better
than the new ones, blah blah."
What's that mean?
Instead of the lower stomach and
crotch area being one piece,
there used to be a separation between them.
Some have strong preferences
when it comes to the name position label.
Whether it's the chest area, or the lower back.
True experts will also have
an opinion on the position of the tag.
And that's not to mention white swimsuits.
Forgive me! I didn't know
you were so into school swimsuits!
Somehow they're all the same design, though.
Uniform designs are super varied,
so why not swimsuits?
I'm just gonna come out and say it:
swimsuits are the summer uniform.
The designs should be much more diverse,
just like the regular uniforms!
True. Some girls pick what school
to go to based on the uniform.
It'd only help if swimsuits also enjoyed that benefit.
And leave the door wide open
for freaks to flood these schools.
It's weird that no matter
the difference in academic performance,
every school's swimsuit looks the same.
They should make the angle of
the swimsuit match the school's score!
That sounds reasonable.
Yeah.
Marii, there's no way your score is that high.
You can't get more than 100.
You're like a 40 at best.
S-Stop!
Stop!
What have you done?!
Give it up already.
Reap what the post-war Japan's
academic score system sowed!
That stupid system is ass!
If you're against the scoring system,
then you must be in favour of...
Loose education!
Behold! A swimsuit for the loose
generation. It's even worse!
Gan, have a little dignity.
Does this mean you were part of generation loose?
It looks really sloppy.
Are you sure you didn't just
accidentally order the wrong size?
It's very hard to tell the size
from the catalogue alone!
Looks like you forgot to
check anything but the bust size.
Better than them being too small!
Sure, but it looks like you could fit
a whole extra Kigu in there.
What are you—
A perfect fit!
I can't believe you fit them both in!
Ah! I hate this!
Stop struggling! It tickles!
I'm gonna friggin' kill you!
This is scary...
Look, you've made Kigu cry.
Huh? What?
She suddenly started feeling like a daughter to me.
My little girl I carried in the womb.
Carrying her on your back must have
awoken your motherly instincts.
W-Would you... call me mom?
Uh...
Mommy.
My baby!
Mommy!
You're starting to feel like my actual mom.
We're one happy family!
What should we do?
Not sure there's much we can do.
I'm a little envious.
Mom...
Mom must smell so good!
That's from a children's song!
Let me smell you... just a little...
Go away! Stop sniffing me!
Let her smell you a bit.
Kukuru just wants to remember her mom.
The smell of soap bubbles!
I said stop!
There's no scent...
No way...
Ah! We can't let her down!
Here!
What's that?
Soapy water.
Smells of soap bubbles!
I'll friggin' murder you!
Sorry to keep you waiting, Gan!
You fell for the trap, right?
Had fun figuring out the Mitaka express?
Yeah...
That's Musashi-Sakai for you.
Sorry! Were you waiting long?
You fell for the trap, right?
The Express Train Overshoot Trap!
Yeah. I went too far and had to get off at Kokubunji.
That's Musashi-Sakai for you.
Whose bright idea was it to have a Musashi-Seki
and a Musashi-Sagawa as well?!
I got on the bloody Seibu line by mistake!
We covered that in an earlier episode.
That leaves just Teto.
Probs went to Musashi-Mizonokuchi by mistake.
Look, there she is.
What is she doing?
Oh, Gan!
I was just pretending to be a Musashi-Sakai
resident and feeling how nice it is.
It's always been the dearest wish of the residents to be able to
smoothly go between the north and south entrances.
Wow, dream bigger, guys.
Hey, don't be rude!
To Musashi-Sakai residents, this is their Berlin Wall!
It's been years of not being able to go
back and forth, despite being the same station!
Okay, shall we head out?
This is the Skip Street shopping mall.
Why's it called "Skip"?
Can you only go down it if you skip?
Skip, skip, skip!
Skipping does nothing for me.
You don't mean...
Don't you know how to skip, Kukuru?
I can't even imagine what that
would look like, to be honest.
Skip shopping mall...
It's like it's accusing me of something.
There's a Skip Village shopping street in Narimasu.
What kinda village is that?!
Everyone skips and nobody walks.
If you did that, you'd be out of
the shopping area before you knew it.
It used to be that in August, men would parade down
this street with their bellybuttons exposed.
Huh?
Not like that!
A traditional bellybutton dance!
They strip down to the waist, paint a face
on their stomach, and hide their own faces.
Oh yeah, I saw that in From the North!
It's a rip-off of the Hokkaido Bellybu—
"Homage", you mean?
Skip Street is scary.
Apparently, it's been replaced by a samba festival.
From bellybutton dances to samba...
Maybe the bellybutton dance was too sombre.
That was a truly terrible pun.
The next road is Doppo Street.
The kanji mean "walking alone"...
A lonely road...
The monument to the writer
Kunikida Doppo is just down here.
That's a pretty ridiculous name.
Right back at you.
What did he write, again?
"Musashi Plain", "The Couple From Kamakura",
"Meat and Potatoes"...
So Mr. Doppo wrote recipe books, too?
You're thinking of Mr. Noppo.
"The Couple From Kamakura" sounds a little bit dirty.
Doppo must be turning in his grave...
Is anybody else starving?
Let's go grab something.
It doesn't look like there's
anything special around here.
Wrong! Musashi-Sakai is the birthplace of oil noodles.
This is supposed to be
where oil noodles were first invented.
Some people say it was Sankou in Kunitachi, though.
Are oil noodles different from tsukemen?
With oil noodles, you stir in a thick sauce
and then add vinegar and chili oil.
Like bukkake udon.
What the hell is bukkake udon?
It's where you put the toppings on udon,
and then pour broth over it.
Ah yeah, sounds similar.
Let's stop yapping and go eat some.
No! I don't wanna!
How come? You don't like noodles?
It's just... the name of the restaurant...
The Wiener?
What's up with The Wiener?
Let's hurry up and enter The Wiener.
Quit repeating it already!
So I guess you'd never ride
the Wiener Linien subway line.
You'd never pet a wiener dog?
And you'd definitely never drink wine from Vienna.
Wiener Gemischter Satz.
That was so good!
Let's come back sometime!
Without that whole spiel next time, please.
Musashi-Sakai certainly has a lot of noodle places.
Maruko, Kiraboshi, Musashiya...
Not to mention GT Ramen.
What does the GT stand for?
Good Taste.
But sadly, GT Ramen closed down on July 21st.
Phewee, I'm stuffed.
I'd like a short breather.
I know just the place!
A café?
A cake shop?
This isn't what I had in mind,
but at least we got to sit down, I suppose.
I wanted to drink tea...
And eat cake...
You know what they say,
"If you want to have fun for a day, drink."
"If you want to have fun for three days, get married."
"If you want to have fun your whole life, learn to fish."
You want us to sit here fishing our whole lives?
That's exactly what they're doing.
They're catching crucian carp.
And we are?
Koi.
C'mere!
Scary!
Then don't feed them, numbskull!
I'm bored! I can't fish!
I guess the deep intricacies of
fishing are lost on children...
One to talk, aren't you?!
A water purification plant.
They've been selling "Tokyo Water" recently.
It's basically bottled tap water.
In Kyoto, they sell "Kyoto Water",
and in Osaka they sell tap water
under the name "Honmaya".
Then I guess the water from here
would be "Musashi-Sakai Water"!
I don't think that'd sell.
The Japanese Veterinary
and Life Science University.
There's a manga artist who went here!
Cool.
Asia University.
You can get in here by playing cup-and-ball.
Would that be a sports scholarship?
Musashino Place.
There's a library, a sound studio
where you can practice music,
and a performance studio for practising dance or drama.
Do you think there's somewhere to practise rakugo?
Probably not.
Well, that ended up being pretty fun.
We've gotta be careful not to get caught
in the Seibu Line Trap on the way back.
What's that?
Musashi-Sakai station isn't only
connected to the JR Chuo Line.
It's also on what's known as the Tamagawa Line.
Tamagawa Line?
First it was the Tama Line.
Then, the Koremasa Line.
Then, the name changed to the Musashi-Sakai Line.
Finally, they settled on the current Tamagawa Line.
It's like how frogs change name as they develop.
There are still plenty of people
who call it the Koremasa Line.
Shall we head home?
Wait, wait! We still haven't achieved our goal.
Goal?
What did you guys come all the way out here?
Something to do with that building?
Look.
We owe our existence to the solemn efforts
of a certain company there!
The reason we're here is
to offer them our encouragement!
And if they're up to episode eleven,
their schedule must be ruthless.
Please take good care of us.
"Ack, carrying that tree
really did a number on my neck."
"Well you know what they say,
Christmas'll crush muscles!"
"Lord have mercy on me for that one!"
Thanks for your continued appreciation.
Good job getting a Party Bucket!
Nope, look inside.
Grilled chicken!
Aw...
I forgot to make a reservation.
But you did get the bucket?
Hey, grilled or fried, chicken is chicken.
Let's have a toast!
Non-alcoholic for you, Kigu.
Merry Christmas!
Did everybody bring their presents?
Yeah!
Shall we hand out the gifts, then?
Counter-clockwise!
I know how this'll turn out.
Tetora will get the best gift.
This sucks so much.
And stop!
Open it!
That's from me! Isn't it Christmassy?
Sure, but what am I meant to do with it?
Wear it, silly!
This is useless once Christmas is over!
Aw...
Sweet chestnuts.
Ah, they're from me!
"Christmas" and "chestnut" both start with "ch".
What about the rest?!
Nice idea, but somehow I'm struggling
to be pleased with this.
There was a 1000 yen limit...
It's Christmas so I got you an ashtray.
Not you, too!
Mine is so big!
That's from me.
100% pure pulp toilet paper!
That's a very Marii present!
Got piss-all to do with Christmas, though.
Sorry, I didn't have time to buy anything.
No worries. Thanks!
That's the best one out of all of them.
Your nose is very red, Marii.
Like a certain reindeer.
I've got a bit of a cold.
Blow your nose.
By the way, shouldn't a Christmas Party have a tree?
I bought one online.
I thought it'd be here today.
You need to order them earlier.
Whatcha doing there, Teto?
Don't look!
So that's where you get material for your routine.
Hey, it's hard coming up with opening gags.
They always seem to know exactly
what you want to browse or buy.
It's a pretty amazing service for a rainforest.
Sometimes it's scary how accurately
they can pin down your interests.
When things are on sale,
I always end up buying them.
I forgot that I pre-ordered something
and bought it when it came out. Now I've got two...
But it's very kind how they say
"You last bought this in such month of so year".
My nose is all bunged up.
It's very red.
Delivery service!
It's here!
Whoops.
What's this?
I think it's the tree I ordered!
Isn't it a bit big?!
I couldn't tell how big it was from the website!
Check before you buy!
It's like the Amazon jungle in here.
How apt!
Hey! Is everyone still alive?!
Just about!
I'm alive!
The leaves are poking me and it hurts!
Well girls, the tree's here.
Time for our Christmas party!
Party?! Like this? Are you being serious right now?
Agh, these branches are so annoying!
Are you listening to me? You forgot to say
"I'm so sorry everyone"! Say it! I wanna hear you say it!
It's pitch black!
Starless and Bible black...
Darkness, surrounded by branches.
What on Earth are we gonna do?
Mhm? A single light, shining in the darkness.
And so, even though everyone had
made fun of her for her shining, red nose,
Marii ended up being of great use.
Am I a reindeer?!
Everyone, group up. Don't stub your toes!
We're going to rub a nose?
Just like the Maori of New Zealand.
They touch noses as a greeting.
I said "Don't stub your toes"!
A grubby rose?
What do you mean?
Don't stub your toes!
Use Marii's nose as a guide.
Follow the light!
Go towards the light!
Yes, we should go into the light...
No, wrong light! Wrong light!
Did she hit her head on a branch?
Don't leave us, Kukuru!
Towards the light, towards the light...
That's your cellphone!
Hey, what are you doing?
We could have used the light of the phone.
The Bespectacled Bully strikes again.
Who was that! Show yourself!
Gah! Stupid trees!
The time has finally come!
I'm the only one with the power to light my way!
Oh, the light went out...
Hope you're ready, Bespectacled Bully!
I've got years of pent-up retribution to unleash!
Ow!
Oops, wrong person.
Marii hit me!
Sorry, I didn't know it was you.
Marii's turned into a jungle guerrilla!
You never know when I'm going to
strike at you from the darkness of the jungle!
Who are you, Rambo?!
Where'd you get that from?!
From Amazon!
I bought something, too!
What are you, a Predator?!
Stop this! The dressing room can't take it!
Why do you look like that?
It's fluorescent paint from Amazon!
This is a mudpack I bought from Amazon.
What the hell have you guys been buying?!
Gan, are you okay?
If we're talking jungle films,
there's one thing you can't leave out.
Cannibals!
What's happened to your skin?!
The Yamamomo tribe!
This is scary. Somebody's gotta take her out.
There she is. I see her!
How...
Idiot. During a night fight, the person
emitting light is at a disadvantage.
It's gotten even brighter.
I guess when you punched her,
her nose swelled up and got brighter!
Oh, nice going!
But it's still dark.
Could we make it a little brighter?
For the greater good!
The light was so sublime that
it drew all kinds of people from near and far.
The delinquents who gathered
by the light of a convenience store.
Out of fried chicken? What a joke.
Couples visiting Don Quixote late at night.
Isn't that totally awesome?
The spirits of the dead.
Yes, we should go into the light...
The warrior of light, Haraguchi.
The fiber-optic-obsessed CEO.
Ota Hikari, followed by his companion Tanaka.
Bugs.
Squid.
What a fascinating tree.
This turned out to be a great
Christmas party in the end.
I've never...
I've never been to such a lively Christmas party...
Stop making this out to be a happy ending!
All it needs is Christmas boots to make it perfect!
I ordered some, you know.
Delivery!
This is too big!
It's hard to tell the size online!
I'm scared to see what happens at New Year!
I already ordered the bamboo decorations.
Thank you for your continued patronage.
I hope you'll forgive me for
not revealing my face or giving my name.
However, I'm sure we'll meet somewhere, someday.
For example,
right behind you!
Here's the penultimate episode of Joshiraku.
"Dreamer's Revenge", "Scary",
and "Blue in the Face".