Life's Butt a Comedy
Red Feather Donations
Entrance Ticket
Marii
Buratei
Rakugo Girls
Year Pass
Kukuru Anrakutei
Birds?
The Bear of Ueno
Standing Bar
Futa
Stand to attention and drink!
Watch out for dung
DANGER!
Gorillas hurl their dung
WARNING!
Hippos fling their dung with their tails.
Be careful of spitting camels
WARNING!
Bears have 5 fingers!!!
Rakugo Girls
Sleep-Talking
I went to Shirakawa
in Kyoto.
Nice.
I slept.
Liar.
Web
Wikipedia
Google
Asleep at
the wheel
Sleeping on
the job
Me!
Miss Glasses
Frames
Miss Young
Sunday
Miss
Chuo Line
Miss Tokyo
Metropolitan
Ordinance
Regarding the
Healthy Development
of Youths
Miss No
Make-Up
|||||||||||||||||||||
Next Time
① Pumpkin Band
② The Battle of Shinjuku
③ Cavity Beach