"I'm going on a trip to Antarctica."
"Nice, and maybe one day you'll be
able to go to Human-Arctica."
Thanks for your continued appreciation.
I sense danger afoot.
Why?
It's a holiday, but there were hardly any children in today!
Oh, you're right.
Well, rakugo's never really been
something that attracts kids, y'know?
But today's a holiday!
Other amusement and tourist spots
are overflowing with children!
They're pulling in children from far and wide!
We need to offer more services to attract children!
Kigu's wigging out!
It's true. Kigu's wigging out!
Kigu's gigging now!
It's true. Kigu's gigging now!
Thank you very much!
Kigu's giving big!
It's true. Kigu's giving big!
I give up! I give up!
Kigu's giving in.
It's true. Kigu's giving in.
Anyway, this doesn't help us
get kids to come to our shows!
Then why don't we introduce a Happy Meal-type thing?
Kids really like Happy Meals.
How about we add something extra with the entry ticket?
It can't be anything too fancy,
but what about trading cards?
Nice. It's pretty fun to collect all the types.
And if you collect all the cards in a set,
you get a special limited-edition card!
That's just a gacha system.
Okay then, collect all the cards to get a special gift.
Like an anime collector's edition?
Meet and greets!
Hopefully we can lure in some whales this way.
Yeah, but we're trying to target kids, not just anyone.
What do they like?
Round stuff!
Kids like round things.
There aren't any kids like that!
Well, I'm already contributing in my own way.
With your glasses?
Children do like round characters.
Maybe we should all try and have something round.
I feel like I've seen that character a lot.
I've gone with a circle-patterned kimono.
The circles are made up of smaller circles,
which are made up of even smaller circles,
creating an infinite mandala effect.
Are you tryna scare 'em away?!
If they're going to be scared, let them!
They'll never come again!
In that case, maybe I'll become physically rounder.
I'll get round by eating a lot!
Uh...
I don't think your body'll expand that much.
Can I have some?
Help yourself! There's plenty to go around!
Don't ler her fool you, guys!
She's the only one who can eat as much
as she likes without gaining weight!
She's planning to stay slim without
succumbing to the onslaught of calories!
How terrible!
Can't let your guard down for even a sec!
Don't you have any ideas, Marii?
I don't need brats to like me.
Ah, but you're...
Get off me! I don't have a Mongolian spot!
Enough of that.
This'll definitely make you popular with kids, Marii!
The question is, how best to display your butt on stage.
Showing your ass isn't something
that should be taken lightly!
Do it wrong and you'll be labelled an ass-flasher
and mocked for decades to come!
We'll always be remembered as that ass-flashing anime!
Ass-flashing anime?
Are you prepared to deal with that?
No! I didn't want any of this!
Have it your way. I won't stop you.
Do as you please.
I never wanted to flash my butt!
But...
If you don't show your butt, we'll never
get the kids to come to our show!
What?!
Marii exposing herself is the only choice we have.
I know you'll do the right thing!
What are you on about?
There are lots of ways to attract kids!
We have a lot of choices left!
Nope.
Not at all.
There's nothing we can do...
...but have you flash your ass.
We have no other choice!
Your viewpoint is too narrow!
Saying "There's nothing we can do" is how you end up
killing your family and turning the gun on yourself!
The decision has already been set in stone. Give it up.
When was it set in stone?!
Let's take one last trip to D*sney Land and Sea together.
We can stay at the M*racosta
and eat French food at Club **.
Then...
It's ass time.
This is stupid!
Marii, please listen to me.
You're not a child anymore.
You can talk until you're blue in the face.
You're blue in the butt!
Y-You've got me there...
Agh, what am I saying?!
I'm sick of this.
Stop moaning and just get your ass out!
Everyone! Get 'em off!
Lemme go!
No! That bruise is evidence of child abuse!
Huh? Anybody know this foreigner?
Child abuse?
What are you talking about? That's a Mongolian spot.
I've heard of this.
Only Asian people get Mongolian spots,
so there have been cases
where foreign doctors who weren't used to seeing them
mistook them for evidence of child abuse.
You Japanese are uncivilized brutes!
I'm taking this child into protective custody!
Let go of me!
He took her.
Hey, let's sing a song in memory of Marii.
Poor little girl, ashamed of her butt, her big blue butt.
Stolen away, far, far away, by a foreigner.
You don't think there are no kids here because
the foreigners kidnapped them all, do you?
Oh, maybe.
Makes sense.
Scary...
I'm so glad it's sunny out!
It's a perfect day for the zoo!
I haven't been to the zoo in ages.
Last time's gotta be two or three years ago.
Wow. I've got an annual pass.
I wouldn't have expected that.
When I've lost too much hope in humanity,
I recharge by spending time with quiet animals.
Should we start with the pandas or the polar bears?
If you see everything in order, you're bound to get tired
before you reach the birds and the petting zoo.
Birds?
Where the flamingos at?
Everyone knows flamingos are the stars of the zoo!
So you end up wasting your time taking pics
or whatever, and then you're in a hurry later on!
Just after you enter is when your energy's at its peak.
Everything seems cool and rare.
I wonder why they put flamingos at the entrance.
I heard the reason flamingos stand on one leg
is because the water they stand in is cool.
Maybe they're by the entrance
because it's sunnier there?
They're like old people lying in the sun!
Panda, panda!
Going straight to the pandas?
That's like sitting down
and going straight for the main dish,
or announcing contest results starting
with the winner, don't you think?
That's the Ueno Zoo for you.
Casually bringing out the big guns right away.
It shows their confidence in their zoo
being more than just the panda.
Either that or it's just like
"Hey, you came all this way to see the panda,
why not see the other animals while you're here?"
I think you might be reading too much into it.
Whatever. A panda's a panda!
Let's go check it out!
It's not moving!
Well, that's just how it goes sometimes.
Eating and sleeping in the same spot... pretty cushy.
What a life.
The panda couple's life gets streamed online, though.
Seriously?!
Their private lives broadcast to
hundreds of thousands of people...
They know you but you don't know them.
How terrifying is that?!
And once something's on the internet, it's there forever.
Make one mistake and they'll never stop flaming you,
and that data of your error will never go away.
The internet is so scary! You've got to be careful!
Anyway, aren't pandas cute?!
Your love for pandas suits you to a T, Kigu!
Pandas are the best!
I couldn't care less about pandas.
Their eyes are terrifying.
So, everyone likes the giant panda?
There's nobody who dislikes pandas!
Please take some time to think
of the lesser panda occasionally.
Originally, the word "panda" referred
to the smaller, brownish type.
But after the discovery of the giant panda,
the brown one got saddled with "lesser".
"Lesser"? That's kind of mean.
Don't worry, it's not a judgment.
It just means that it's smaller than the other kind.
It still sucks to be compared to someone else.
They should call it the red panda
or the standing panda, at least.
Not all of them stand up!
Giant pandas stand up sometimes, too.
Then the name is even lesser-suited!
Nobody's got anything to say about
the Chinese name, "great bear-cat"?
It's very clearly not a cat.
What about that one dude who claims to be
a cat despite being blue and round?
He's not a cat, he's a cat-shaped robot!
Popular things are popular whether
they're a bear, a cat, or a robot.
Bears are scary.
Brown bears are so smart and vengeful,
they've been known to wipe out whole villages!
If we're talking scary, gorillas throw their poop at people.
Hm? I'm sure I've seen a poop warning somewhere else.
Hippos! They use their tails to flick poop everywhere.
Camels spit.
What kind of fetish is that?!
What's your favourite animal, Kukuru?
Wait, don't tell us!
Let me guess. Giraffes, right?
I love giraffes.
Their long tongues are disguscute.
Huh? Thought it'd be the spectacled leaf monkey.
It'd fit you well.
My elementary school nickname!
Just because I wear glasses,
I had to endure years of being called
spectacled monkey, spectacled bear, spectacled
caiman, spectacled owl, and spectacled duck!
I'm fed up with it!
Soz.
I think my fave is the polar bear.
They're certainly good at running cafés.
And they're really cute as cubs.
They look like cuddly toys!
What about you, Marii?
Huh? Koalas or something, probably.
That's surprisingly normal.
I thought you'd say kangaroos.
How come?
I thought you'd relate to them.
When they lie down they look just like you.
Am I an old man?!
Marii's not an old man!
She's more of a kid.
So which animal is your favourite, Kukuru?
The naked mole-rat.
Ah! Gross! They're so ugly!
A rare rodent with a queen-based society.
They form colonies around one individual,
with multiple males and worker bees—
I mean worker rats.
They're your favourite?
Yeah. Also, they live for a really long time.
And they don't get cancer.
By the way, they say that the queen stops any usurpers
ousting her by covering them with her urine.
Urine?!
That's gotta put a dampener on their ambitions.
It'd work on people too, I guess.
Or they'd be really happy.
Do you ever learn something
you wish you could unlearn?
Oh! I've got some animal trivia, too!
A polar bear's skin is black underneath!
Isn't their defining feature being white?
And their fur isn't actually white either, but transparent!
Wouldn't that make them invisible? Not cute at all.
When giraffes go to sleep,
they use their back as a pillow.
Huh?
An elephant's top speed is forty
kilometres per hour. They're surprisingly fast.
Elephants.
What's up?
Faithful Elephants...
Stop! Don't even mention that!
Just the title is enough to tear me up!
Stop war!
Gon, the Little Fox.
Please stop! I don't wanna think about it!
The Happy Prince.
Poor swallow! Why didn't you fly south for the winter?
Tarou and Jirou.
They survived in Antarctica!
They were so brave!
Milo and Otis.
Hachiko.
Hachi!
We walked around a lot today.
But we didn't get to see everything.
There were lots of animals
I'd never heard of or seen before.
Let's come back sometime.
Pimo.
What's "Pimo"?
A mysterious animal that many have seen,
but few know where it comes from
or where its name originates from.
Does an animal like that exist?
Huh? Where?
Don't sleep...
What if Master came and found you?
She says while sleeping.
Why do they call dozing off
"Riding the Shirakawa night boat"?
Shirakawa sounds like a river,
but it's actually an area of Kyoto.
There was once a guy who said he'd seen
it all, and was asked "How's Shirakawa?"
He lied and said "I sailed down it on a boat,
but I slept and didn't see anything."
That's where the phrase originated from.
According to the internet.
The internet's amazing.
"Asleep at the wheel", "Sleeping on the job"...
The world's kind of against sleeping in general.
What about "Let sleeping dogs lie"?
So sleep is only for dogs?
Humans aren't allowed to sleep?
I don't like that at all.
If you wanna sleep, just sleep.
Good things come to those who sleep.
That's my motto.
I'm not sure that's what the proverb is.
Well, she is sleeping.
It sure would be easy if good things came
and all you had to do was sleep.
...I can't eat anymore!
What a cliché.
Refreshments courtesy of a patron.
Nice!
Good things came!
Marii! Marii!
Shh! No need to wake her.
Let's eat them now!
Delicious.
So good!
These are great.
Now, now.
We shouldn't eat them all.
That was the last one...
Was there something good?
N-No, there wasn't.
Are you sure?
Yup, nothing at all.
That's how it goes, eh?
It'd be too easy if all you had to do was sleep!
Feel free to sleep more.
That was quick.
You're gonna be famous...
I wonder what that's about.
How's your schedule tomorrow?
We need five people at short notice
to shoot a commercial.
Anyone here interested?
Me!
Right, that makes five.
I'll catch you up later.
Six would be one too many.
This means...
Not once, but twice...
Good things came while Marii slept!
Nope!
Not at all!
Are you sure?
Y-Yes!
That's how it goes!
That nap really perked me up.
What?!
Don't worry. She's just sleeping.
Um, it looks like it, but...
There are so many kitties, I'm purrfectly happy...
They're so cute!
These cats are adorable.
Fare-meow!
Who's making that racket?
What's up? You all look very content.
She woke up.
What's with that mean look in your eyes now?
What kind of skill is that?!
Come on in, the hot spring is nice and warm...
Huh? Everyone's looking refreshed and full of life.
Tch, she's awake.
And weary and dead now all of a sudden!
Chloroform?!
I can't believe I won the grand prize!
An announcement from the principal!
Milk at bedtime!
Lamb!
Good evening. My name is Leo Morimoto.
I'm not tired anymore!
Somebody make her go to sleep.
Hm, but...
It seems difficult.
Ah... I wonder if I'll win the lottery.
Say that in your sleep!
So close!
She nearly said it in her sleep!
Come on, say something big about getting rich!
Me? Marry an Arabian prince?
I am Zoebi bin Sultan al Teq'ila.
Who wants to be one of my five wives?
Me!
We'll consider it a temporary contract.
Six would be one too many.
Say what you like, but...
Isn't this a few too many convenient coincidences?
I'm gonna be a nationwide idol sensation!
The commercial proved to be very popular.
Momoiro Clover Z are looking for five new members...
We're in!
I can't wait for the tour!
Let's make it a big success!
Then the member election...
Then the dream is a solo career!
I should have known.
Everything was a little too convenient.
What if... we're all just...
part of a dream Marii's having?
The world... has ended...
Tetora Bouhatei here.
If you could buy three cucumbers for ninety-eight yen,
or five for a hundred and twenty yen,
which would work out cheaper?
I like cucumbers, but I can't eat five in one go.
If you keep them in the freezer, they go all mushy.
And you can't eat them,
just as if you hadn't bought them.
Anyway, here's what's in the fifth episode of Rakugo Girls:
"Pumpkin Band", "The Battle of Shinjuku",
and "Cavity Beach".
See you next time!