Thank you kindly for your attention
oato ga mata yoroshikute
I hope to have it again and again
osaki mo mae mo yoroshiku ne
Twing-twang twing-twang-twong
chin-ton chin-ton-shan
The theater's full
jounai manjou
Mysteries are fun
nazotoki dokidoki shinan
Tricks are fun as well
shikake ga ariari desu
We can solve girly problems by throwing dice
joshiteki onayami wa sugoroku sai wo futte
(really?)
(hai hai)
It's not one nor six, but nine
ichi de mo roku de mo nain
(really?)
(sou kai)
The stakes are high, but you can get a sign
ichi kake bachi ka de sain
(really?)
(sou kai)
I don't really see how that's related
hanashi no tsunagari ga miemasen ne
See, this looks like it's gonna be fun
oya omoshiroku narisou na yokan wa
(see, see?)
(oya oya desu)
Or am I just seeing things?
me no sakkaku desu ka
I don't even care
iya soredemo kamawanai
Come on, everyone
hai minna
Let's spin!
mawatte
Front and back, let's just turn it around
omote mo ura uragaeshite
You can turn the story upside down too
dondengaeshi mo yoshiyoshi
Let's go on, ladies first
osaki ni ikou saa douzo
I hope to see you around again and again
osaki mo mae mo yoroshiku ne
The backstage is the main stage
ura butai ga hare butai de
That's where we can chat idly
muda uchibanashi mo yokayoka
Thank you kindly for your attention
oato ga mata yoroshikute
I hope it was a good comedy
osaki mo shiroki gokuraku da
A comedy, a comedy
gokuraku da gokuraku da
A comedy from the comedy heaven
arayotto gokuraku joudo ringu
Twing-twang twing-twang-twong
chin-ton chin-ton-shan
I'm going with the South Pole, then!
That's a cool stick indeed.
Thank you kindly for your attention.
A
Buttoufu
There's a crisis a-brewin'...
Huh? Why?
It's school holidays, but there were hardly any kids in the audience!
That's true.
Rakugo isn't really aimed at kids, though.
But it's the school holidays!
Every amusement park, every tourist spot, and all the popular hangouts are filled with kids!
They're doing everything they can to attract children!
We gotta do something to attract them as well!
Kigu's kiguing!
Yeah! Kigu's kiguing for sure!
Kigu's gigging!
Yeah! Kigu's gigging for sure!
Thank you!
Red Feather
Kigu's gifting!
Yeah! Kigu's gifting for sure!
Kigu's giving!
Yeah! Kigu's giving for sure!
The point is, we won't attract any kids this way!
Then what? Should we do some kind of Happy Meal thing?
Kids love Happy Meals.
Then why don't we include something extra with the ticket?
Ticket
Price
We can't really do anything big, but how about trading cards?
That sounds good.
We can give out multiple kinds so people can collect them.
And if you're able to collect a certain combination, you can claim an extra rare card.
Didn't cellphone games do that already?
Then, if you collect them all, you can get a bonus extra!
That's what anime collectors' editions are for.
Maybe a meet & greet?
You better hope enough people turn up.
But we're trying to target children here, not just anyone.
What do children like?
Round things!
They say children like round things!
Not that kind of child!
Well, I've already taken measures of my own.
Your glasses?
Children like round characters, right?
Let's just add round things to our costumes!
There's already been a ton of characters like that.
I put circles on my kimono.
The circles consist of even smaller circles,
and those circles in turn consist of smaller circles still,
forming an infinite mandala.
That'd only scare them away!
What's wrong with scaring them?
If you scare them, they won't come!
Let's see... I'll make myself round!
I just need to eat and eat until I'm practically spherical!
Yuck.
You really don't have to go that far.
Can I have a little?
Sure, go on!
You can all have some. There's plenty to go round.
Don't let her fool you!
She's the kind who doesn't get fat no matter how much she eats!
While we put on weight, she'll just dodge all the calories and remain slim!
That's terrible!
We can't let our guard down for one minute!
Do you have any ideas, Marii?
I'm not gonna suck up to brats.
But Marii, surely you...
Stop that! I don't have a Mongolian spot!
That's enough of that.
The kids are gonna love you, Marii!
But how are we going to show her butt in the theater?
A
Buratei Marii
Easier said than done.
It's showing your butt, after all!
If you screw up, you'll be labeled an ass flasher for decades!
ass pictures
Ass flash Marii
Marii's ass
The shame of the female rakugo community
Trends
#ass
Promoted
Marii
ass
Mongolian spot
ass flash bot
We'd forever be remembered as an ass flashing anime!
Ass anime?
Are you prepared for that?
I never was!
If you really want to go to such lengths, I won't stop you.
Do as you wish.
I told you I'm not gonna flash my ass!
But...
If you don't show your butt,
the kids won't come to see us!
The only thing we can do is put your ass on display.
You'll do it for us, right?
Wait a moment!
Surely there are all kinds of things we can do!
We're just trying to attract kids, after all!
No...
We can't...
Showing off your ass to the world...
is our sole remaining option.
We have no choice!
You're not seeing the big picture!
It's narrow reasoning like this that results in family suicides!
This matter has already been decided. Let it go.
Who decided it?!
Let's all visit D**ney Land and Sea before the end!
And we can stay at the 'Costa and eat French food at Club **!
Then...
Show your butt!
You're talking nonsense!
Marii, listen to what we're saying!
You're not a child anymore!
I don't need some butthurt kid to tell me that!
You're the butthurt one!
O-Oh, right!
Wait, quit making me say stuff like that!
Jeez.
Just shut up already and show your butt!
Girls! Catch her!
Stop!
Oh my God! It's evidence of child abuse!
Look, a foreigner.
Child abuse?
What's he talking about? That's a Mongolian spot...
Ah, I've heard about this before.
Mongolian spots are a condition endemic to Asian people,
so Western doctors that are unfamiliar with the sight can mistake it for signs of child abuse.
Barbarian Japanese!
I'll protect this girl!
Let go of me!
He took her away.
Girls, let's sing for Marii!
The girl who was ashamed of her bruised behind
was taken away by a foreigner.
Do you think maybe the kids aren't coming because foreigners took them away?
Could well be.
Makes sense.
That's terrible!
U e n o
We're lucky the weather's clear!
This is perfect zoo weather!
It's been so long since I last came to the zoo.
Two or three years even.
Oh? I've got a yearly pass.
A
Yearly pass
Name:      Anrakutei    Kukuru
Gender:          Male        Female
A
Yearly pass
Name:      Anrakutei    Kukuru
Gender:          Male        Female
A
Yearly pass
Name:      Anrakutei    Kukuru
Gender:          Male        Female
Wow, really?
When I get tired of humans,
watching animals who don't talk helps me relax.
Should we go see the panda or the polar bear first?
If we see everything in order,
I'd get bored at the birds or the small animals' corner and want to go home.
Birds?
Look, there aren't any flamingos!
Flamingos are the stars of zoos!
We'd waste time taking photos and stuff,
then just run around in a hurry later!
Yeah, everyone loves how elegant they are.
Everything about them feels so unusual.
But why do they always put flamingos at the entrance?
Flamingos stand on one leg to minimize heat loss from the cool water.
The entrance always has very little shade.
Are they elderly bathing in the sun or what?!
A
The Bear of Ueno
It's the panda!
Starting with the panda is like
eating a whole meal starting with the meat,
or announcing election results starting with first place.
Nothing less from the Ueno Zoo.
They brought out the big guns right away.
They're confident enough that the zoo's not all about the panda.
They may be just naive enough to think
that if people bought the ticket already, they'll want to see more.
Aren't you reading a bit too much into it?
But no matter what, the panda's the panda!
We've gotta check it out!
It's not moving!
Zoo animals do that.
Well, they don't have to worry about their daily bread.
I'd love a life like that.
Their love life gets covered on the net though.
You serious?!
Thousands and thousands of people watching your private life!
Imagine everyone knowing about it except for you!
How dreadful!
What makes it to the net can never be taken down.
People may even start trolling or white knighting you.
The data may haunt you for all your life.
The net's so scary!
We must be careful!
Anyway, aren't pandas cute?
Loving pandas totally fits your cute personality!
I love pandas!
Seriously, I don't give a fuck about pandas.
Their eyes are damn creepy too.
So you all like the giant panda?
Is there anyone who doesn't?
Please remember the lesser panda too every now and then.
Right, that small brown thing was called a panda first,
but when the giant panda was discovered,
the poor thing got labelled "lesser."
It's called that in Japanese?
The English word "lesser" is borrowed.
It means "not so much" or "smaller."
It's tough to be compared like that.
At least call it the red panda or the standing panda...
A
Standing Bar
Fuuta
Everyone drink standing steady!
Down here
Booze
Not everyone's standing straight!
And the giant panda can stand up too.
That's an even lesser chance!
How come no one complains about the Chinese word for them? That means "big cat bear."
Panda
Big Cat Bear
It's not a cat, no matter how you look at it!
It's a bear!
But some people call that blue and round one a cat too.
He's not a cat, just a cat-form robot!
Bear, cat, robot, it doesn't change its popularity.
Bears are so scary!
Brown bears are smart and tenacious.
I've heard stories that they destroyed whole villages!
Speaking of scary, gorillas throw crap at people.
Watch out for crap
Danger!
The gorilla throws crap
Wait, wasn't there another crap alert too?
Warning!
The hippo throws crap
around with its tail!
It was at the hippo.
It throws crap around with its tail.
Camels spit.
Watch out for camel spit
Warning!
That's some weird fetish!
What's your favorite animal, Kukuru?
Wait, let me guess!
I'd say it's the giraffe!
I like giraffes.
It's long tongue is so creepy-cute!
Yours should be the specter lemur. Fits you well.
Is that a grade school nickname or what?!
Just because I'm bespectacled, they'd call me specter lemur...
Spectacled bear... Spectacled caiman...
Spectacled owl... Spectacled flying fox!
I get fed up with it!
Sorry.
I like polar bears.
It's gotten attention for its cafe recently.
Bears have five fingers!!!
When they're little, they're so cute!
Like stuffed toys!
And you, Marii?
Koalas, I guess? Nothing special.
That's surprisingly normal.
I thought you'd say the kangaroo.
Why?
I thought you'd feel close to it.
It looks just like you when lying down.
Are you calling me an old fart?!
Yeah, Marii's no old fart!
She's a kid.
What do you like then, Kukuru?
Naked mole rat.
Creepy! Ugly!
Naked mole rats.
They're unusual for having a queen.
Their society consists of the queen and a number of males,
who are worker rats just like worker bees and build their village.
And you like this?
Yeah. They live so long even though they're rats.
They don't get cancer either.
They say there aren't any revolts against the queen
because she covers the others in her urine.
Her urine?!
No one would want to revolt then...
Humans would be the same.
Some people would even be happy about it.
I could've lived without knowing that.
I know animal trivia too!
The polar bear's skin is black!
That doesn't look like it at all!
Its fur isn't white either! It's transparent!
Then what, it should be called the invisible bear?
It isn't cute at all!
Giraffes use their own backs as pillows when they sleep.
Elephants walk at 40 kilometers an hour. Surprisingly fast.
Elephants...
What's wrong?
Faithful Elephants...
Stop it! Don't mention that book!
Just hearing the title makes me cry!
Damn war!
Gon, the little fox...
Stop it, seriously! Don't make me remember!
The Happy Prince...
Little swallow, why didn't you fly south?!
Tarou and Jirou!
South Pole! Reunion!
That was so good!
Milo...
Hachiko...
Hachi!
We walked around quite a lot.
But we couldn't see it all.
There were quite a few animals I didn't know or saw for the first time.
Let's come again.
Pimo...
Pimo? What's that?
Everyone's seen it at least once,
but no one knows how it was born or got its name.
Did we really see that animal?
Where?
A
Sleeptalk
Don't sleep on the job!
What if the Master catches you?
You're the one who's sleeping.
Why does the Japanese idiom for "sound asleep" literally mean "night boat on Shirakawa"?
Shirakawa isn't a river, it's a place in Kyoto.
I went to Shirakawa in the capital.
Oh?
Once, a guy who claimed to have seen it all was asked "how was Shirakawa?"
He lied, "I passed by it on a boat, but I was asleep so I didn't see anything." That's why.
I was asleep.
Don't lie.
Originally, it referred to someone who acts in a know-it-all manner.
At least, that's what I read on the Internet.
A
Web
Google
Wikipedia
The Internet's amazing!
"Idle one's life away" and "slovenly" both have "sleep" in them.
A
Idle one's life away
Slovenly
Society is so dismissive about sleeping.
But they also say "kids who sleep well grow up big and strong."
Only children are allowed to sleep.
Adults cannot.
That's no good.
It's okay to sleep...
They say "sleep and let fortune strike you."
That's my personal motto.
It's not often that she actually quotes a proverb correctly.
Maybe she can only do it in her sleep.
If only we could just sleep and let good fortune come to us.
I can't eat another bite!
She sure is hitting the sleeptalking clichés.
One of your fans sent this.
It happened!
Fortune smiles upon us!
Marii, Marii!
Quiet. Don't wake her just yet.
Let's dig in!
It's so good...
Yummy!
These taste great.
Hey, slow down! We shouldn't eat them all.
You're eating the last one.
Did anything lucky happen?
No, nothing...
Really?
R-Really.
Of course not!
Life would be far too easy if fortune just came to us as we slept.
Feel free to snooze a bit longer.
She's out like a light.
We're gonna be famous!
What are you talking about?
Are you free tomorrow?
We're filming a commercial and we need five more people.
Are any of you interested?
Me!
Okay, then you five it is.
I'll call you with the details later.
We don't need a sixth one.
It...
happened again...
Fortune strikes when Marii sleeps!
No, nothing happened...
Really?
R-Really.
Of course not!
That nap sure was refreshing!
What?!
Don't be fooled. She's fast asleep.
That's true, but...
So many cats... I'm in purr-adise!
Omigosh, they're so cute!
These kittens are adorable!
Fare-meow!
What's that racket?
Huh? You all look so kind and peaceful.
Shit, she's awake.
Why are you glaring all of a sudden?
Where'd you learn to do that?!
The water feels so nice...
I love hot springs...
Huh? You all look so flushed and full of life.
Shit, she's awake.
Why do you look so clammy and dead all of a sudden?
Chloroform?!
Oh look, I won a beauty contest...
The principal's giving a speech!
Here's some warm milk before bed!
Have some lamb!
Good evening. I'm Morimoto Reo.
I'm not sleepy anymore!
Someone make her fall asleep!
It won't be that easy.
I wish we'd win the lottery...
Sleeptalk when you're sleeping!
That was so close!
Just a moment later and it would've been sleeptalking!
This time, you'd better say something grand and opulent!
The wife of an Arabian prince?
I'm Zouebi bin Sultan al Tequila.
I can have up to five wives.
Me!
Then consider this our provisional engagement.
I don't need a sixth one.
Don't you think...
...we're a bit too lucky for our own good?
I'm a national idol...
The CM we made was a huge success.
Momokuro need five more people.
It's okay!
Next up, we go on tour!
Let's make it a huge success...
Win the elections...
And launch our own solo careers!
It really does feel like we've been far too lucky.
Yeah.
What if...
we're all just...
part of Marii's dream?
The world ends.
A
Live long, live long and prosper
jugemu jugemu gokou no surikire
A
May great wealth await you wherever you go
kaijari suigyo no suigyou matsu
A
Even in different lands and under different skies
unrai matsu fuurai matsu
A
May you always have your daily bread
kuuneru tokoro ni sumu tokoro
A
And always be brimming full of life
yaburakouji no burakouji
A
Like the long-lived king Shuringan
paipo paipo paipo no shuuringan
A
And his dear wife Gurindai
shuuringan no guurindai
A
And their children Ponpokopi and Ponpokona
guurindai no ponpokopi no ponpokona no
A
Live a long and blessed life
choukyuumei chousuke
A
Let me have a bit of your time
choi to jikan itadakimasu
Please listen closely
goseichou kudasai
A
We're ready
totonoimashita
A
You write it "laughing"
warau koto to kakemashite
A
You read it "let's party"
omatsuri yarou zo tokemasu
A
And the point of it is, the point of it is...
sono kokoro wa sono kokoro wa
A
That everyone will be happy!
dochira mo happi ni naru deshou
A
Thank you kindly for your attention
oato ga yoroshii you de
Laugh, laugh, hey, let's laugh
waraou waraou sa waraimashou
Life may be hard, but let's laugh
konna jidai koso waraimashou
Laugh (yeah yeah)
waraou (soiya soiya)
If you cry, you lose
naitara make da
So just laugh until your sides ache
yakekuso waraimashou
Life may have its ups and downs,
haranbanjou sui mo amai mo
But great Japanese can get over it
norikoeta appare nipponjin
Laugh, whatever time may bring
waraou donna toki de mo
Laugh until you run out of breath
nanikuso waraimashou
Who cares where you are? Just laugh
kuuki nante yomazu ni warattoke
Smile (smile), smile (smile)
egao (egao) egao (egao)
Smile and the world will smile back at you
warau kado ni wa fuku kitaru
A
Preview
I'm Bouhatei Tetora.
3 cucumbers at 98 yen or 5 cucumbers at 120 yen, which is the better deal I wonder?
As much as I love cucumbers, there's no way that I'd be able to eat them all...
Even if I keep them in the fridge,
they'll just become pliant.
In the end, without any change, I still can't eat them all.
Next time, on Joshiraku:
Pumpkin Band, Battle of Shinjuku and Cavity Shore will be performed.
A
Pumpkin Band
Battle of Shinjuku
Cavity Shore