"I can't eat another bite."
"Well, if you can't eat it, try drinking it."
"Whew, that hit the spot!"
Thank you for your continued appreciation.
Which is more important to you, rakugo or me?
Don't ask such—
Obviously you, Kukuru!
Nothing compares to you!
Especially not stupid rakugo!
Hey, cool it with the stupid!
Both are important!
But...
But?
When I ask for a bite of something,
you don't let me have one.
When I like your outfit and want to buy it,
you won't tell me where you got it.
You promised you'd introduce me to some nice guys,
but you're all already seeing people
and won't go with me on group blind dates.
Give it a rest!
This isn't about you or rakugo,
it's just a pain in the ass!
I knew you liked rakugo more than me!
I want to kill rakugo and then myself!
A double suicide pact with rakugo?
I guess that means rakugo is pretty important.
Ooh! We should focus on birth rather than suicide.
Let's all throw a big party!
A Christmas party!
Good idea.
Let's do it!
I'm pretty sure this is completely out of season.
Time waits for no one.
I mean, do you match the season of the air date,
or the DVD release of stuff you watch?
Yeah. Don't sweat the small stuff.
This isn't "small stuff"!
Anyway, who are you guys gonna
spend real Christmas with?
Me? Ebi***.
Ebi***.
Wow, I guess everyone's spending it with Ebi***.
Y'all are full of bull!
Everyone loves a crazy actor.
No, they don't!
Y'know, even if we had a Christmas party,
the world economy's in such a bad state,
I don't think we could enjoy ourselves.
Forget Ebi***, it's us who should be acting crazy.
What do you mean?
When there's a recession,
people tend to curb their spending.
In other words, they get boring.
Things won't get better until
you start going ham with your cash.
That goes doubly for freelancers!
Spend, spend, spend!
I won't be going out of my way to name names,
but if you've gotten rich from drawing manga,
don't buy nice square corner lots!
Cut loose a little!
I see. So Christmas won't be fun
for anyone unless we go crazy.
Like buying all the first-class seats
on your honeymoon flight,
or having your teeth
completely coated in diamonds.
Or having other parts coated in diamonds.
Too far!
What are the three principles of acting crazy?
Skinner, Trunchbull, Dumbledore?
Wrong.
Getting into fights, tequila shots,
calling yourself a national treasure?
Note: Ebizou did all of those.
W-r-o-n-g!
Oh, I know! I know!
Drinking, spending, partying.
You mean like boozing, gambling, hookers?
No. Drinking medicine, spending your life
in depression, parting from those you love.
Now that's acting crazy...
Wrong!
So that's why people go to church on Christmas.
The priest listens to all your woes.
You've got it all wrong!
The priest encourages you
not to put yourself down so much.
Don't worry! You're a wonderful person!
You can get a lot of comfort from him.
So that's why you sing "hims".
This is all totally wrong!
To cheer her up, there now follows
a hymn in praise of Kukuru.
Don't...
Don't worry!
Did you have this musical prepared?
You're a wonderful person!
Don't worry! Don't worry! Don't worry!
It's her again!
You're a wonderful person!
Shut up and let me sing!
You've ruined the whole thing now!
Sorry, Kukuru. We'll start the hymn
from the beginning if you like.
No... it's fine...
You're all making fun of me!
Kukuru!
This painting looks like a Rubens...
I'm so tired, Patrasche...
That night, there was a Christmas miracle.
Cheer-ups descended upon Kukuru.
Cheer-ups? Not cherubs?
They seem to have cheered her up a little too much.
It's a miracle on Shinjuku 34th-chome!
Now she can join in with her own praise hymn!
Don't wooooooorry!
Don't worry!
D-D-D-Don't worry! Worry!
Santa's coat, red with blood!
Don't worry!
D-D-D-Don't worry! Worry!
You're all singing different things!
Why don't you join in?
I'm... good, thanks.
Is Marii...
Tone-deaf?
That night, a miracle happened.
Pain-gals descended upon her.
Pain-gals? Angels that cause pain?
Wouldn't they be demons?
Satan was a former angel, after all.
We have to cast Satan out!
Call an exorcist!
Did someone mention Satan?
The Devil himself descended upon them.
To this day, somewhere, the struggle
between Pain-gals and Cheer-ups continues.
We must... we must drive out Satan!
How can we do that?
There is but one way!
If you rub her nipples, the Devil will be cast out.
If you then set the photo as your
lock screen, happiness will follow.
And that's how...
I became so happy!
Try it yourself!
Don't even think about it!
S-So this is the famous Harajuku.
I feel a bit nervous going anywhere that isn't
the theatre, my house, or the convenience store.
I don't go out much these days.
Same.
They're going to think we're some sort of peasants.
It's fine, we're all humans just the same!
She's right. Just look at this street!
The people are like garb—
What are you saying, Marii?!
None of that nerd crap here.
This is a trendy place.
Don't be so stupid!
Miyazaki is mainstream!
Nobody's going to complain!
Miyazaki senior's stuff is a special case.
Not sure about his s*n, though.
I thought the rule was that you can mention
anything from Nausicaä onwards?
If you try and talk about Cagliostro or
Panda Kopanda, nobody's gonna understand.
What about Howl? I don't know about the s*n...
Beats me.
That reminds me. I need to go
to some celeb merch shops.
What kind of celebs? Pop idols?
Kunichan, Marcy... oh and Tacchan's pickle store.
Don't forget Harajuku's main attraction,
the Takenoko-zoku dancers!
The '70s called, they want their attraction back.
My Harajuku debut slips out of reach...
Maybe it's better that it does.
Come on, guys! We're here, so let's enjoy ourselves!
There are lots of cool shops in Back-Hara.
Back-Hara?
Yeah. Short for "Back Harajuku".
Wait just a sec. Who's calling it the "back"?
Uh... everybody?
Back-Hara, huh?
Don't they know that "back" carries
some unsavoury connotations,
like "backdoor enrollment", "backside" or "backstreet"?
Or "backstabber" or "backhander".
Or "backdoor trojan".
Or a "backlog"!
Just think of the poor producers
who had to ride the bullet train to deliver
the SR tapes to the local studio in time!
Just a thought, but since it's beyond Harajuku,
shouldn't we call it Harajuku Beyond? Hara-Bey?
Nice! We don't need to call it "back" anything.
Hara-Bey it is!
Typical Back-Hara!
I mean Hara-Bey!
There certainly are a lot of blue-letters.
Blue-letters?
It's to do with fashion magazines.
That style is called "blue letter".
A more ladylike, mature style is called a "red letter".
Blue letter, red letter... yellow letter?
If you add that, it sounds like a tongue-twister.
Like the name of that Harajuku-style idol...
Rakyu... p-pamyu... shuchu...
Like "the antiquated Tokyo to Kyoto queue counter".
That kinda thing?
Or what about "a long silly sing-along of a song"?
She sells seashells.
Chevrolet... sushi hell...
Marii, it's easier if you think of it
as "She's Elsie shells".
"She's Elsie Shells"?
She sells seashells. She sells seashells.
She sells seashells! You're right!
But...
I feel sorry for all involved.
Chevrolet Sushi Hell.
It smells like overcooked fish...
It does sound awful.
Like a fish market on a hot day.
Woo! Let's have some crêpes!
A crêpe from that famous Harajuku place?
Harajuku is known for crêpes,
but I haven't had one in a long time.
What's the go-to here? Choco banana?
I'm sure they're all good!
Huh? Mango? Almond jelly?
Soy flour and red beans? Salted caramel?
They're just crêpes! Flour, water, and eggs!
Learn from the purity of takoyaki!
One medium-size strawberry custard rollup
with extra whipped cream, brownies,
chocolate spray, maple syrup,
and caramel sauce, please.
Did Kigu just cast Revive?
What? What language is that?
It's just strawberry with chocolate.
Then ask for that!
It's no fun if you don't add some toppings and shots.
Shots?
They're just crêpes! Adding too many
time-consuming choices is just tedious
and makes a mockery of the whole damn thing!
So tacky!
One crêpe. Plain.
Plain?
That's like ordering a takeout pizza
and going for just cheese instead of
half-and-half or a four-item family combo.
You're a hero! We've got a hero in our midst!
It's been a while since I had a crêpe.
Yeah, it's not like a big occasion or anything.
Hm? Marii, have you never had a crêpe before?
I-I feel like if I did, my whole life would change.
What do you mean?
Is it really that momentous an act?
It's not like that!
It's just kind of embarrassing to eat it in public.
It's like going to an open-air concert,
or waiting an hour to buy doughnuts,
or buying a lame character's merch,
or waiting at the airport to spot foreign celebrities.
It feels like a big deal.
I don't think it is.
Yeah. We're all eating them.
There's no such place as Creamy Hill
in Kunitachi! What a stupid name!
They spelt it "Kurlml" in the anime,
but that doesn't really help.
-
No, it bloody doesn't!
Calm down, Marii! It's only flour after all.
Just imagine it's a grilled squid, but sweet.
Just some Osaka junk food.
Grilled squid...
Just a squid grilled in flour. With soy sauce.
That's right. No problemo, right?
Nope. No, it's no good!
Grilled squid's served on a polystyrene tray,
not wrapped in cute paper like this!
And you happily pay like five
or six hundred yen for this crap?
That's like being one of those suckers
who'd pay two thousand yen for a bowl of ramen!
It's not worth it!
Standing in public and eating this is wrong!
It's bad behaviour! Don't you see? I'm talking to you!
Shut up and eat!
And now for the weather.
Due to atmospheric conditions,
today will be particularly dry.
Now for the local—
It really is dry.
My fingers are so dry they're cracking something awful.
If your nails get too dry...
You'll end up working your fingers to the bone!
Young rakugo performers work so hard, their nails
are the only thing keeping their fingers intact!
You know that's just a metaphor, right?
Nails are their only defence!
I think she really believes that. Scary.
This is like that time I told her
she'd get her fingers burned,
and she was convinced she had magical powers.
It would be great to have magical powers, though!
Anyway, as I was saying,
my skin's so dry my nails are cracking.
That must be awful.
Your skin's soft like silk, Kigu.
Hey! Stop poking me!
Must be nice. Mine's like sharkskin.
You're right! It makes the perfect grater!
Ow! Stop grating wasabi on me!
Sharkskin graters make for the most fragrant wasabi!
Dry skin...
Silk skin...
Sharkskin...
It's pretty cool how we've all got our own type of skin.
I wonder what kind of skin mine is.
Your skin is...
Thin skin?
Yeah, you've only gotta spend
five minutes with Marii to get that.
So... thin skin...
Um... what kind of texture is that?
A moist texture? A rough texture?
A springy texture? Or maybe a dry texture?
You do know it's not a real—
It's the kind of skin that's easy to tattoo.
By the way, did you know that the word "tattoo"
comes from the Samoan word "tatau", meaning "to strike"?
How come you know so much about tattoos, Teto?
Does she have a tattoo on her ankle like you-know-who?
That's beside the point.
Let me draw one on you!
Let me give you an amateur tattoo!
Applied with all the skill of accidentally stabbing yourself
with the lead from a mechanical pencil in middle school,
leaving a mark to this day!
Let's see how thin that skin of yours really is.
Go to hell! Let go of me!
That's enough, Gan.
She's already got a mark, see?
That doesn't count!
If Marii got a tattoo, she wouldn't be able
to go to the hot spring she loves so much,
like Okobe Springs, Hakone Yunessun,
Marine Spa Atami, or Spa Resort Hawaiians.
And she wouldn't be able to run for office in Osaka.
She's taking this well.
Maybe her skin's not so thin after all.
Okay, I'll do something with art materials
that you can wash off later.
Hmm, what picture would suit Marii?
Why don't you just paint a picture of her?
Somehow doesn't quite feel right.
Looks fine to me.
Jerks! I bet you did it slapdash
just because I can't see it!
So what should we paint?
Hmm, thinking about people with thin skin...
The Afghan hound and the Hiroshima emblem
seem a bit out of place.
You think?
Well, why don't you just try drawing Y**ki Am*mi, then?
It looks just as crappy!
Wow, pretty rude to Am*mi.
My turn! I'm good at drawing, so let me try!
Must... not... say... comeback...
We've got such a variety of skin types,
isn't there anything we can do with that?
Dry skin!
Sharkskin!
Silk skin!
Thin skin!
Together, we're...
The Skin Arrangers!
Gasp! What's that?!
Cream?
We'll cream her!
I see! It's an ad for skincare products.
Did you come up with this?
You must have genius skin!
Wait a sec. Rangers usually have fives members!
We've got five, including genius skin here!
Wh-What about me?!
Her skin isn't anything special...
She could be an enemy, the Glasses Grunt?
That could work.
If we're being forced to include her, yeah.
You jerks, I swear I'll—
Goosebumps!
You could make that work!
You're on the team!
Your skin went back to normal!
That won't do. Without a special skin quality,
you can't be one of the Rangers.
But... goosebumps aren't something
you can keep up constantly...
Then we've got ourselves a problem.
You can't be a member of the Skin Arrangers.
We've got to gather up all the stuff she hates.
The slimy, rotten vegetables from the fridge.
The sound of nails on a chalkboard!
An image search for "insects"!
Only an enemy looks as horrifying as that!
And whose fault is that?
It didn't have to be stuff I hate!
What about goosebumps from being moved?
Play me that clip of Susan Boyle
from Britain's Got Talent!
Then we should move you to goosebumps
the only way we know how.
Something like this.
Congratulations on your graduation.
Congratulations!
So moving.
Hey...
I really do have goosebumps.
Hey! W-Wait, what do you mean by graduation?!
We'll stay friends forever!
We'll never forget you, Gan!
What do you mean by graduation?!
Let's all meet up for dinner sometime.
Good luck!
Hey!
The remaining members will work hard
to live up to Gan's legacy!
Hey! Somebody, please explain!
What do you mean by graduation? Hey!
Kigurumi Haroukitei here!
How's everyone doing today?
Do you think a wet puppy is cute or sad?
I think it's cute-sad.
Here's what's in the sixth
awesome episode of Rakugo Girls!
"All Four One", "Multiple Musashis",
and "Servant's Revenge".