A
Live long, live long and prosper
jugemu jugemu gokou no surikire
May great wealth await you wherever you go
kaijari suigyo no suigyou matsu
Even in different lands and under different skies
unrai matsu fuurai matsu
May you always have your daily bread
kuuneru tokoro ni sumu tokoro
And always be brimming full of life
yaburakouji no burakouji
Like the long-lived king Shuringan
paipo paipo paipo no shuuringan
A
And his dear wife Gurindai
shuuringan no guurindai
And their children Ponpokopi and Ponpokona
guurindai no ponpokopi no ponpokona no
Live a long and blessed life
choukyuumei chousuke
A
Let me have a bit of your time
choi to jikan itadakimasu
Please listen closely
goseichou kudasai
A
We're ready
totonoimashita
You write it "laughing"
warau koto to kakemashite
You read it "let's party"
omatsuri yarou zo tokemasu
And the point of it is, the point of it is...
sono kokoro wa sono kokoro wa
A
That everyone will be happy!
dochira mo happi ni naru deshou
Thank you kindly for your attention
oato ga yoroshii you de
Laugh, laugh, hey, let's laugh
waraou waraou sa waraimashou
Life may be hard, but let's laugh
konna jidai koso waraimashou
Laugh (yeah yeah)
waraou (soiya soiya)
If you cry, you lose
naitara make da
So just laugh until your sides ache
yakekuso waraimashou
Life may have its ups and downs,
haranbanjou sui mo amai mo
But great Japanese can get over it
norikoeta appare nipponjin
Laugh, whatever time may bring
waraou donna toki de mo
Laugh until you run out of breath
nanikuso waraimashou
Who cares where you are? Just laugh
kuuki nante yomazu ni warattoke
Smile (smile), smile (smile)
egao (egao) egao (egao)
Smile and the world will smile back at you
warau kado ni wa fuku kitaru
The End