Thank you kindly for your attention
oato ga mata yoroshikute
I hope to have it again and again
osaki mo mae mo yoroshiku ne
Twing-twang twing-twang-twong
chin-ton chin-ton-shan
The theater's full
jounai manjou
Mysteries are fun
nazotoki dokidoki shinan
Tricks are fun as well
shikake ga ariari desu
We can solve girly problems by throwing dice
joshiteki onayami wa sugoroku sai wo futte
(really?)
(hai hai)
It's not one nor six, but nine
ichi de mo roku de mo nain
(really?)
(sou kai)
The stakes are high, but you can get a sign
ichi kake bachi ka de sain
(really?)
(sou kai)
I don't really see how that's related
hanashi no tsunagari ga miemasen ne
See, this looks like it's gonna be fun
oya omoshiroku narisou na yokan wa
(see, see?)
(oya oya desu)
Or am I just seeing things?
me no sakkaku desu ka
I don't even care
iya soredemo kamawanai
Come on, everyone
hai minna
Let's spin!
mawatte
Front and back, let's just turn it around
omote mo ura uragaeshite
You can turn the story upside down too
dondengaeshi mo yoshiyoshi
Let's go on, ladies first
osaki ni ikou saa douzo
I hope to see you around again and again
osaki mo mae mo yoroshiku ne
The backstage is the main stage
ura butai ga hare butai de
That's where we can chat idly
muda uchibanashi mo yokayoka
Thank you kindly for your attention
oato ga mata yoroshikute
I hope it was a good comedy
osaki mo shiroki gokuraku da
A comedy, a comedy
gokuraku da gokuraku da
A comedy from the comedy heaven
arayotto gokuraku joudo ringu
Twing-twang twing-twang-twong
chin-ton chin-ton-shan
"Pickled plums are the best rice ball filling.
"And the way us hags fill 'em makes 'em taste especially good."
Thank you kindly for your attention.
A
Four Wows
It's so cold!
What are you looking at?
No one else was graduating, but it was still a very touching event!
No one else will be at her reunion either.
In space, no one can hear you scream.
Gan, who we respected oh so dearly, has graduated and moved forward.
We'll just have to go forth as a group of four!
You're right.
Anyway, let's eat these oranges.
Oranges on a warm table!
It feels right with four people.
Yeah, we each get one side of the table.
Grab a fork, girls. We have a cake here.
It's so easy to cut into fours.
Everything works out when we're four!
Yeah. With four people, it's easy to split things accurately.
Four works for everything!
One taxi fits four people.
No one's left out of four-player games.
We can make a reservation for two twin rooms when we go on a fortnight's vacation.
The war brought about the rise of the nuclear four-person family.
As a result, having a group of four is the easiest way to get by in society.
You could say modern society was built for fours!
The seasons are spring, summer, autumn, and winter. Four again.
Five seasons would be a sign of the impending apocalypse.
Look, there's a fivrefly!
Just kidding, lol!
A
May the anime
.  industry enjoy peace
You'll pay for this!
I just meant five is bad!
It's all about four.
Just think of the four-leafed clover.
Or the four beasts: The Black Tortoise, the Azure Dragon, the Vermillion Bird, and the White Tiger.
It's easy to do stuff with four people too.
Remember that movie, Fourrest Gump?
What're you saying now about Fourrest Gump?
You know, the Gang of Four was pretty dangerous.
Oh yeah, Madame Mao, huh.
And there's a four in misfourtune.
That's true...
But there's also a four in fourtune!
Cinderella was so fourtunate that her prince wasn't in a foureign country.
How about Deb? She was a four-striped damselfish!
Don't forget about fourtune cookies!
Or four-cheese pizza!
Yep, all good things!
Four makes me hungry too!
Four is awesome!
But we aren't really talking about the number four anymore.
Yeah, we were supposed to focus on that!
Oh right! Since we're here, let's do something we can only do with a group of four!
What's something you can only do with a four-person group?
A
May the anime
.    industry enjoy peace
I have a good idea!
You see...
Sounds good.
We'll be the Elite Four!
That said, isn't the "Elite Four" a bit too broad?
Like, we're the Elite Four what? Card suits?
Well, I suppose.
Kigu gets to be the cutest suit!
Yay!
I don't want the heart!
But the heart suit is so cute!
M-Make it another Elite Four!
Another Elite Four?
The Kanto Elite Four!
The Johto Elite Four!
The Elite Four Dittos!
Okay Kigu, Transform into Lupin!
Hey Fujiko, babe!
You're pretty bad at this.
Then don't make me do it!
We're having so much fun between the four of us!
We're lucky to have a group of four!
If we were five, we'd have to take collective responsibility and duke it out!
Yeah. Think of the musicians too.
You know how those five-man bands always have problems.
We get graded with five letter grades.
Japan holds the census every five years.
If we do nothing all day, we'll gain five pounds in no time.
L-Let's just fourget about five and focus on what fun things we can do with the four of us!
Intro
Story
Then...
Intro
Story
Twist
Intro
Story
Twist
Intro
Story
Twist
Intro
Story
Twist
Intro
Story
Twist
Intro
Story
Twist
Intro
Story
Twist
Intro
Story
Twist
Intro
Story
Twist
Intro
Story
Twist
Intro
Story
Twist
Intro
Story
Twist
Intro
Story
Twist
Intro
Story
Twist
Intro
Story
Twist
Intro
Story
Twist
Intro
Story
Twist
Intro
Story
Twist
Intro
Story
Twist
Intro
Story
Twist
Intro
Story
Twist
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
What's this?
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Story
Twist
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
Intro
Story
Twist
Punchline
The four-panel comic you've all been waiting for!
Joshir4ku
Red and White.
A
“Red and White”
Omigod!
The graduation ceremony curtain was stolen!
The ceremony curtain? You mean that red and white curtain?
Don't worry!
It's back!
I know who did it!
So do I.
If the suspect used it to make a red and white striped shirt, then it must be a certain missing person...
The Second Button.
A
“The Second Button”
I got Ebizou's second button!
Good for you!
But why is the second button so important?
Because it's closest to the heart!
So it's like I have his heart!
And I got Shintarou's fifth button!
The fifth button?
Marii, that's dirty!
Wait, why?!
Graduation Photo.
A
“Graduation Photo”
Is that your graduation photo?
Show me yours too, Kukuru!
It was taken during flu season...
Get it retaken!
We might get into Manga Time Kirara!
W-Wait!
Weren't those kinda boring?
There's nothing wrong with being boring.
You know, like those high school girls who play light music!
High school girls being light?
Like this?
Extortion!
X-Tort!
Or this?
Rip off!
R-Off!
Or this?
Cover-up!
C-Up!
A
Important
Secret
A cute font and an exclamation mark can even make crime look cute!
What they're doing isn't even cute!
But that doesn't sound like something that would be remotely popular.
I see...
You're right. I guess it needs to be able to sell...
And to sell...
It should be something sexy!
How about swimsuits?
Finally! A beach episode! A beach episode!
Summer Vacation!
A
“Summer Vacation”
We're going on a summer vacation!
Then let's go buy swimsuits together!
Wait, what about the fourth panel?
There's no punchline!
Is it really a big deal?
Use your head to fill in the blank.
Then it isn't really a four-panel comic!
But there are so many without punchlines.
Next up, hot springs!
Hot Springs.
A
“Hot Springs”
This feels so good!
I'm glad we came.
Can't get much better than this.
Now there's four panels, but it's still not a real four-panel!
I wanna stay in the water for the entire hot springs episode!
But a four-panel comic's gotta have all four elements!
Well, we don't have to be four for a four-panel comic, do we?
We haven't split up the roles either.
Oh look, I'm the punchline.
I bet you were hoping I would show off my butt since I've been the butt of so many punching jokes!
Too bad, so sad!
No one said that...
Who are you even talking to?
Oh no, it's gotten so late!
We've gotta get home!
That's right.
Huh?
Hey, it won't open!
What should we do?!
Doesn't the power get shut off at night?
Yeah, to save electricity.
It's off!
The power's out!
Has the dressing room always been this cold?
S-So cold...
I'm getting so sleepy...
Don't! You'll die if you fall asleep!
Even in this situation, it pays to be four!
We'll sit around the table and take turns going around
and waking up the next person so that she won't fall asleep.
Hey girls, are you awake?
Kinda...
I'm awake...
Wait...
With this method, someone is always moving,
so no one will be at the first person's corner!
It doesn't work without five people!
Someone's here...
Someone's here!
Thank God!
We managed to stay awake because there's four of us!
No! Listen! There was a fifth!
There was a fifth when there should've been four!
A fifth?
It's all thanks to her...
That we're alive?
Who could it be?
So five is actually better than four!
Thank you, Mask!
Well, this is odd.
Where is everyone?
Why?
A
Musashi Scenery
I'm pretty sure I got the time right.
Musashi-kosugi Sta.
Musashi-itsukaichi Sta.
The others are wrong!
Guess I have no choice.
I have to spend the day alone.
The PALM mall is 800 meters long.
Walking it alone and in silence makes it seem so much.
Sushi
Gosakimaru
I'm a lone girl under the glass arcade.
I bought grilled chicken heart and pickled radish when the smell lured me there.
Fancying yourself the Lone Gourmet?
I'm here for you!
And here I meet Gankyou, who has newly graduated and commands respect.
You forced me to graduate!
And I don't command respect, either.
If you don't command respect...
Then what?
Thank you kindly for your attention.
A
The Servant's Vengeance
Excu—
Is that any way for a rookie like you to greet her seniors?!
What's that? Did I just see a flash of rebelliousness in your eyes?
I'm afraid you are mistaken. Please forgive me.
As long as you understand.
In this world, you can never forget who's above you in the hierarchy.
Hey, Kigu! You've got your own junior now, so take good care of her!
Sir, yes sir!
Let me teach you who's above you!
That makes it pretty clear.
Wait a moment!
Even though I'm above you, I still feel inferior!
Don't even think of making fun of me!
First of all, rookies like you shouldn't have to wait for their seniors to tell them what to do!
Just watch what we do and figure out what we want by yourself!
You mustn't, Kigu! You're underage!
Who're you calling Kigu? That's Kigurumi to you, rookie!
When I do this, it's obviously because I want a candy bar!
I'm sorry. I didn't know that.
You should really learn some manners.
You blew it! This is curry flavor!
How do you not know that I always eat corn potage flavor?!
I'm sorry.
Good grief.
The least you could do is remember what snacks your seniors like.
Though, it's not that I don't like this one.
Then just shut up and eat it.
Now then.
I know! You want a magazine!
No! And isn't this the Strawberry?!
Could you get any dumber than this?
I'm sorry.
If I do this, obviously I want sweet rice wafers!
Do you live off snacks or something?
Well, at least that makes it easier to guess.
One finger? What does that mean?
One. One. One finger.
See, it's not that hard!
If I do this, I want potato rings!
Thank you.
That's right! Five fingers means I want crunchy cones!
This is the only way to eat crunchy cones!
Though your parents would spank you for it.
Also...
You're good!
That's pretty impressive.
Looks difficult.
I'd rather not get involved. It looks troublesome.
Not just me! Go and serve your other seniors too!
That's quite all right...
Please, allow me to guess what you desire from your actions.
I've got a really, really bad feeling about this!
Tetora's gone!
A disaster! The Apocalypse is upon us!
Hey, kiddo.
Please, you need not speak.
Clearly, you desire a hot pot.
So hot that it burns!
Oh, I'm happy to hear that!
I'm delighted to have fulfilled your desire.
No! No!
Could it be you also desire this red-hot steel ingot?
Or this? Or this?
A hot pot! I want a hot pot!
I knew it! I just knew it!
How am I so good at figuring out what people desire?
You don't have to say another word.
Even in silence, I know very well what my dear seniors desire.
You want this?! You want that?!
You should enjoy my service in silence too!
Wait!
If you know so very well what people desire,
you shouldn't waste your talents on serving the likes of us.
Become a public servant!
I will represent you all and win the election!
A
Kuurubiyuutei Gankyou
Politics as clear as my glasses!
Sour Party
She's eligible for election?!
How old is she?
I can read your feelings as if they were written in a book!
- Lower glasses tax
- Compulsory glasses-holder in every ramen shop
- "Glasses Only" train cars
- Move the capital to Sabae
- Ban contact lenses
- Ban LASIK
Isn't that what we call a dictatorship?
Everyone, please cast your vote for Kuurubiyuutei Gankyou!
Politicians are just normal people if they lose their election.
She wasn't even a politician to begin with.
Must've been a tough defeat.
Now I'm even deeper in debt...
Debt?
Must be because of the election deposit.
It costs a certain amount of money to run for election.
Though, if you're able to achieve above a certain number of votes, you can get it back even if you lose.
Really?
But don't you have to be at least 30 years of age to be eligible?
Except for the lower house and the prefectural assemblies.
You didn't just lose, you weren't even in the running to begin with.
Then my three million...
What about all those election goods I got when I paid?
You've been tricked!
Must've been one of those election deposit cons!
Kigu, you can come out now.
What's wrong?
The d-daruma doll!
She's afraid of daruma dolls.
Put it away somewhere, please!
Guess I've got no choice...
You're not thinking of putting away that daruma without achieving the goal you bought it for, right?!
It's not like you to be so intense.
You mustn't defy tradition when it comes to talismans!
She's scaring me!
Kukuru's really strict about traditions and customs...
Put it away! Please just put it away already!
But Kigu's afraid of it...
Then she should just fulfill her goal by winning an election.
It doesn't matter what kind of an election it is. She just has to win one.
Election
That election's even scarier!
Oh?
Though if I entered that, I'd end up winning.
The deposit for this election is 2 million.
BKA Elections
Deposit: 2 million
Block votes:  OK
Self-promotion: Anything's OK
A
That's cheaper than running for mayor!
That's not it...
It's another con!
But if you just enter every election you find, you'll win one eventually!
Such as?
You should start off with a student council election!
That sounds like it should be pretty easy to win!
No, wait!
Japanese student council presidents are too high-level!
Th-That's true!
The title of "student council president" shows that
they are fighting against evil organizations and monsters!
Not even Gan could win that race!
It's perfect!
I might have popularity issues, but I've never once lost a fight!
Are you praising or criticizing yourself?
But why would you risk running in such a difficult election?
You should just enter some simple, easy-to-win one, like the neighborhood association's...
Yeah, that sounds good!
I've got it!
A
Neighborhood
Association President
Candidate List
A
Neighborhood
Association President
Candidate List
A
Neighborhood
Association President
Candidate List
A
Neighborhood
Association President
Candidate List
A
Neighborhood
Association President
Candidate List
A
Neighborhood
Association President
Candidate List
Here's a list of all the candidates for the neighborhood association's presidency!
Let's see...
Gan, you aren't qualified to enter.
Why?!
Let me give you your qualification!
What are you planning to do?
The president of the neighborhood association must be bald!
Then I'm dropping out of the neighborhood election.
Are there any others that would be good?
At this point...
I'll run for anything!
Where am I?
Someone's there.
Welcome. Your candidacy has been accepted.
Former prime minister?!
I merely took his form.
Actually, I'm the Galactic Federation Solar System's former prime minister.
So aliens really do exist!
Indeed.
I am from Venus.
As I have resigned, we will now be holding prime ministerial elections for the Solar System.
There's a poster for me?
You are also in the running.
Since when?
Since you held your glasses up toward Venus with people around you.
What a coincidence!
Anyway, as for your slogan:
"Not on my home planet!"
What does that even mean?
It's a political maneuver.
Which means you have no concrete plan?
I've got something up my suit.
Here.
A
Plan
No way.
This guy is seriously hopeless.
Anyway, since you've been accepted as a candidate, please pay your deposit.
Another deposit?!
How much this time?
It's the approximate net worth of one Earth.
One Earth?! Nobody has that much money!
Why don't you just sell the Earth?
I've actually made money that way, you know.
You sold the Earth?!
You sold not only Japan, but the whole Earth?!
You sold my planet!
She hit the former prime minister!
Saturn
A
Mercury
She totally hit him!
Oh my God!
Pluto
A
Oh crap... I'm done for...
We have a winner!
People hate you this much, even in space?
Former prime minister...
I'm telling you, I won the Solar System election!
Let's keep it a secret, though.
It would be huge news!
I'm bigger than Obama!
Ah... Isn't that great?
If people found out, all the world rulers would come to me seeking audience!
So don't tell anyone!
Sure, we won't.
We're having a Solar System Assembly meeting next week.
We'll be discussing what to do about the Solar System's rising pulse.
Remember Level E?
Most of it was true, you know!
Good luck!
Glasses are even scarier than daruma dolls...
A
Live long, live long and prosper
jugemu jugemu gokou no surikire
A
May great wealth await you wherever you go
kaijari suigyo no suigyou matsu
A
Even in different lands and under different skies
unrai matsu fuurai matsu
A
May you always have your daily bread
kuuneru tokoro ni sumu tokoro
A
And always be brimming full of life
yaburakouji no burakouji
A
Like the long-lived king Shuringan
paipo paipo paipo no shuuringan
A
And his dear wife Gurindai
shuuringan no guurindai
A
And their children Ponpokopi and Ponpokona
guurindai no ponpokopi no ponpokona no
A
Live a long and blessed life
choukyuumei chousuke
A
Let me have a bit of your time
choi to jikan itadakimasu
Please listen closely
goseichou kudasai
A
We're ready
totonoimashita
A
You write it "laughing"
warau koto to kakemashite
A
You read it "let's party"
omatsuri yarou zo tokemasu
A
And the point of it is, the point of it is...
sono kokoro wa sono kokoro wa
A
That everyone will be happy!
dochira mo happi ni naru deshou
A
Thank you kindly for your attention
oato ga yoroshii you de
Laugh, laugh, hey, let's laugh
waraou waraou sa waraimashou
Life may be hard, but let's laugh
konna jidai koso waraimashou
Laugh (yeah yeah)
waraou (soiya soiya)
If you cry, you lose
naitara make da
So just laugh until your sides ache
yakekuso waraimashou
Life may have its ups and downs,
haranbanjou sui mo amai mo
But great Japanese can get over it
norikoeta appare nipponjin
Laugh, whatever time may bring
waraou donna toki de mo
Laugh until you run out of breath
nanikuso waraimashou
Who cares where you are? Just laugh
kuuki nante yomazu ni warattoke
Smile (smile), smile (smile)
egao (egao) egao (egao)
Smile and the world will smile back at you
warau kado ni wa fuku kitaru
I am Kuurubiyuutei Gankyou.
A
Preview
I have finally come to an understanding.
In both married life and anime, there is a stage of ennui.
It is said you can overcome this by adding further and further stimuli,
but if the stimulation causes inflation, things just end up even worse than before.
To this end, we will also take proper care of ourselves.
We have made it to the questionable seventh performance of Joshiraku:
A
Delinquents are Scary
Fish Story
Dressing Room Files
Delinquents are Scary, Fish Story and Dressing Room Files will be performed.