"Pickled plum onigiri really are the best."
"Only because you make them, Granny."
Thank you for your continued appreciation.
Ah, it's freezing!
Whatcha looking at?
A one-person graduation ceremony.
Wasn't it moving?
The reunion will be one person too.
Snore, and you sleep alone...
Now that Gan's graduated from the group,
let's try our very best as a quartet!
Yeah!
Anybody want a mandarin?
A kotatsu and mandarins!
This is perfect for the four of us.
Each of us gets their own side of the kotatsu.
Someone gifted me some cake. Want some?
It cuts so neatly into four.
Feels like a perfect fit!
Everything divides neatly into fours.
Four truly is the best!
Everyone gets their own seat in a taxi.
Nobody needs to sit out of four-player games.
When on a trip, you fit evenly into two rooms.
With Japan's postwar focus on the nuclear family,
society reformed around four-person units.
Four really is the most modern number.
The Beatles had four members.
They were pretty popular.
Five beetles would be too many.
Over there! Five beetles!
Just kidding!
Why, you little—
It was... five's fault...
Four is best.
Four-leafed clovers are lucky!
Or the four mythical beasts: the Black Tortoise,
the Azure Dragon, the Vermilion Bird, and the White Tiger.
It's cheaper to do things as a four-man group.
We'll be able to affourd to eat out more!
Who's buying a Ford?
A Gang of Four has dangerous connotations.
Like Jiang Qing?
"Four" can also be "fourboding".
That's true.
But it's also in "fourtunate"!
Cinderella was fourtunate that her prince
wasn't in some foureign country!
Fourests are nice.
They're very fourmidable!
One four all, all four one.
This is fun.
There are a lot of words with "four" in them!
"Four" the best!
We've kinda strayed away from
the actual number, though.
Oh yeah, we were talking about
how neat of a number it is.
Ooh, ooh! Let's come up with some things
we can only do now that there's four of us!
So, what kinda things are there?
I've got one!
How about...
Sounds good.
The Big Four!
"The Big Four" is way too vague.
You have to explain more than that.
Let's see now...
For Kigu, the cutest suit.
Yay!
No! I don't wanna be the Heart!
Isn't the heart cute, though?
Make it a different Big Four!
Another set of four...
The Four Horsemen?
The Fantastic Four?
The Elite Four?
Kigu, you be Lupin!
Oh, Fujicakes...
That was godawful.
Then don't make me do it!
The four of us are having a great time!
I'm so happy we're a group of four!
If we were a group of five, the pressure
of our collective responsibility would take its toll.
That does always seem to be the case for singers.
Whenever there's a scandal,
it's always a five-man group.
Surveys with Likert scales are annoying, too.
The Japanese national census is once every five years.
I tried the 5:2 diet and it was horrible.
F-Forget five. Let's do something fun for the four of us.
Ta-dah!
What's this?
The four-panel comic you wanted!
Rakugo Girls!
Red & White.
Oh. My. Gosh!
Someone has stolen the bunting
for the graduation ceremony!
Bunting? You mean, like, the red and white banners?
No worries! I got it back!
I know who the culprit is!
Me too. I'm sure he won't be hard to find.
The Second Button.
Ebizou gave me his second button!
Grats!
But what's so special about his second button?
It's closest to the heart,
so it's like he's giving me his heart!
I got Shintarou's fifth button!
The... what?
You're so dirty!
The hell?!
Graduation Photo.
Is that your graduation photo?
Show me yours, Kukuru!
It was flu season...
Retake it!
We might get to be in Manga Time Kirara!
J-Just wait a minute...
Those panel strips were kinda lame, though!
That's fine, people like lame.
Y'know, like that one about
those girls who play light music.
Girls who play light music?
You mean like this?
X-Tort!
Or like this?
Embezzlement!
Or even this?
Cover-Up!
Even crime looks cute if you write them
in a cheery font with an exclamation mark.
But the actions themselves
are anything but cute!
I really don't think any of those would be hits.
Hmm, maybe they're not very marketable.
To make them more appealing...
Why not sex them up a bit?
Like putting everyone in swimsuits?
Hell, yeah!
Swimsuit issue! Swimsuit issue!
Summer trip!
It's vacay time!
Let's go buy swimsuits!
Ta-dah!
Huh? What happened to the fourth panel?
There's no punchline!
It doesn't need one.
The reader can fill in the blanks themselves.
It's not that kind of comic strip!
It's not out of the ordinary
to not have a punchline.
How about we hit the hot springs next?
Hot spring.
Ah, that hits the spot!
I’m glad we went.
We're in heaven.
Hehehe...
Just having four panels
doesn't make it a four-panel comic!
I want to spend the whole
hot spring issue in the hot spring.
A four-panel comic needs all four elements!
But it doesn't necessarily need four people.
It's not like we're each only
responsible for one element.
Since I'm the ass-end of the story,
I bet you thought my butt would
be the butt of every joke.
Well, you thought wrong!
Nobody thought that.
Who is she even talking to?
Oh, no! I lost track of time!
We've gotta get going!
Yeah.
Hey! We're locked in here!
What will we do?
The lights'll turn off at night.
They put them on a timer to save electricity...
They went out!
It's so dark!
Has the dressing room always been this cold?
Brrr...
Ugh... I’m getting sleepy...
Don't you dare! If you fall asleep, you'll die!
At times like these, there's something else
we can do as a group of four!
Sit at the corners, then take turns tapping
each other's shoulders so nobody falls asleep.
Is everyone still awake?
Just about...
I'm awake...
Wait.
Using this method, someone is always moving,
meaning there's nobody in the first corner.
It wouldn't work unless there was a fifth person!
There's someone here... There's someone here!
What a relief!
Because there's four of us,
we made it without falling asleep.
No... listen to me...
There was a fifth.
Someone who shouldn't have been there!
A fifth?
It was thanks to them...
Did they save us?
Who was it?
I knew five was better than four!
Cheers, Mask-Face!
Something's wrong.
Why aren't they here?
Why?
I'm sure I got the time right.
They all got it wrong!
Oh, well. I guess I'm alone today.
Shopping Street Palm. Eight hundred metres long.
Feels longer when you're walking it alone.
I bought some chicken after being tempted
by the scent from one of the arcade shops.
Pretending you're in "The Lonely Gourmet"?
I'm here, you know!
Oh, it's Gankyou, the graduée.
I didn't so much graduate as got forced out!
Besides, we're in the same year!
If we're in the same year, then...
Then what?
Thank you for your continued appreciation.
I'm coming in—
Newbie! You forgot the greeting!
What's with that attitude?
It's nothing, I promise.
I apologise.
Remember, kiddo, this world's got
a pecking order. You can't escape it.
Kigu, she's all yours.
Make sure you educate her properly!
Yessir!
I will drill the pecking order deep into her!
Really drilling it deep.
No, wait!
Even though I'm on top,
it looks like I'm lower on the totem pole!
It doesn't work if you treat me like a kid!
Newbies should be able to figure out
what the pros want from their actions,
without them having to make it abundantly clear!
No, Kigu! You're underage!
You're too young to smoke!
Hey, now! That's Ms. Kigu for you!
When I do this, I obviously want an Umaibou snack!
I didn't realise, Ms. Kigu.
You really are an incompetent girl.
What's this? Curry flavour?
How do you not know that
I only eat Corn Potage Umaibou?!
Forgive me.
Geez. The least you can do is learn
your supervisor's favourite Umaibou flavour.
Although I like this flavour, too.
Then why not just shut up and eat it?
Next.
I know this one! Newspaper, right?
No! Besides, this is Strawberry News!
You really are dumb.
I apologise.
When I go like this, obviously I want a giant rice cracker.
Is it just all snacks?
That makes it easier, at least.
Her index finger? What does it mean?
Index finger... Index finger...
A single finger...
Hey, so you can get it right!
This means I want a potato ring.
Thank you, Ms. Kigu.
Yes! Five fingers mean five Bugles!
There's simply no better way to eat them!
It's bound to make your folks mad, though.
Anyhoo...
Well done!
She's really getting the hang of it.
Looks like a lot of work.
Yes, it does. Let's try to stay out of it.
Hey, guys! Why don't you come get in on the action?
I-I'm good...
No, no, Ms. Supervisor. I implore.
Let me guess what you want from the way you act.
D-Don't you feel like something strange is going on?
Ah! Tetora's gone!
It's a tragedy! A tragedy has taken place!
Hey, rookie.
You didn't mention it yet,
but you want a steaming winter hotpot, right?
Nice and boiling hot!
I'm so glad you like it!
Meeting your desires is the greatest honour.
No, dammit!
Oh? Could it be that you were looking for
this red-hot piece of metal instead?
Or these?
Hotpot! Just hotpot!
That's what I thought.
Looks like I finally became someone
who can understand the feelings of others.
There's no need for words anymore.
I'll know what you want without
being told, my dear supervisors.
Is this what you want?! Is that what you want?!
You, too, will be silenced while I serve you!
Wait.
If you understand others' feelings like that,
it'd be a waste just being our servant.
Time to become a servant to the nation!
Representing you all, I promise to win this election!
Is she even eligible to run for office?
How old is she?
I understand your feelings clear as day!
That's what people call a "dictatorship".
Voters! Cast your votes for Gankyou Kuurubiyuutei!
A politician who loses an election is just a person.
She was never a politician, though.
A crushing defeat.
Yet more debt...
Debt?
Wasn't it a deposit?
You have to pay to announce your candidacy.
Win or lose, you get it back
if you get a certain number of votes.
Wow.
Don't you have to be at least thirty to run, anyway?
Except for members of the Lower House
and the Prefectural Assemblies.
Forget losing, she should never have been able to run.
So what about my three million yen?
What about the election goods I bought
when I sent off my application?
Hah, sounds like you got swindled!
You're the victim of fraud.
Come in, Kigu.
What's up?
Th-The daruma...
She's scared of daruma dolls.
Just put it away, please!
Guess we should.
You think you can just put it away
despite not winning an election yet?!
It's not like you to be this aggressive, Kukuru...
There's a serious taboo against breaking
customs when it comes to lucky talismans!
You're scaring me...
Kukuru's very strict about traditional customs.
Put it away! Hurry! Just put it away!
Kigu's so scared, we have little choice.
Well, why don't you win an election?
Which election doesn't matter.
She just has to win one.
Like this one.
That election is even scarier!
Oh.
If I entered, though, I'd be bound to win.
Nope.
The deposit for this one is two million yen.
Less than the Tokyo governor election.
Forget it.
It's gotta be fraud!
If you just run in every election you can find,
you're bound to win something!
For example?
Like student council elections!
She'd probably have a pretty good
chance with one of those!
Wait!
Japanese student council presidents are a cut above!
Y-You're right! Battling evil organizations and
vengeful ghosts is all in a day's work for them!
Gan can't possibly win against them!
It's all good.
I might have lost when it comes to popularity,
but I've never lost when it comes to violence!
I can't tell if that's a boast or a roast.
There's no need to risk competing at such a high level.
Why not run in a lower-stakes election,
like a neighbourhood association or something?
Ah, good idea!
I got it! The list of candidates!
Let's see...
Gan seems unqualified.
What? Why?
Don't worry. I'll turn you into a qualified person in no time!
Wh-What are you planning?!
You're not qualified to be a neighbourhood association
president... unless you're completely bald!
Maybe that's not such a good idea.
There must be other options.
It's come to this...
I'll enter any election!
Where am I?
Who's there?
Welcome. We have accepted your candidacy.
Former Prime Minister Hatoyama?!
That was a temporary form.
Truthfully, I am former Solar System Governor
Hatoyama of the Galactic Federation.
So he really was an alien!
I am. My home planet is Venus.
Since I am retiring from the government, there is to be
an election to find the next Solar System Governor.
My poster!
You stood for election.
When?!
You stood among your people
and raised your glasses towards Venus.
This is a crazy coincidence...
Your slogan is...
"I'll Make the Federation Out of This World!"
What's that supposed to mean?
It's a means to an end.
So what you’re actually saying is that
you have put no thought into this at all.
The plan is to go with my gut.
See?
This is terrible. This guy is terrible.
Since you announced your candidacy,
could I trouble you for the deposit?
More deposits! How much?
About one Earth's worth.
The value of the Earth?!
I don't have that kind of money!
Why not just sell the Earth?
You know, that's what I did.
You sold the Earth?
So it wasn't just Japan he sold out.
Earth-selling bastard!
She punched the former governor!
Punched him!
What?!
Oops... I shouldn't have done that...
You win!
Looks like they hate you in space
as well, former governor.
So, to sum it up,
I won the election for Solar System governor.
Oh, it's a secret though. It'd be big news if it got out.
I guess this makes me more important than Obama!
Wow... That's great...
If they found out, the presidents of the world
would come seeking an audience.
So don't tell anyone!
Nope. Don't worry.
Next week is the first meeting
of the Solar System Parliament.
We're discussing increasing blood pressure
across the Solar System.
Remember the manga Level E?
That was basically all true.
Good luck...
Glasses are scarier than darumas...
Gankyou Kuurubiyuutei here.
Looks like we're nearly at the midpoint.
As with life, there comes a point
where you kinda get sick of a show.
You can use stimulation to try and counteract that,
but if the stimulation causes inflation,
it's even more of a pain.
We don't want to push ourselves too much, either.
The next episode of Rakugo Girls
looks a little something like this:
"Delinquents Are Scary", "Something Fishy",
and "Backstage Investigation".