Live long, live long and prosper
jugemu jugemu gokou no surikire
May great wealth await you wherever you go
kaijarisuigyo no suigyoumatsu
Be it on unknown soil or under foreign skies
unraimatsu fuuraimatsu
May you always have your daily bread!
kuuneru tokoro ni sumu tokoro
And always be brimming full of life
yaburakouji no burakouji
Like the long-lived king of Paipo, Shuringan
paipo paipo paipo no shuringan
And his dear wife, Gurindai
shuringan no gurindai
And their children, Ponpokoki and Ponpokona
guurindai no ponpokopi no ponpokona no
Who lived a long and blessed life
choukyuumei no chousuke
Esteemed guests, spare us but a moment of your time!
choi to ojikan itadakimasu
All eyes on the stage!
goseichou kudasai
All ready to go!
totonoimashita
Someone who smiles a lot
warau koto to kakemashita
And a traditional Japanese coat
omatsuri yarou to tokimasu
What do they share in common?
sono kokoro wa
They're both happi! Haha, get it?
dochira mo happi ni naru deshou
Thank you kindly for your appreciation!
oato ga yoroshii yo de
Let's laugh, crack open a smile!
waraou waraou
C'mon, it'll be worthwhile!
saa waraimasho
We could all use a bit of laughter these days
konna jidai koso waraimasho
C'mon, grin!
waraou
Yeah, yeah!
soiya soiya
You cry, you lose
naitara made da
Even if it's out of desperation, smile!
yake kuso waraimasho
Ups and downs, highs and lows
haranbanjou
And all that falls in-between
sui mo amai mo
You've overcome so much, Japan! Bravo!
nori koeta appare nipponjin
Laugh no matter what
waraou
Cheer up and let's drown in laughter together!
donna toki demo nanikuso waraimasho
Laugh like it's the last day of your life!
kuuki nante yomazu ni warattoke
Smile!
egao
Like the sun!
Good fortune comes to those who can give a hearty laugh!
warau kado ni wa fuku kitaru