Heya! This is an additional track that contains
trivia about our translation choices, references,
and other fun and interesting little titbits.
Heya! This is an additional track that contains
trivia about our translation choices, references,
and other fun and interesting little titbits.
This track is only recommended for viewers
who don’t mind if we sap out all the comedy
by over-explaining jokes, references, etc.,
and geeking out over cool bits of trivia.
This track is only recommended for viewers
who don’t mind if we sap out all the comedy
by over-explaining jokes, references, etc.,
and geeking out over cool bits of trivia.
For regular viewing, we highly recommend
you switch to the first subtitle track,
and maybe revisit this track on a rewatch?
For regular viewing, we highly recommend
you switch to the first subtitle track,
and maybe revisit this track on a rewatch?
This track may contain spoilers to other works,
cover large parts of the show, and require
frequent pausing. Watch at your own expense!
This track may contain spoilers to other works,
cover large parts of the show, and require
frequent pausing. Watch at your own expense!
If you'd like to learn more, we include additional
comments and resources in the subtitle files,
which you can access by extracting this track.
If you'd like to learn more, we include additional
comments and resources in the subtitle files,
which you can access by extracting this track.
We hope you enjoy the show! - Kaleido Team
Tetora is performing "rakugo", a classic
Japanese comedic storytelling art, and
is also where the title comes from.
Tetora is performing "rakugo", a classic
Japanese comedic storytelling art, and
is also where the title comes from.
These stories often contain a lot of
clever wordplay and exaggerated voices,
making them a pita to translate.
These stories often contain a lot of
clever wordplay and exaggerated voices,
making them a pita to translate.
The audience being so small likely indicates this
opening act was performed very early in the day.
In Japan, seal stamps are commonly used in situations
where Westerners would typically sign documents.
Couriers will often take either, so you can simply sign
if you don't have your seal stamp on hand.
In Japan, seal stamps are commonly used in situations
where Westerners would typically sign documents.
Couriers will often take either, so you can simply sign
if you don't have your seal stamp on hand.
Pun on aisatsu (greeting) and haitatsu (delivery).
The name plate with the performer's name in the shimote
(left wing) is called the mekuri. It gets continually
swapped out as the programme continues.
The name plate with the performer's name in the shimote
(left wing) is called the mekuri. It gets continually
swapped out as the programme continues.
That sound you hear in the BGM is made by this
instrument: the tsuzumi, a type of drum.
In the background is a joshiki-maku,
a curtain that is often raised and
lowered in between kabuki plays.
In the background is a joshiki-maku,
a curtain that is often raised and
lowered in between kabuki plays.
The colour palette originates from Morita-za,
which was a kabuki theatre located in Edo
(former Tokyo) in the 1600s.
The colour palette originates from Morita-za,
which was a kabuki theatre located in Edo
(former Tokyo) in the 1600s.
The onomatopoeia "chin-ton-shan" is the sound
the shamisen's three strings make.
Sugoroku is a traditional Japanese board game
that plays similar to Snakes & Ladders.
From a bonus page in volume 2 of the manga,
where the girls can be seen pretending to eat soba.
The main quintet are riding the Type 61,
a Japanese tank first deployed in 1961.
This scene is inspired by
Idiots Are Coming in Tanks (1964).
Toraya is a confectionery shop in Tokyo.
Rakugo performers often bought their
yokan (a type of sweet) as a gift when
apologising to their mentors.
Toraya is a confectionery shop in Tokyo.
Rakugo performers often bought their
yokan (a type of sweet) as a gift when
apologising to their mentors.
Tanakaya is a reference to Masaga Tanaka,
the character designer for Rakugo Girls.
In the background, Tokyo Tower and Tokyo Skytree
can be seen on the verge of collapse.
Wagasa (oil-paper umbrellas) were historically used to show
nobility. Now it's often considered an objet d’art, and they're
very common in kabuki theatres.
Wagasa (oil-paper umbrellas) were historically used to show
nobility. Now it's often considered an objet d’art, and they're
very common in kabuki theatres.
Red wagasa often symbolise happiness and good luck,
while purple often symbolise longevity for elders.
In this case, it's probably referring to rakugo and
its dwindling popularity with the youth.
Red wagasa often symbolise happiness and good luck,
while purple often symbolise longevity for elders.
In this case, it's probably referring to rakugo and
its dwindling popularity with the youth.
Gankyou is seen here playing the shamisen, the instrument
that makes the "twing-twang" sound in the intro.
This may be a reference to the K-ON! Opening.
The way Tetora moves Kukuru is a reference to
the rakugo story "The Camel", where a deceased
"camel" is made to dance.
The way Tetora moves Kukuru is a reference to
the rakugo story "The Camel", where a deceased
"camel" is made to dance.
These are all casual clothes shown in
volume 2 bonus pages of the manga.
This flat, monochromatic colour scheme may be a homage
to Akiyuki Shinbo, an anime director mostly known for
his heavy involvement in studio Shaft productions.
This flat, monochromatic colour scheme may be a homage
to Akiyuki Shinbo, an anime director mostly known for
his heavy involvement in studio Shaft productions.
This entire cut is animated on "ones",
meaning every frame is a unique drawing.
This takes a lot of time and effort to do!
This entire cut is animated on "ones",
meaning every frame is a unique drawing.
This takes a lot of time and effort to do!
This is the standard frame rate for Disney
animation, but your average anime will be
animated on twos or threes, mostly for
timing purposes and to reduce workload.
This is the standard frame rate for Disney
animation, but your average anime will be
animated on twos or threes, mostly for
timing purposes and to reduce workload.
The TV behind Gankyou is the SF1 SNES TV.
This model came out in 1990!
She's talking about you.
A twist on a famous line from the theatrical anime film,
"Porco Rosso." The original line goes "A pig who can't
fly is just a pig."
A twist on a famous line from the theatrical anime film,
"Porco Rosso." The original line goes "A pig who can't
fly is just a pig."
This title is likely a reference to "Konnyaku Mondou"
(the Konnyaku Dialogues), originating from Osaka,
where it's known as "Mochiya Mondou" (the Mochi
Shop Dialogues).
This title is likely a reference to "Konnyaku Mondou"
(the Konnyaku Dialogues), originating from Osaka,
where it's known as "Mochiya Mondou" (the Mochi
Shop Dialogues).
Marii takes on the tsukkomi (straight man) role,
a very common trope in Japanese comedy.
The phrase Marii  is using is a common tsukkomi response on 2ch.
The names blurred here are real beef bowl restaurants.
In order: Yoshinoya, Matsuya, Sukiya, and Tokyo Chikara Meshi.
The egg holding the bowl is the manga artist, Yudetamago.
The birds are obviously stand-ins for Tweets.
Back when the Rakugo Girl's one-shot was first published,
Yudetamago's comments on Twitter cracked a lot of eggs
the wrong way.
Back when the Rakugo Girl's one-shot was first published,
Yudetamago's comments on Twitter cracked a lot of eggs
the wrong way.
The outfit with glasses is inspired by Saori Bajeena,
a side-character from My Little Sister Can't Be This Cute.
This invitation mentions Kodansha, the publishing company's,
12th basement level. They don't actually have one, but they do
have a private underground access point near the Tokyo Metro
Gokokuji Station.
This invitation mentions Kodansha, the publishing company's,
12th basement level. They don't actually have one, but they do
have a private underground access point near the Tokyo Metro
Gokokuji Station.
They also mention directions that are
directly taken from Kodansha's website.
There are various people dressed as manga characters,
such as the Naked General, Fujiko Mine, and Lupin III.
These parties are often hosted in upscale hotels,
so it's important party-goers follow the dress code.
Various female uniforms, such as for students, McDonalds and 7-Eleven
employees, etc. The girl in the blue apron is a Yoshinoya employee.
Apache Baseball Team, which was adapted into an anime
in 1971 by Toei Animation. "Being naked is our uniform"
is a lyric in its Opening Theme.
Apache Baseball Team, which was adapted into an anime
in 1971 by Toei Animation. "Being naked is our uniform"
is a lyric in its Opening Theme.
That's what Google is for, baby.
All the character's names are actually puns!
A brief explanation is displayed alongside them.
Japanese names are typically rendered as surname → first name, unlike
the western first name → surname, so "Marii Buratei" would typically
be read as "Buratei Marii", or "Bloody Mary" in Japan. There is a lot of
contention surrounding name order in western Japanese media fan circles.
Japanese names are typically rendered as surname → first name, unlike
the western first name → surname, so "Marii Buratei" would typically
be read as "Buratei Marii", or "Bloody Mary" in Japan. There is a lot of
contention surrounding name order in western Japanese media fan circles.
Bloody Mary is a popular urban legend involving a ghostly
apparition named Bloody Mary, said to appear in a mirror
when summoned by chanting her name three times in the dark.
Bloody Mary is a popular urban legend involving a ghostly
apparition named Bloody Mary, said to appear in a mirror
when summoned by chanting her name three times in the dark.
Toshitaka Saito serves as a director
for the variety show, Downtown's
This Is Not a Test!. He often appears
as a cowardly character on the show.
Toshitaka Saito serves as a director
for the variety show, Downtown's
This Is Not a Test!. He often appears
as a cowardly character on the show.
His nickname used to be "Renho",
but it seems he changed it, likely
due to past implications.
His nickname used to be "Renho",
but it seems he changed it, likely
due to past implications.
The so-called "Manga and Anime Regulation Issue".
The purpose of this bill was to reduce sexual
depictions of minors in anime and manga, but due to
its open-ended phrasing, they were afraid this bill
would be heavily abused.
The so-called "Manga and Anime Regulation Issue".
The purpose of this bill was to reduce sexual
depictions of minors in anime and manga, but due to
its open-ended phrasing, they were afraid this bill
would be heavily abused.
This is likely a reference to nuclear energy,
which has been a hot topic since the 2011
Tohoku Japan earthquake.
This is likely a reference to nuclear energy,
which has been a hot topic since the 2011
Tohoku Japan earthquake.
"That's all folks!" is the signature
closing sequence for Looney Tunes.
This signboard on the right reads "Peace",
from the phrase "Love & Peace".
This place on the right, "Denboko Tei", is playful
twist on the European-style bar, "Bodegon Tei".
Suehiro Tei, the name of this theatre, is
a real rakugo theatre located in Shinjuku.
All of these names are puns:
____- "Fourth Dirty Harry" (from the Dirty Harry films)
____- "Biollante Godzilla" (from the 1989 film, Godzilla vs. Biollante)
____- "Musunde Hiraite" (a popular Japanese children's song)
____- "Andanta Largo" (terms used for pacing in music)
____- "Doushite kou natta" (slang, similar to how we may say, "How did we get here?")
____- "City Boy" (reference to a tweet by the Rakugo Girls director, Mizushima Tsutomu)
____- "Love Me, Love Me" (song by the Japanese band, "The Beavers")
All of these names are puns:
____- "Fourth Dirty Harry" (from the Dirty Harry films)
____- "Biollante Godzilla" (from the 1989 film, Godzilla vs. Biollante)
____- "Musunde Hiraite" (a popular Japanese children's song)
____- "Andanta Largo" (terms used for pacing in music)
____- "Doushite kou natta" (slang, similar to how we may say, "How did we get here?")
____- "City Boy" (reference to a tweet by the Rakugo Girls director, Mizushima Tsutomu)
____- "Love Me, Love Me" (song by the Japanese band, "The Beavers")
A couple more name puns (including some shown later):
____- "Nekonotei Kokaritai" (an expression for being in dire need)
____- "Kaitei Kazen" (submarine volcano)
____- "Maternity Dress"
____- "Chiba Lotte Marines" (pacific league team)
____- "Safety Bunt" (a bunt in baseball to tap the ball, safety probably comes from "playing it safe")
A couple more name puns (including some shown later):
____- "Nekonotei Kokaritai" (an expression for being in dire need)
____- "Kaitei Kazen" (submarine volcano)
____- "Maternity Dress"
____- "Chiba Lotte Marines" (pacific league team)
____- "Safety Bunt" (a bunt in baseball to tap the ball, safety probably comes from "playing it safe")
The greeting used here is a typical greeting in the rakugo scene.
Gankyou is dressed up in gothic lolita, a Japanese fashion style blending
Victorian and Gothic aesthetics with a doll-like look. Many anime characters
dress up in this style, such as Victorique from Gosick.
Gankyou is dressed up in gothic lolita, a Japanese fashion style blending
Victorian and Gothic aesthetics with a doll-like look. Many anime characters
dress up in this style, such as Victorique from Gosick.
The performer listed in the background is Yakokutei Mondo,
a nod to Italian documentary film director Gualtiero Jacopetti.
He pioneered the genre of "mondo films", documentaries infamous
for their emphasis on engaging storytelling over factual accuracy.
Gankyou is listing off a bunch of real variations on the gothic lolita
style. "Sweet loli" is characterised by lots of pink and white, resembling
a more princess-like style. "Black loli" is a subset of "sweet loli", but
features a predominantly black colour scheme. You can infer what the
others mean.
Gankyou is listing off a bunch of real variations on the gothic lolita
style. "Sweet loli" is characterised by lots of pink and white, resembling
a more princess-like style. "Black loli" is a subset of "sweet loli", but
features a predominantly black colour scheme. You can infer what the
others mean.
The four remaining rakugo theatres in Tokyo are the Suehiro Tei
(where they are now), Engei Hall, Suzumoto Entertainment Hall,
and the Engeijo theatre.
The four remaining rakugo theatres in Tokyo are the Suehiro Tei
(where they are now), Engei Hall, Suzumoto Entertainment Hall,
and the Engeijo theatre.
There used to be around 300 theatres in Edo, and even
after World War II, there were still six theatres primarily
dedicated to rakugo. "There are still four left" really
reflects how much the rakugo landscape has changed.
There used to be around 300 theatres in Edo, and even
after World War II, there were still six theatres primarily
dedicated to rakugo. "There are still four left" really
reflects how much the rakugo landscape has changed.
These are all rakugo performer ranking terms.
A haori is a short, stylish jacket worn over a kimono.
Second rakugo performers may use it as a prop
during their performances.
A haori is a short, stylish jacket worn over a kimono.
Second rakugo performers may use it as a prop
during their performances.
The Dalai Lama, a title given by the Tibetan people to the
foremost spiritual leader of the Gelug or "Yellow Hat"
school of Tibetan Buddhism.
The Dalai Lama, a title given by the Tibetan people to the
foremost spiritual leader of the Gelug or "Yellow Hat"
school of Tibetan Buddhism.
What you hear is the ichiban-daiko, or the "first drum".
It signals that the theatre is about to open.
It's typically the junior apprentices,
or "maizaza's", job to announce it.
In the background you can see the schedule for the day.
There's a lot of references hidden in here as well.
A handful of the more interesting ones:
____- Procen Studio (recording studio for Rakugo Girls)
____- REAL-T (the editor for the manga)
____- Studio Kanon (background art for Rakugo Girls)
____- Kumeta Kouji (the author of the Rakugo Girls manga)
____- Yasu (the artist of the Rakugo Girls manga)
____- J.C. Staff (the animation studio for Rakugo Girls)
____- Japan Meteorological Agency
____- Doraemon (popular kids' anime character)
In the background you can see the schedule for the day.
There's a lot of references hidden in here as well.
A handful of the more interesting ones:
____- Procen Studio (recording studio for Rakugo Girls)
____- REAL-T (the editor for the manga)
____- Studio Kanon (background art for Rakugo Girls)
____- Kumeta Kouji (the author of the Rakugo Girls manga)
____- Yasu (the artist of the Rakugo Girls manga)
____- J.C. Staff (the animation studio for Rakugo Girls)
____- Japan Meteorological Agency
____- Doraemon (popular kids' anime character)
This title is a reference to the rakugo play, Akbizinan (Yawning Guide).
The story revolves around a young man who wants to start a new practice
with his friends. Together, they visit the "Akbizinanjo,"
seeking guidance on yawning.
This title is a reference to the rakugo play, Akbizinan (Yawning Guide).
The story revolves around a young man who wants to start a new practice
with his friends. Together, they visit the "Akbizinanjo,"
seeking guidance on yawning.
This is not necessarily true. Tea and coffee caffeine levels change with brewing.
Tea has 3.5% caffeine in leaves, while unbrewed coffee beans contain 1.1-2.2%.
Coffee brewing usually results in a higher caffeine content than tea.
This is not necessarily true. Tea and coffee caffeine levels change with brewing.
Tea has 3.5% caffeine in leaves, while unbrewed coffee beans contain 1.1-2.2%.
Coffee brewing usually results in a higher caffeine content than tea.
From a segment in Super Jockey called the "Hot Water Commercial".
The exact comparison she makes here is between two chocolate
biscuit brands, "Kinoko no Yama" and "Takenoko no Sato".
From the show "Magical Brain Power!!": "A person with the face
of Fujiwara Kika and the body of KONISHIKI, or a person with
the face of KONISHIKI and the body of Fujiwara Kika?"
From the show "Magical Brain Power!!": "A person with the face
of Fujiwara Kika and the body of KONISHIKI, or a person with
the face of KONISHIKI and the body of Fujiwara Kika?"
Snoopy from the comic strip Peanuts.
Perlorian, photographs of cats in human clothes
that were popular in the 80s. They started with
delinquent-style clothes.
Perlorian, photographs of cats in human clothes
that were popular in the 80s. They started with
delinquent-style clothes.
Likely a reference to The Ultimate Choice, where they asked
whether participants would rather eat unappetising curry or
something that looks unappetising but tastes like curry.
Likely a reference to The Ultimate Choice, where they asked
whether participants would rather eat unappetising curry or
something that looks unappetising but tastes like curry.
The house is from the Ending Theme of Sazae-san.
Outside the window are a large amount
of Cat Gods from Pani Poni Dash.
Shamisen used to be made of cat or dog skin, depending on the sound
you wanted to play. Luckily, most use synthetic materials like plastic
instead nowadays.
Shamisen used to be made of cat or dog skin, depending on the sound
you wanted to play. Luckily, most use synthetic materials like plastic
instead nowadays.
Chiri Kitsu from Sayonara Zetsubou-sensei.
Either King Kong or Robot Monster (1953).
May be referring to an incident that occurred in August 2011,
where a woman and her friends dug a pitfall to prank her husband,
and both of them fell in and suffocated to death.
May be referring to an incident that occurred in August 2011,
where a woman and her friends dug a pitfall to prank her husband,
and both of them fell in and suffocated to death.
Kamehameha the Great, the conqueror and
first ruler of the Kingdom of Hawaii.
Assuming standard atmospheric conditions, the speed of
sound is approximately 343 m/s (roughly 767 mph).
The distance from Japan to Hawaii is roughly 6400–6500 km.
We can calculate the time it takes to reach in seconds by doing
6400 x 1000 / 340, which is about 18824 seconds. That's 5 hours,
13 minutes, and no sound because it would have dispersed aeons
before it'd reach the shoreline of Hawaii.
The distance from Japan to Hawaii is roughly 6400–6500 km.
We can calculate the time it takes to reach in seconds by doing
6400 x 1000 / 340, which is about 18824 seconds. That's 5 hours,
13 minutes, and no sound because it would have dispersed aeons
before it'd reach the shoreline of Hawaii.
The Kuril Islands dispute, a territorial
dispute between Japan and Russia.
The abductions of Japanese citizens
by North Korea from 1977 to 1983.
Various allegations of China stealing Japanese technology.
The Senkaku Islands dispute between Japan, China, and Taiwan.
The National Diet Building. In 2012, the Social Security and
Tax Reform Act passed, increasing consumption taxes.
The float Tetora is dancing on is from the Mid-Autumn
Festival held in Kansai. The "daikogata" who dance on
it are considered the highlight of the festival.
The float Tetora is dancing on is from the Mid-Autumn
Festival held in Kansai. The "daikogata" who dance on
it are considered the highlight of the festival.
The portable shrine Gankyou is riding is the Hanazono Shrine.
It's paraded around Shinjuku during the annual festival.
The tree stump Kukuru is riding
is a reference to the Onbashira Festival.
Festival of San Fermín, a Spanish
festival known for its bull running.
Parody of a photo taken during
the Beatles' tour to Japan.
The Tokyo Tower, Tokyo Skytree,
and Sky Tower West Tokyo.