So Kumagoro comes back in the morning
and knocks on the door of the old lady's house.
Knock-knock, knock-knock.
"Who's this? Do you bring news of my father's death?"
"You batty ole bird, yer dad popped 'is clogs thirty years ago!"
"It's me, Kumagoro the carpenter."
"Oh, so it is. What are you after at this hour?"
"I came to let ya know that, thanks t'you,
I finally managed to make a delicacy."
"Well now, isn't that wonderful?"
"Learning to cook like that is a sign
that you've really grown as a person."
"You honestly deserve a great deal
of praise, young man."
"So, what kind of delicacy did you make?"
"Ah, well I just handed over the package,
asked fer the guy's seal stamp,"
"and let 'im know that if 'e didn't have
his seal handy, 'e could sign fer it."
"You idiot."
"That's not a delicacy, but a delivery!"
Thank you for your continued appreciation.
I learned a lot on stage today.
If you want to read manga, read manga.
Adapting it into an anime makes no sense!
What's this all of a sudden?
What're you saying?
Why take a perfectly fine manga,
where we do little more than talk in this room
day in, day out, and make an anime out of it?
Well, when you put it like that...
You have a point.
You said it.
Wh-What?!
Stop this!
It may be unnecessary, but they're going through
a lot of trouble to animate us in incredible detail!
It's a bit much to say the whole thing's a flop, Gan.
I didn't say anything of the sort!
You lot were on the verge of being convinced, too.
Dear God, if we're turned into an anime,
please make it so Gan's the only one who doesn't move.
Hey!
At any rate, the audience is definitely
a lot bigger than the manga's.
But most viewers aren't watching this
on official streaming services.
Only lowlifes would watch a show
without paying for it.
Feeling like I'm being watched makes me nervous!
Idiot. Just do what you usually do.
The conversations in this anime
are written to be as inoffensive as possible
so as not to interfere with
your enjoyment of viewing cute girls.
Yeah, but "usual" is kind of hard to define, isn't it?
What does everyone do usually?
Don't ask such dull questions!
Shopping, I guess?
I read. Surf the net.
Sleep.
Is that really a "usual" activity?
I guess it kind of is, actually.
Sleep's important.
Well, in that case, I "usually" eat and drink.
Yep, yep! Good one.
I usually breathe!
I usually resent and begrudge.
Yep, yep! Good—What the hell?
You need some more positivity in your life.
I live...
So the answer to "what do you do usually?" is... live?
That's the biggest cop-out I've ever heard.
So basically, I'd say eating, sleeping, and...
And rakugo! Right?
Eh?
Y'know, as rakugo performers
we should eat, sleep and breathe rakug—
Hey guys! What do you usually like to eat?
Don't ask such dull questions!
You mean if we talk about the usual stuff,
things'll just play out like usual?
I would say the thing I eat the most is beef bowls.
Oh, what place do you like best?
Knock it off. Don't go asking about specific names.
You'll cause us all kinds of headaches.
Yeah, but if we cut a deal to promote a brand,
then we'll probably get to eat for free!
You don't think that'd be a headache?
I used to find it difficult to go into beef bowl places.
How come?
They're always packed with dudes.
You can't look like you're trying too hard,
but you can't look like you're not trying at all.
You don't want to stand out or be an outcast.
Yeah, it's hard to pick out clothes
for a situation like that.
Geez, why make a special effort?
Just wear your usual clothes.
Sorry to change the subject,
but we've been invited to a party.
An invitation?
I don't think you changed the subject.
Hm?
Look here!
"Please wear your usual clothes."
Usual clothes.
How usual are we talking?
"Usual" is hard to define.
"Please wear your usual clothes", pfft.
That doesn't mean you can go
wearing your usual clothes!
How many poor manga artists have been
publicly shamed by taking that phrase at face value?
Your "usual clothes" is just a tracksuit, isn't it?
Wearing that to a party would be pretty uncouth.
Why have you all decided
my usual clothes are a tracksuit?
If everyone in the world went to
a party wearing their usual clothes,
it'd look like some sort of cosplay event.
Students usually wear a school uniform,
and people who have work clothes usually wear those.
Yeah, those are the clothes you end up
wearing the most, aren't they?
So "please wear your usual clothes"
is code for "cosplay party"?
That's kinda saucy...
I definitely don't think that's it.
Who even knows that many people
with interesting jobs?
I really don't think they mean work clothes.
So they mean your civvies?
I wear different things on any given day.
You could just wear whatever you'd
decided to wear on that particular day.
That's it!
Pajamas count as "usual clothes"?
Well they're what you wear most
outside of work clothes, right?
Hey, you're right!
I saw on TV it's fashionable
to go out wearing pajamas in China.
What do you mean?
I guess it makes it look like you're
a cool person who lives downtown.
Ah, but didn't they ban it before
the Olympics for being indecent?
Anyway, I think we've found
the ultimate "usual clothes"!
In other words, "please wear your usual clothes"
is code for "we're having a pajama party"!
That's kinda saucy...
I definitely don't think that's it.
Pajamas? Really?
Are you sure you sleep in pajamas?
Wh-What else would I wear?
When you sleep, you wear p-p-pajamas!
That's not what you said!
When I sleep I just let it all hang out.
Let it...
all...
hang...
out...
That means Marii's usual clothes are... nothing!
That's not "clothes", you numbskull!
So a "please wear your usual clothes" party
is code for a completely nude party?
Is that what you're saying?
That's kinda saucy!
I think that goes a bit beyond saucy!
Let's strip her down.
Or should I say...
Put her in her usual clothes.
Gerroff me!
Deal with it!
This is definitely not to boost the ratings!
And it's definitely not to increase sales either!
The hell is wrong with you people?!
You're very sexy all of a sudden.
This could be the start of a new career direction.
It gets a lot sexier if you flip this up.
So it does.
Even though you can't really see any more.
Cut it out, guys!
People are gonna start losing respect for me!
Can you really lose something you never had?
Being naked all the time reminds me of a baseball
manga... that I can't name because of copyright.
What kinda reference was that?
There's no way anybody's gonna get that!
It's flippin' time!
It's not like flipping the sheet will show more anyway!
No!
This makes it look like I'm the nude one!
I'm not having it!
Now it looks like I'm the nude one!
This won't do!
Make it someone else!
Now it looks like I'm the nude one!
Only fairies are allowed to be naked!
Now it looks like I'm not wearing
anything, glasses included!
Huh?
Wait...
Did we just...
Perfectly introduce all the main characters...
For non-manga readers?
Perfectly?
Someone else!
What the? He's not even in this.
That's not a name!
That's not even writing!
Too long!
Who's "we"?
Not relevant!
I'm trying to fix that!
We'll be right back!
Greetings to you.
Greetings to you!
Morning, Kigu.
Morning!
What are you listening to?
Here, have a listen!
What in the world...
Death metal!
Not what I was expecting.
Greetings to you!
What weren't you expecting?
Not what we were expecting...
Yeah, what isn't?
That you'd wear something like that.
Are you sure this isn't a bit of a stretch?
Rude! What do you mean by "stretch"?
Well, like when a fat person wears
unflattering colours like white or pink...
That's called go-thick loli.
Go... thick?
Yeah, thick as in thick.
There's also sweet loli, black loli, friend loli,
granny loli, grampy loli, ugly loli...
So what about you, where you
just wear whatever you like?
Erratic loli.
If you move your head like that, you'll...
Get-sick loli.
Right now, we're...
Frolic jolly!
They call permanent vaudeville theatres "fixed seats".
There are only four left now, though.
You mean there are still four left!
They call the stage the "high seat".
There's no "low seat" though.
They say you "go up" to the high seat,
but isn't it more like sitting down?
When you start out, you're called a "Starter".
After a while, you get promoted to a "Second".
Then you get the right to wear a haori...
And the title of "Headliner".
Phew, it's a bit hot today.
Here, have some wind.
Wipe your face with this drama.
Thanks, guys.
I get what you mean by "wind",
but why did you call this a "drama"?
Because it's what I use to drama-self off.
I'm just dra-mazed you thought
that was worth the setup.
Look at all these Dalai Drama!
'Sup guys?
Here comes drama.
That's the first thing you say to me?
Hey, the tracksuit look actually really suits you.
Yeah, there's something quite... Marii-ish about it.
It's very you.
I'm not sure whether to
take these as compliments or not!
They're not.
Anyway, you're a rakugo performer.
You should say "greetings to you", not "'sup guys"!
I always get those mixed up. Either works, right?
You drama-teur.
The drum means it's starting.
What kind of noodles do you
want today, udon or soba?
Don't ask such dull questions!
Soba.
Udon, I think.
Um?
Are we forgetting something?
Spices?
Chopsticks?
Ordering?
Ah well.
Greetings to you!
"Purr! Purr-purr!"
"C'mon, I don't understand
what you're tryin' to say!"
"You're pawin' at my knees...
you must want something real bad."
"What on earth could it be?"
"Purrrr... purrr... "
"Minimum service charge is twenty purrcent, sir."
Thank you for your continued appreciation!
Um, this is a difficult question, but...
Are you guys dog people or cat people?
Don't ask such dull questions!
The conversations in this anime are
written to be as inoffensive as possible
so as not to interfere with your
enjoyment of viewing cute girls.
Ugh, this is so stupid.
Which is it?
I like them both.
Me too.
And which do you like better, coffee or tea?
Don't ask such dull questions!
Coffee.
Coffee for me, too.
If I had to pick, tea. The smell is so relaxing.
Tea actually has more caffeine than coffee.
Oh, really?
Which do you like more, iced or hot?
Iced!
Hot, I think.
A cold bath or a hot bath?
Weird question.
Hot, obviously.
Hot, so they don't cheat you by using too much ice.
Come on, you guys.
A real choice would be something like
crunchy versus smooth peanut bu—
If I had to choose between cats and dogs...
Hey! What about sumo-style girls and—
I like the sound dogs make more...
Nah, it's gotta be cats.
Dogs get to be in the zodiac and be police officers.
I feel sorry for cats getting left out.
Yeah, but then there are expressions like
"dogs of war", which are unfair to dogs.
Cats have things like "what the cat dragged in",
"cat burglar", "scaredy-cat", and so forth.
Evil spirits and stuff in folk tales are always cats.
You ever heard of a witch's dog?
They have that vengeful aura.
Dogs are too friendly to be ghosts.
Can you imagine a dog with a grudge?
They're just not cut out for it.
Not at all.
There are loads of famous dog characters!
Cat ones, too.
Poop-flavoured curry or curry-flav—
When it comes to sound, cat is better than dog.
Sound?
Well, dog sounds so military.
Military?
Fetch!
Oh, like military training?
Yeah, skill training.
My dog has no skills at all.
If you want, I could bring him by for training.
Sure thing.
I just hate the character for dog.
How come?
Sometimes when I'm feeling
uncertain and try to write it,
I forget where to put the little thingy.
Don't be stupid!
Yes, but...
Don't you find that the longer you stare at them,
the less sure you are of which one is right?
O-Of course I don't!
Really?
You were hesitating for a sec there.
The character for dog is a person
with their dog beside them.
They're carrying a hoe and working
with their doggy by their side.
Is that true?
I just made it up!
Dogs just wanna be next to people.
Give me strength.
If that was the case, the thingy could go anywhere.
Here, or here, or here, or here, or even here.
Not there! It's being impaled!
Isn't it a bit lonely if there's only one doggy?
No! Poor thing!
Agh! Too many dogs!
She's being attacked!
I've come up with a new character.
"Grieving pet owner".
That's just "big".
Um, this is a difficult question, but do you guys
prefer the ocean or the mountains?
Don't ask such dull questions!
It's a tradition.
Tradition.
What the hell?
I'm so done with you lot.
I deffo prefer the ocean.
Mountains. More delicious.
Do you mean, "Which do you prefer,
the sea in winter or the mountains in winter?"
No, let's go with summer.
Summer...
In summer, decay is a problem in both of those places.
And exactly what are you talking about?
Where you'd rather die,
the ocean or the mountains. Right?
How the hell did you interpret the question that way?
Well, if we're talking about where to die,
I think the mountains are best.
Get all encased in ice at the peak,
and get discovered hundreds of years later!
The people of the future would be so incredibly
moved by my beautiful and inspiring appearance!
How did we end up talking about
ice-encased future corpses?
The question is, which do you prefer,
the mountains or the ocean?
Well, aside from which I like better,
people are coarser at the ocean.
Coarser? Why?
In the mountains, people shout:
"Hello!"
But at the ocean, people shout:
"You dumbass!"
Right?
I see.
I really don't think people yell
"you dumbass" at the ocean.
Oh yeah? Then what do people yell at the ocean, eh?
"Catch me if you can!"
Though that's not at the ocean, per se.
It has nothing to do with the ocean, really.
That tanka poem about playing with a crab?
It's kind of hard to shout a poem.
What?
If you fell in a hole on the beach—
Shut up.
Maybe it is "you dumbass".
Yeah, "you dumbass".
"You dumbass".
Right? Right? Right?
I suppose she's right.
I can't come up with anything else.
Doesn't it change depending on
which ocean you're shouting it at?
How d'you mean?
I think you'd shout different things depending on if
you're facing the Sea of Japan or the Pacific Ocean.
On the Pacific side, there's nobody to shout to.
To shout at King Kamehameha, your voice
has to carry six thousand four hundred kilometres.
Too far!
"You dumbass" travels at
three hundred forty meters per second.
How long does it take to arrive?
Is it quicker to shorten it to "dumbass"?
Yeah, it definitely gets your point across faster.
The Sea of Japan has stuff that's
a lot nearer, so you should shout...
I knew she wouldn't think of anything.
"You dumbass" works fine.
Yeah. Just don't read too much into it.
"You dumbass" can cover a fairly wide angle.
But don't read too much into it.
The issue with "you dumbass" is that it's
so rude, it probably won't solve anything.
Solve?
I've got it.
Give it back!
Yeah, that's it!
You should shout "give it back!" at the ocean.
Yes.
Yeah.
It basically covers every angle.
Give back the Northern Territories!
Give back our citizens!
Give back our technology!
Give back our submarine resources!
Give back everyone's money!
Tetora Bouhatei here.
Thank you so much for stopping by.
It sure has been hot and humid lately, eh?
Be careful. If you sleep with the AC on,
you'll get ill, so watch out.
So anyway, here's what's in the
next episode of Rakugo Girls:
"Backstage Wealth", "Tower Trip",
and "Girl with a Cold".
See you there!