The conversations in this anime
are written to be as inoffensive as possible
so as not to interfere with your enjoyment
of viewing cute girls.
Usual Conversation
Invitation
Party
Marii Buratei
Tetora Bouhatei
A
Kukuru Anrakutei
Kigurumi Haroukitei
A
Gankyou Kuurubiyuutei
Marii
Buratei
Heipo
The nickname of
Saito Toshihide,
a famous
TV personality.
Stand Up,
Japan!
Lovely weather
we're having,
isn't it?
This morning
where dandelions
bloom by the
side of
the road.
P
Wedrewthis!
Tokyo Metropolitan
Ordinance
Regarding The healthy
development of youths.
Endemic lack
of
transparency
Endemic lack
of
transparency
Tetora Bouhatei
Rakugo Girls
Different Clothes
A
Marii Buratei
Rakugo Girls
Shouting Instructions
The conversations in this anime
are written to be as inoffensive as possible
so as not to interfere with your enjoyment
of viewing cute girls.
Year of the
Dog
Dogs of war
Sick as a dog
Die like a dog
What the cat
dragged in
Cat burglar
Cat that ate the canary
Weak as a kitten
Scaredy-cat
Next Time
③ Girl with a Cold
② Tower Trip
① Backstage Wealth