The conversations in this anime
are written to be as inoffensive as possible
so as not to interfere with your enjoyment
of viewing cute girls.
Usual Conversation
Party
Invitation
100th Kodansha Anniversary
Buratei Marii
Bouhatei Tetora
Anrakutei Kukuru
Haroukitei Kigurumi
Kuurubiyuutei Gankyou
Marii
Buratei
Heipo
The nickname of
Saito Toshihide,
a famous
TV personality.
Stand Up,
Japan!
Lovely weather
we're having
don't you think?
This morning,
dandelions bloomed
by the
side of
the road.
P
Wedrewthis
!
Tokyo Metropolitan
Ordinance
Regarding The healthy
development of youths.
Endemic lack
of
transparency
Endemic lack
of
transparency
Bouhatei Tetora
Rakugo Girls
Different Clothes
Buratei Marii
Rakugo Girls
Shouting Instructions
The conversations in this anime
are written to be as inoffensive as possible
so as not to interfere with your enjoyment
of viewing cute girls.
Year of the
Dog
Dogs of War
Sick as a Dog
Die Like a Dog
What the Cat
Dragged In
Cat Burglar
Cat That Ate the Canary
Weak as a Kitten
Scaredy-Cat
You dumbass!
|||||||||||||||||||||
Next Time
① Backstage Wealth
② Tower Trip
③ Girl with a Cold