"Hello, hello, hello, hello!"
"What's with the racket, Yassan?"
"It ain't no racket, no sir!
I'm just preparing for Hello-ween."
"That's not what it's called!"
Thanks for your continued appreciation.
Trick or treat!
You certainly got a lot, Kigu!
You certainly got a lot, Marii!
Yeah!
What is this crap?!
Dried squid.
Crispy peanuts.
Cheese fishsticks.
Very grown-up.
These are bar snacks!
The whole room is gonna stink now!
Am I some kind of old geezer?
Does salami count as sweets?
No, it bloody doesn't!
I got bugger-all as far as sweets go!
What about this?
Sweet beans don't count!
I just want something that could be called candy!
What about this?
Breath mints don't count!
You shouldn't look a gift horse in the mouth.
I know I shouldn't, but...
There's something so un-Halloweeny
about smoked squid and dried fish!
Well, it was originally a Western holiday.
It's always gonna feel funny doing it in Japan.
Nothing's quite as "Halloween" as John Carpenter!
How old are you, Gan?
Kigu!
Halloween wasn't that popular back when we were kids.
When did it start?
They say it started in Urayasu.
Urayasu is...
Ah! I know! It's where Disn—
Shh!
We don't say that name here.
Yeah.
Because we're adults.
Is that really why?
Someone mentions something and everyone goes
"Whoa whoa whoa, you can't say that!"
But imposing restrictions on yourself
out of fear of rumours and bad press
is exactly how an industry dies out.
But what should we do then?
Well, of course we shouldn't impinge on
the precious intellectual rights of others.
But...
Hi everybody!
Stop it!
So I can't talk in a high-pitched voice?
What's wrong with introducing myself like that?
I... guess you're right.
Yeah.
People's voices often break
like that when they're nervous.
Hello!
I'm Kukuru!
I'm Marii!
I'm Gankyou!
I'm Tetora!
My name's Kigu!
People never really used to buy whole pumpkins before.
Or hollow them out and carve faces.
They're sometimes called Jack-o'-lanterns.
Where does Jack Frost come from?
Is Halloween just a commercial holiday
fabricated by the industry, like Valentine's Day?
We're all just dancing to the whims of capitalism...
Ah, I think it's fine.
As long as we have a little self-awareness,
it keeps the economy ticking.
Once Halloween's firmly established,
what do you think they'll try and push next?
Like how White Day followed Valentine's Day.
Thanksgiving? Easter?
We'll probably end up celebrating
American Independence Day in Japan.
I can see them forcing that on us.
And Martin Luther King Jr. Day.
And Presidents' Day.
Ugh, how annoying.
Trick-or-treat, the practise of threatening mischief
unless you get candy, is just so not-Japanese.
How do you mean?
That kind of bullying tactic is typical
of an egotistical superpower.
Big Stick diplomacy.
"Hand over your territory or else."
"Or else we'll burn it to ash."
"Or else we'll continue the tests."
What kind of tests?
It sounds like we should maybe try
and have a Japanified Halloween instead.
Japanified, eh?
Would you give me candy if I recited a poem for you?
That's heavy.
A Japanese Halloween...
If you give me candy, I'll follow you always!
No, Kigu! Don't follow strangers!
Your teachers must have told you that!
He's not a stranger! He's really famous!
Even celebrities are capable of evil.
In fact, celebrities are especially capable of evil!
There could be drugs in the candy for all you know!
I'm talking about the story of Momotarou!
Oh, Momotarou. I see.
That might be a little too Japanese.
Since it's Halloween, how about
we translate it into English?
"Momo" means... peach?
What does "tarou" mean in English?
We just need a popular foreign boy's name.
Like John.
"Peach John"?
That's actually a really sk*tchy name.
It's just your imagination.
Yeah, must be.
Yup.
There's a manga called Peach Girl too, right?
What about Princess Peach?
Or Wedding Peach.
I think we got a little off-topic.
If I'm not allowed to say "If you give me candy,
I'll follow you always!", what should I say instead?
"If you give me candy, I'll say thank you."
You should either way.
It'd be weird if you didn't. You should always
thank people when they give you something.
A version of Halloween where you offer to say thanks
in return for candy is lacking a little "oomph" for a festival.
But on the other hand, we can't go too extravagant.
"If you give me candy..."
"I'll keep my silence."
If you're gonna go down that path,
you should ask for money instead of can—
That's blackmail!
Okay then, "If you give me candy..."
"I'll pray for your health!"
You can get that without handing out candy!
That's just like the palm-readers
you see in front of the station!
Why doesn't everyone just offer whatever they can?
Makes sense.
Whatever we can...
Hey!
"If you give me candy, I'll sing you a song!"
Sweets make me happy, gimme more sweets!
Sticky sherbert mix, candy in a bowl!
She's like a kid who just got her pocket money.
It's not very exciting, and it's not very Halloweeny either.
I could hit up a candy bar right now!
Doesn't it depends more on what you sing?
If you sang death metal, it'd be pretty Halloweeny.
"If you give me candy, I'll sing death metal!"
Hell! Flames! Demons! Despair!
Now that's Halloweeny.
Works for me.
But performing death metal solo is too sad.
Okay, I'll be on guitar!
I'll play bass.
Vocals for me!
I'll play keyboards!
I'll play drums!
Don't we look a bit like the evil counterparts
of a certain light music club anime now?
Or minor antagonists!
Or Krauser!
Let's see your Kaiser Wave, then!
Detroit Metal City, not Fatal Fury!
Minor antagonists would be okay.
I wonder if that show will end up using us?
It'd be five versus five!
And we air on the same channel, so it's gotta be worth it!
Big nope! It's the same company,
but we're on a different channel!
Really?
And here I was hoping we'd get to go to the UK.
If we ain't getting anything out of it, why bother?
Being in a band sucks!
Animating this stuff's a pain in the ass!
They could do it over in Kyoto,
but Musashi-Sakai? Hell, no!
Even animating someone who's turning is hard as hell!
So what should we say in order to get candy?!
If we have to go through all this trouble,
I'd rather not have any at all!
Here!
Ah! I got something!
What are you gonna do?
I-If you give me candy,
I'll give you a mandarin orange!
F-For me?!
If you give me a mandarin,
I'll give you an issue of Jump.
Huh, me now?
If you give me an issue of Jump,
I'll give you an anime DVD!
If you give me an anime DVD,
I'll give you an anime Blu-ray!
If you give me an anime Blu-ray,
I'll give you a PS Vita!
If you give me a PS Vita, I'll give you
a coupon for a spa vacation in Yufuin!
If you give me a coupon for a spa vacation,
I'll give you a Bulgari watch!
If you give me a Bulgari watch,
I'll give you an Hermès bag!
If you give me a bag,
I'll give you a Van Gogh painting!
The Straw Millionaire!
Trading a piece of candy into
a house is like a modern fairytale!
We're straying further and further from Halloween!
I think it was a mistake to go from candy in the first place.
What do you mean?
We learned in elementary school, remember?
C.A.N. for candy!
Ah, to help you remember what to do in an evacuation!
What was it again?
C.A.N. for candy, go!
Consumption tax, Atomic power, New fighter jets
Cold!
Castro, Angela Merkel, North Korea
Absolute zero!
Calm, Aware, No talking
Ah, that's it.
Candy or trick...
Instigate a disaster or I'll trick you?!
It's a bomb threat!
There must be a bomb planted somewhere!
Any of these could be a bomb! Evacuate!
Well, then. Don't mind if I do.
Kabukichou!
The greatest entertainment district in the East.
It's not that far from Suehirotei.
I haven't been before! Woo!
Kigu! If you get too carried away,
they'll carry you away.
There's not really much reason
to come to Kabukichou on a normal day.
Yeah, true. Especially for women on their lonesome.
Marii'd probably blend right in.
Why me?
Well, I mean...
You've already nailed the Kabukichou way.
You callin' me an old geezer again?!
But it suits you.
I'd say Marii is more the Memory Alley type.
Ah, you mean Piss Alley?
Throwing around words like that
is why you come across like an old geezer.
At least say "Pee Alley".
Or "Tinkle Alley".
Or "Urine Alley".
I wonder where the name Kabukichou comes from.
Isn't it just because they do kabuki here?
There aren't any kabuki theatres here.
Really?!
There are a surprising number of
places with names like that.
Kichijouji sounds like a temple name,
but there's no Kichijou Temple.
And there's no university at Toritsu University
or Gakugei University Station.
Like the theme park-less Mukogaoka Theme Park.
I wonder if there's any eucalyptus at
Yukarigaoka Station, since it's named after them.
But hey, there may be none now, but there must've been
loads of kabuki theatres in the past, right?
There have never been any kabuki theatres in Kabukichou.
So it's a scam?!
Where does the name come from, then?
Maybe it's where kabuki actors came to blow off steam...
I don't hate the idea, but it doesn't seem likely.
I wouldn't hate that either.
Kabuki connection aside, that guy seems like
the kind of person who'd be at home here.
But that can't be it...
They were planning to build a kabuki theatre here,
and the name persisted even though
the theatre was never built.
Like how they wanted to build a university
at Oizumi University, but it didn't work out.
Here's where they were going to build the theatre.
This is where the Shinjuku Koma Theater used to be.
The Koma Theater was built after
the plans for the kabuki theatre fell through.
Then it started to fall into disrepair and stopped
pulling in the crowds so they tore it down.
Time really waits for no one.
What are they building here now?
A hotel and cinema complex, apparently.
Not a performance space, huh. Shame.
Times change. Not much you can do about it.
I wanted to go see Peter Pan.
And Matsuken Samba.
And that famous cartwheel scene.
They only perform Vagabond's Song
at the Imperial Theatre now.
Musicals are all well and good, but the Koma Theater
was a legendary venue for enka singers. Hallowed ground!
Hold on there.
If you're talking hallowed ground in Kabukichou,
you can't neglect this place.
Where are we?
The LOFT/PLUS ONE.
Hallowed ground for subcultures.
They have a lot of anime events, too.
They focus mainly on deep, hardcore events.
Looks like there's something on today.
An anime event?
I wonder what it is!
I wasn't expecting that.
I see what you meant by deep and hardcore.
Wouldn't it be great if we had an event here?
Like a group performance!
All together now... bow!
We hope you'll come to our show!
Is it just me, or does it feel like
Kabukichou's gotten a lot safer recently?
There are lots of fun new places.
It's a nice mix of retro and modern.
I think it's a shame.
Kabukichou's meant to be an underground Mecca.
The Harajuku of troublemakers!
You don't think it's better if it's safe?
Eh, I guess you're right.
If you want a taste of danger, why not
visit the South Bronx or Johannesburg?
Too far.
We'll get told off again for using real names.
These aren't even the right images.
How would Kabukichou look if you had your way, Marii?
Lessee now...
'Scuse me, ma'am.
We've got the best girls!
Telephone cards!
Hey lady! C'mere! Ours better! Get you high!
Stop, you punk!
Something like that.
Sounds like that game, Yakuza.
I don't think even that happens in Yakuza.
Nope.
Not at all.
"That's an unthinkable disaster!"
"Well, my groin sure hurts!"
Thanks for your continued appreciation.
What's that? Who's this blank-faced guy?
He's a man whose disappointed
expression I can never forget...
Which one would you like?
Whichever I'm insured for.
I can't forget my dentist's grief-stricken face
when I told him to go with my insurance...
The dentist's expression, huh?
A pro shouldn't be letting their feelings show.
My heart is in pain...
I have no recourse...
He haunts my dreams...
And so, as my penance...
I draw!
How is drawing pictures any kind of penance?
Is it a bit like copying Buddhist sutras by hand?
I didn't really get any of that build-up,
but this week is Cavity Prevention Week!
What do you mean, "this week"?
When this episode goes out,
it'll already be September.
And when it goes on sale, it'll be January.
If there's trouble and the DVD has to be redone,
it could be delayed into February.
Forget delays, maybe it'll just be cancelled altogether.
Wouldn't that be super hilarious!
I wouldn't be laughing.
That'd be no laughing matter.
It wouldn't be funny at all.
Let's not even talk about it.
I know it's a joke, but don't tempt fate.
Anyway, don't worry about that.
We're already deep into the season.
Yeah. No need to stress over small things.
Don't you feel like there are a weirdly high number
of dentists compared to other doctors?
Really?
The puns are a bit too much.
Is it just me, or do the puns get worse
the closer you get towards Kyushu?
They have a good dialect for jokes.
Some of the pun names must
actually be the dentist's real name.
Like Cohen C. Dental?
Axie Dental as well?
Not that I care,
but wasn't the way we treated that first sign a bit shoddy
compared to how we treat that bloody American mouse?
We pussy-foot around that one while
this one is like "Eh, um, well, whatever."
Or is that because one's from
the English-speaking world and the other isn't?
No, no! It's just... an old woman with hair like that.
There are definitely way fewer
doctor's clinics with those kinds of names.
They deal more directly with death,
so maybe a punny name would be in bad taste.
Even cavities can lead to serious
health problems if you ignore them!
People who talk for a living like us
should be especially careful
to get not even a single cavity!
Wow, they're so clean, Kigu!
Of course prevention is a daily task,
and I go to the dentist if I do get a cavity.
I can't help but notice that one of
our number is keeping her back to us.
That's a very clichéd-looking toothache.
No! Marii's got cavities!
Absholutely noh! Shup your mouh!
Poke!
Whah ah you doogh?!
She's got 'em bad.
Go to the dentist!
No way! Neber!
An earthquake could strike Japan at any moment!
Go to the dentist while you still can!
While we're on the subject of earthquakes,
I took the liberty of preparing helmets for us.
Wow, nice!
Emergency warning!
Everyone, prepare to evacuate!
Protect your head!
Marii, you too!
Hurry, put this on!
Looks like it was a false alarm. Phew.
Hearing the emergency alarm sound
makes me reflexively tense up!
To me it sounds like it's saying "Panic! Panic!"
That's definitely not the intended effect!
They should go with something cuter.
That's adorable!
But if there were real cats around,
would you be able to tell the difference?
Hmm, yeah. It should be a sound
you don't hear in real life.
That sounds like Jason's gonna jump out any moment.
They could only play it on Fridays.
The original was Psycho, though.
Surely the best thing would be
to make it customisable, like a ringtone?
I shudder to imagine.
Wheh is ohly my one full-face?
Why are you still wearing it?
Shtop pullihg!
Let her keep wearing it if she wants.
You should go up on stage like that.
If Marii did that, it'd be infringing her character!
She's mad now!
Ow! It hurts!
Painkillers! Does anyone have any painkillers?!
We do have some.
Those are painkillers all right...
Painkillers for the mind.
Painkillers for the mind...
You mean they're happy pills?
Yeah, something like that.
Old mister dentist, old mister dentist,
please pull my cavity, pull it right out!
What are we gonna do? She's acting all weird now!
Pull it out, la la la wa la la wa la la!
Looks like the meds wore off.
Ow! It hurts! It hurts so much!
Old mister dentist, old mister dentist,
please pull my cavity, pull it right out!
She's gone back to being high again.
It hurts! Ow! It hurts!
Are the only two options "pain" and "high"?!
This terrible cavity is doing this to her.
Maybe we should just remove it.
When she stretches in the morning, it'll pop right out.
That reminds me of something.
There's no way this primitive method is the answer!
I'm with you. It is very primitive.
I thought you might say that,
so I prepared a high-tech machine!
This looks ridiculously overcomplicated!
Is this Pythagoras Switch or what?
D-Does this string lead outside?
The mechanism's gone outside!
At this time, the effect—
Kigurumi Haroukitei here.
Hello everyone!
Last Sunday, I went to visit my granny's grave.
I cleaned it up, placed some flowers,
and promised to concentrate more on my rakugo.
I'm still not very good at it, but I told her I'd try my best.
Only three episodes of Rakugo Girls left!
Here's the eleventh one!
"Family Drama", "Sakai's the Limit",
and "Tree's a Crowd".
I hope you'll be satisfied!