Pumpkin Band
White Pepper
Salami
Sweet Beans
Japan ' s
Best
Trip Invitation Ticket
3 days and 2 nights in Yufuin
Hot Springs Vacation
C
A
N
Consumption tax
Atomic power
New fighter jets
Consumption tax
Atomic power
New fighter jets
Consumption tax
Atomic power
New fighter jets
Consumption tax
Atomic power
New fighter jets
Castro
Angela Merkel
North Korea
Calm
Aware
No talking
Dark Thunder
Thunder
Rakugo Girls
Kabukichou Ichibangai
The Battle of Shinjuku
ANIME CHARACTER
BATTLE ROYALE
Fuushin
Hall
Rakugo Girls
Kukuru Anrakutei
Cavity Beach
Hybrid ceramic crown
All-ceramic crown
Zirconium ceramic crown
Durable but not
overly rigid, making it
kind to adjacent teeth.
Clean, white,
and stain-resistant.
Extremely sturdy and
difficult to break.
Suitable for most teeth.
¥80,000
¥100,000
¥150,000
June 4th
Cavity Prevention Day
Che-brush-ka Dental
Axie Dental
Cohen C. Dental
Indepen Dental
Oxy Dental
Evi Dental
Pru Dental
Prece Dental
Che-brush-ka Dental
Kukuru
Gankyou
Kigurumi
Bouhatei
Kukuru
Gankyou
Kigurumi
Bouhatei
Buratei
Kigurumi
Bouhatei
Gankyou
Chiba
Saitama
Tokyo
Kanagawa
Shizuoka
Bouhatei
Chiba
Saitama
Tokyo
Kanagawa
Shizuoka
Buratei
Colds
Painkillers
Remedication
Dereliction of Duty
|||||||||||||||||||||
Next Time
① Family Drama
② Sakai's the Limit
③ Tree's a Crowd