Happy new year!
Have...
a good...
year...
everybo...
...dy.
The new year really refreshes your spirit.
A new start.
I love things that have "new" in them.
Like a new release, or a new product.
Or new bride, or new recruit!
They're bursting with possibility.
New jackpots and new machines make me
want to go try my luck at pachinko.
Some things have "new" attached
to them pointlessly, though.
Like New Okubo station or New Kawasaki station.
What's new about a newspaper, anyway?
The internet's quicker.
They should be called oldspapers.
New potatoes! New York pizza!
Is that what newtritious means?
The "nu" in "nutritious" has nothing to do with "new".
Oh, okay!
Huh? What's up, Marii?
You know full bloody well what's up!
"Dy"?! Seriously? "Dy"?
D?
Did you see a deer?
No!
Don't worry about being a delinquent.
That again!
I'm gonna defeat you!
I can't deny it!
What about this?
Devotion.
Depravity.
No, no, no, no, NO!
What, then? What's "D"?
Why was my part in our announcement just "dy"?!
Oh right, the announcement.
Oh, is that all?
Whaddya mean, "is that all"?
But you've got to be the end, Marii.
She's right.
The thought of going last makes me tremble...
I'd be so nervous, I could see myself saying,
"Have a good year everybo... doo."
How awful...
Yes indeed.
I'd say something like
"have a good year everybo... dow."
How awful...
The only one who could give that "dy"
the proper treatment is you, Marii.
Yes. It's true.
Really?!
Don't you think "dy" is a bit too short, though?
What do you mean? Longer doesn't always mean better.
I know a certain guy with a short name who works a lot
harder than a certain guy with a longer name.
Ah, that's very convincing.
What about Jugem, with the really long name?
He never did much besides beat other people's children.
Ah! That reminds me, I got something
from Master to give to you.
New year's gifts!
Everyone should pick the one they want.
The "dip" in "lucky dip" is short for
"dip-ressingly small amount of money."
Is that true?
It might as well be. Japanese people love being humble.
Well, it's from Master,
so we shouldn't expect too much, eh?
He said he really splashed out this year, though.
Really?
In that case, I want this one-
Hey, what was that?
You can go last now, as well.
Everyone knows going first is best!
Wanna play rock-paper-scissors to decide?
Winner gets to pick first!
One, two, three!
So Marii picks last.
Gimme another chance!
Let's play a different game, then.
Marii goes 5th.
Marii's the last.
Going last is Marii's destiny.
The late bird misses the worm.
Now that's settled, shall we choose our gift bags?
Hang on a sec!
Choosing last means I'm at a disadvantage, right?
That's not true.
A fat envelope might be stuffed with 1,000-yen bills,
but a slim one could have one 10,000-yen bill.
Good point.
What is it they say? "There's luck in leftovers"?
I'll go last.
Right. I'll start, then.
This thin one... It's gotta be 10,000 yen!
There!
Bzzzt! That's what you get for being greedy and rushing.
Our stingy Master's never going
to give us 10 grand, is he?
Me next!
I don't care about the values, I just want a lot of notes!
What a cutie-pie!
She's still just a kid.
There WERE 10-grand bills!
G-good for you, Kigu.
Heh.
Um... Sure, this one.
I-is this a 2,000-yen bill?!
You can't use these in vending machines...
They don't even have someone's face on them.
This throws a spanner in the works.
They just seem kinda fake!
Literally anything could happen now.
Thin and thick? You guys are so small-minded.
Forget trivial details. Submit to the whims of fate.
Eenie, meanie, miney, mo...
Oh, it's not money.
It's a stock certificate.
And it's for the Central Japan Railway Company!
One share is 600,000 yen!
How can one person be so lucky?!
The last envelope!
Over to you, Marii!
It's COINS?
You left that one on purpose!
Yeah, but coins doesn't mean low value.
There've been commemorative coins
worth hundreds of thousands of yen.
That doesn't sound very likely.
It's probably foreign coins.
Foreign coins?
It's probably 500 won.
How much is that worth?
At the current exchange rate, 1 won is 0.08 yen.
Wow, so it's 4,000 yen?
No, 40 yen.
It's that little?!
Yeah, but you can use 500 won as
a fake 500-yen coin if you want to.
No you can't! That's a crime!
It used to happen a lot.
Hey, it's not limited to won.
There could be any coin in that envelope.
Or alternatively...
it could be a key!
I WIN!
It's gotta be an apartment key!
That's an impressively greedy leap.
As greedy as a Ginza bar owner
during the economic bubble.
How big d'you reckon it is?
6 tatami? 8? Maybe even 10?
I don't think she can measure in anything but tatami.
I think the key is for a dungeon.
Full of hordes of terrifying monsters!
Scary!
Awesome! There's bound to be a bunch
of treasure at the end!
Of course.
A bunch of 500 won coins!
No way it's won!
Well, whatever it is, it's probably not a key. Huh?
A camera?
Oh, should we say something to
the folks viewing via satellite feed?
Marii should go last.
Last again?
The last words are the ones people remember.
R-really?!
Happy new year!
Have...
a good...
year...
everybo...
...dy.
Marii's new year gift is missing!
Marii...
This isn't good. She's closed off her heart.
I do wonder what was in the envelope, though.
I think it was really a key.
The key to Marii's heart.
That didn't wrap anything up!
Won.
My name is
Marii.
I chased an adorable cat,
and ended up lost somehow.
I remember something I heard a long time ago.
A place built from the dreams and
wishes of children who never grew up.
Could this be... Akiha-
It's Jizodori shopping street.
In Sugamo.
Not Akiba? You mean I dressed as a maid for nothing?
Maid outfits aren't the Akiba uniform.
Look, a maid!
A maid? Touching them'll take you to paradise!
They're maid in heaven!
Where's best to touch?
The chest area, for sure.
Right where the heart is!
Stop it!
Praise be! Thank you!
Why are there so many animal-themed clothes?
This one with Mount Fuji looks like
it'd be very good luck indeed!
I bet this T-shirt with Kannon
on it would bring you fortune!
Gonna buy it? Y'can't take it with you
into the next world, you know!
Right?
The keywords here are "good luck",
"fortune", and "the next world".
If we don't blend in, it could turn nasty again.
What should we talk about, then?
What about our health?
My shoulders have been so stiff lately.
My lower back's killing me.
Sometimes I see pink elephants.
Those are hallucinations.
Bland conversations like this make me tired.
Okay, let's take things up a notch.
Shall we eat some grilled lamprey?
Lampreys are kind of scary.
They call them "nine-eyed eels".
They do have a lot of eyes!
Those aren't eyes, they're gills.
Ah! The soy-boiled carp's looking at me!
That reminds me of when my grandma made me
eat soy-boiled locusts to make my teeth strong.
I was made to eat bee larvae.
You guys are minor-league.
I was made to eat rice made from caddisfly larvae.
When you lift the lid of the rice cooker...
black lumps wiggle and jiggle!
Stop it!
No more!
Oh look, Kintaro candy.
Takes me back to being a kid.
It's got the same face running
through it wherever you cut.
What if it had Gankyou's face wherever you cut?
What if it had Kukuru's face wherever you cut?
That doesn't sound like it'd be sweet.
Today's main event,
the shrine of Thornpuller Jizo.
A long time ago, a maidservant swallowed
a needle by mistake,
but she was saved by swallowing an image of Jizo.
They say you can use the water from
here to cure your body's problems.
That's not Thornpuller Jizo.
You're thinking of Washing Kannon.
Oh, really?
A lot of people make that mistake, apparently.
I feel like I got tricked somehow.
We came all the way here, if you wanna wash, wash!
Going to cure your eyes, Gan-chan?
More like her attitude.
Where would you put the water for that?
On the heart, I guess.
Hey! You wash the statue of Kannon,
not the person themselves!
Oh, really?
I daresay it's rounded Gankyou out a bit.
What do you think, Marii-chan?
Marii... chan?!
What's wrong, Gan-chan?
Bespectacled asshat!
Now now, mind your language, Marii-chan!
That's rather dangerous, Marii-chan!
It's a beautiful day today. I'm so happy!
I guess Thornpuller Jizo's blessing really works.
Chest! I'm gonna splash it on my chest!
Butt for me!
She's self-conscious about it after all.
My head!
Heart...
Nothing really changed.
Nope.
Why did it only benefit Gankyou?
Why do you think it did?
You're all so naïve!
That was fun, but I feel like it aged me.
Forget Girl Power,
our Granny Power certainly increased.
Don't worry. Eating turtle makes your skin youthful.
Everyone gets old and wrinkly sooner or later.
You get pains in your shoulders, lower back and knees...
Your eyes get cloudy...
It happens to everyone.
I suddenly got the feeling that whatever will be, will be.
I think that's the feeling of enlightenment.
Or of losing the strength in your shoulders.
This is a pretty mature conversation.
I think having conversations like this is
how you end up being mature.
My eyes are already cloudy...
Your glasses steamed up.
"I bought this cat 'coz you told me
it'd live a thousand years,
but it died yesterday!"
"Oh dear. Yesterday must have been
its thousandth birthday, huh."
Thanks for your continued appreciation.
It's April.
April's here.
What are you talking about? It's already Ma-
Read the room!
Today's April 40th.
What?
Kukuru gets the May Blues in May.
Of course, I can't believe I forgot!
It's April!
They're expecting me to get the May Blues again.
A-pril! A-pril! A-pril!
Kukuru-chan's expression got darker!
It's no longer a case of if, but when!
Is there anything we can do to make her smile?
Hey! Let's have a staring contest!
Daruma, daruma, stare me down
Laughing and smiling isn't allowed.
A-puh-puh!
Wh-what about this?!
That... hurts...
You need to try harder than that!
How's this?!
This is dangerous, she's on the verge of an outbreak!
Isn't there anything else we can try?
Hey, we're rakugo performers.
Aren't we meant to be pros at making people laugh?
That's right! Let's try some rakugo!
Who?
Marii, you go!
The weather's certainly perked up lately, hasn't it?
May is when you can really start to feel summ-
A-pril! A-pril!
I suppose I do have resting depression face.
But it's not like I'm only sad during May.
This sucks.
They really expect me to get the May Blues.
She sighed!
It's started!
Who cares about May Blues?
Ah, she said it.
Mei and Satsuki are both May children!
Satsuki is an old name for May.
That's right! The May Blues must
make you able to see Totoro!
How wonderful!
They say manga artists approaching a deadline
hallucinate mythical beasts too.
White crocodiles.
Green cats.
And the assistant who shouldn't exist.
Yamashita.
Yamashita the mythical beast is so scary!
Nope, I've never seen Totoro or Yamashita.
Anyway, I'm not particularly more depressed
in May than any other time of year.
Not more depressed in May...
You mean you get the June Blues,
July Blues and August Blues too?!
Those are believable.
Y'know, these days.
Even if they're not real, they should be.
At any rate, we can't let you suffer alone!
We should help shoulder the pain!
I've got the June Blues!
We'll all take on a different month.
Oh, I see! I'll go for the November Blues.
February Blues.
December Blues!
Well... we managed to use the power of
female friendship to spread the suffering.
But what do my June Blues involve?
Well, it's rainy season, so...
maybe some kind of groin fungus?
Just what I'd expect from a cross-dressing boy.
Shut up!
You'll have to show your gross lumps to a doctor.
I don't have any kind of lumps!
Since it's June, wouldn't your attitude turn a bit clammy?
A clammy attitude?
Holding onto grudges about things from ages ago.
Like when they hid your school slippers,
or rubbed down the corners of your eraser,
or laughed at your house's screen door,
or wrote the lyrics to that "Alice" song
on the bottom of your chair!
I'll never forgive them!
You can take the June Blues.
So then, since you gave up June,
which month will you take?
Hmm, right. Since I'm a woman of extreme kindness,
I'll take on the heaviest month of the year.
Which one is that?
The September Blues sound pretty rough.
Ah yeah. Summers over, back to school. It's a drag.
There are kids who get it so bad
they can't go to school.
How come?
Shh! Don't ask!
Huh? Then what month am I?
I dunno which month to pick.
None of them really seem that heavy.
Only you enjoy the whole year that much, Marii.
Nothing springs to mind except May, huh.
But it's not like I have the May Blues.
Hm, I wonder?
Energetic people are more susceptible
to the May Blues, you know.
Yeah, you should watch out, Marii.
Don't be silly! I'm fine!
Ya...
Yamashita!
J-just asking...
Yamashita isn't standing over there, is he?
Yeah...
Yamashita...
Isn't there.
I had May Blues all along!
I often saw Yamashita after that.
Tormenting me.
Why don't you just forgive her?
Just a little longer.
She's pretty tenacious.
She's come out of her depression a little at least.
When...
When is May gonna end?!
Marii Buratei here.
We've all got nail clippers, right?
Or nail scissors.
Do you share them with your housemates?
You wouldn't do that with a toothbrush.
What about earwax picks? Bowls? Cups?
Where's the line? What's in and what's out?
Once I start thinking about it, I can't stop!
Anyway, here's the next episode of Joshiraku.
"Life's Butt a Comedy", "The Bear of Ueno"
and "Sleep-Talking".
Long live His Excellency Rozen!