Bag of Gold
Y*Su
Koji K*m*ta
Live long, live long and
prosper. May great wealth
await you wherever you
go, be it on unknown soil
or under foreign skies.
May you always have
your daily bread. Like the
long-lived king of Shuringan
and his dear wife, Gurindai,
and their children, Ponpokoki
New Years' Money
New Year's Money
Tetora
Marii
Kigurumi
Gankyou
Kukuru
Loser
Skip?
New Years' Money
1 Share Certificate
Rakugo Girls
Unsteady
Mongolian
Blue Spot
LAMPREY
Nine-eyed Eel
Carp
Locust
Bee larva
Caddisfly Larva
Kogan Temple
Thornpuller Jizo
The shrine is built around an image of Jizo
Bosatsu (also known as Longevity Jizo).
In accordance with Buddhist tradition,
the image is kept hidden from public view.
Turtle and Ginseng
Mukian
Rakugo Girls
Is It Over Yet?
April
Mon
Very Lucky Day
Kukuru's Ups and Downs by Month
High
Low
DECIDED
June Blues
September Blues
JAN
FEB
Chocolate                      Snowball fights
Cherry blossoms
APR
MAR
School trips
Mountains
JUL
AUG
Ocean
NOV                                      OCT
Baked potatoes                                            Halloween
DEC
Christmas
May
Mon
Very Unlucky Day
|||||||||||||||||||||
Next Time
① Life's Butt a Comedy
② The Bear of Ueno
③ Sleep-Talking