"So, I guess this is goodbye."
"I guess it is."
So, this is the last episode.
It's programming rearrangement season.
A time of partings and new meetings.
We should hold each new meeting dear.
Cherish the fleeting.
Cherish the fleeting?
What does that mean?
Each meeting must be treasured, because once gone,
moments in time can never be reclaimed.
Said to be the words of the tea master, Sen-no-Rikyu.
Coming in!
Good morning!
Wh-Who are you?
Master said I could go on stage today.
Well, when I say stage,
what I actually mean is backstage!
I slay me!
Delighted to meet you all!
Or, as they say in England, "cheers, mate"!
Wow, hottie alert!
You gots a BF?
How annoying.
What is her problem?
God, shut up!
Did you really used to be a pot stirrer?
Stop with the on-air reporter shtick!
Is it true you're divorced?
Do you wear gothic lolita clothes
'cuz you think you look good in them?
I can't even with this jerkwad.
Now, now. It's only for a day.
I'm here to shower you with love and support!
It's the last episode!
We don't need your support!
She's late!
Today of all days?!
I was hoping we could give
the show a nice send-off!
Well, you know what they say.
All's well that ends well.
Hopefully it's just this once,
and we can let it all slide.
Well, okay.
If it's just this once.
That's right! Cherish the fleeting!
Whether you laugh or cry, it's the final episode!
We've gotta cherish this meeting!
Meeting you all today makes me so grateful!
So annoying.
It's just this once! Just for today!
Aren't you even gonna tell us who you are?
Oh! Of course! Where are my manners?!
Let me introduce myself!
Why don't we have a little name quiz?
Who wants to guess? C'mon now!
I swear to god, she's so annoying!
It's only one day!
I don't see any raised hands.
You'll make Ms. Me cry, pupils!
Okay then, let's make it so everyone
can raise their hands!
If you have a good guess,
raise your hand like "paper",
if you kind of think you know,
go with "scissors",
and if you have no idea,
go with "rock". Got that?
What is this, parent's evening at school, Mr. Kinpachi?
She's so damn annoying!
It's just this once...
Bzzzt, time's up!
Just tell us your name already!
It's time for the big reveal!
My name is...
Uzannu Uzattei!
Don't forget it, now!
She's so annoying!
It's just this once...
Ugh, "Voiced by ***ko Shin*** ".
She's so annoying!
It's just this once!
What's everyone else's names, then?
I'm—
Ah, wait, wait, don't tell me!
She's so annoying!
It's just this once.
I don't care what Rikyuu says...
For most moments...
Once is enough!
Forget "cherish the fleeting".
Nine out of ten times,
it's good that the moment is fleeting.
Lining up for hours at an attraction
because you don't know when you'll come again...
Yeah, once is enough.
Waiting outside a pancake place
because you happened to be in the area...
Yeah, once is enough.
That internet friend you've been emailing
for a year who you finally got to meet...
Yeah, once is enough.
Once is enough!
That circus of the sun.
Rockers who sing on and on about the good old days.
The first or second qualifying round
of the World Cup.
Movies about a space probe
that just went there and came back.
American candy.
Hollywood remakes.
Middle-school reunions.
Porn made by former celebrities.
Live action anime movies!
Goddammit! She's so annoying!
It's just one time.
But there are plenty of products
that rely on once being enough!
Products that aren't so much
limited edition as "once only",
where they clearly don't intend
for people to come back.
Products where getting you to pay for it once is enough!
Meeting up once is enough for me!
Used cars.
Restaurants at tourist spots.
Expensive health goods.
Try them even once and
you're playing right into their hands!
Exactly right.
Once is enough.
Did she just change?
All I need is one opportunity
to bring about your downfall.
I just noticed that Marii somehow
ended up on the teasing side.
She's usually the one being teased!
I just realized that her strawberry-patterned kimono
is kinda stealing my niche!
She's kinda stealing my niche!
Ah, stop copying me!
Oops, looks like I've upset the character balance.
Because it's the last episode,
it only takes one rogue element to ruin things
as thoroughly as you-know-who ruined Japan!
Time for stage two of your destruction.
Plastic explosives?!
Stop!
Now you're infringing my character!
Character balance: in shambles!
It's true that there are characters who
ruin the balance just by showing up once.
What do you want?
To send this show into an early grave.
The show was ending today anyway!
Look forward to Annoying Girl, airing next week!
What a bloody cheek!
We won't let you get away with this!
But the balance has been ruined so thoroughly...
I know a solution!
The Exile method.
If you add a whole load of new members, stuff like balance
or individual character goes out the window!
This many members is so annoying!
The annoyer has become the annoyee.
Now that's breaking character!
You'll pay for this!
We won!
Once was definitely enough.
Ma, how was these nice ladies' rakugo?
Um, once was enough.
We got a taste of our own medicine.
Once was enough...
Well, maybe kids just don't get traditional arts.
When she's older, she'll definitely...
Season two will be an annoying live-action adaptation!
You're annoying!
Well? Which way are we going?
I think it's this way.
Huh? We're on the platform again.
I think we went wrong somewhere.
Yep, look.
Left, eh.
Huh? I think we were right before.
Um...
What's going on?
Oh, I know!
Don't they want us to go down those stairs over there?
This is needlessly confusing.
What? The signs for Electric Town disappeared!
Just getting outside was a bit of a mission.
This is the legendary Akihabara Labyrinth.
They say that those who get lost in
its multi-level hell are never seen again.
So that's why you didn't want to come to a place like this.
What do you mean by "a place like this"?
Akihabara is a world-famous tourist hotspot!
We're not just talking appliances, cameras, computers
and high-end audio equipment.
We're talking hobby goods,
idol merch, games, and anime!
Don't underestimate the depth of Akihabara!
You're very enthusiastic, Gan-chan!
Like a fish that found water,
or a fan that found a meet-and-greet ticket.
I wouldn't have expected it. She's a little obsessed, even.
Sounds like we should get Gan-chan to show us around.
Very well.
To the Rajikan!
Magician?
No, the Rajikan!
That's the nickname for the Radio Kaikan!
You could say that the Radio Kaikan
is the beating heart of Akihabara!
The main building is being demolished
and rebuilt, apparently.
You didn't know that, Gankyou?
Well now, this is unexpected. What now, super fan?
There are second and third locations
in addition to this main one...
I think she needs a rest.
She's being arrested!
Just questioned. It's common in Akiba.
If you qualify, they'll stop you every 50 meters.
That's not qualifying, that's failing.
Apparently, you'll definitely be stopped
if you're wearing a fanny pack.
Why?
I guess because you never know
what could be inside them.
Fanny packs contain nothing but hopes and dreams!
They're not suspicious!
Oh, Gan-chan's back.
Thank goodness I didn't have a knife.
Even a box cutter could be bad news these days.
Where does that leave manga artists?
How would they cut panels?
Don't forget anime creators!
How would they cut peg holes?
Do a lot of work in the streets of Akiba, do they?
This is great! I love looking at household appliances.
They have a lot of niche products like electric tempura
machines, egg boilers and waffle makers.
The best-sellers have got to be rice cookers.
Rice cookers?
For some reason, foreign visitors always
seem to buy three or four.
Japan leads the world in rice cooker technology.
The most expensive ones,
that fluff the rice up using a vacuum
or are lined with copper, cost as much as 100,000 yen.
100,000 yen?! Do you really need to spend that much
to cook rice that costs 2000 yen for 2 kilos?
Depending on the shop you might
be able to get them a little cheaper...
So, what store is the king of Akiba?
Apparently Laox is a luxury brand in China.
Luxury brand? It's just a regular shop.
I don't know which one is the top,
but they all have one thing in common.
Once the theme song gets into
your brain, it'll never leave.
Ishimaru! Ishimaru!
Ow! Sato Wireless!
Onoden! La la la!
Laox!
Akiba means Yodobashi Camera!
Let's all go to the bright world!
Turn your heart's switch on!
Look, someone is waiting for you!
Hold on tight to your dreams! Hey!
This old bridge is very calming.
Akiba's a very frenetic kind of place.
One minute you're in, the next you're out.
Even in those theme songs we just sang,
there are songs you don't hear anymore.
Long-standing things like
this bridge are few and far between.
We haven't done anything yet but I'm tired.
It's a strange old town, Akihabara.
An army fights on its stomach. Let's go eat something?
We should eat something that screams "Akiba!"
Like what?
Hotpot in a can?
No, not that...
These new kebab things?
Not quite...
An amateurish omelet and rice cooked by a maid?
There's a place where young women
try their best to make sushi for you.
There's a bar with an N-gauge model
railway running through it.
Or a café where voice actors speak
in lines appropriate to your order.
Or a drag king café.
I'm full now. Full of this nonsense!
Aren't there any normal restaurants?!
Uh-oh, Marii's gone aggro.
Akiba's a lovely place that's kind to visitors.
You're speaking up for it after
being questioned by the police?
This place has a legend.
There once was a young man who
was experiencing his first real crisis.
A herculean mission.
A wall that was insurmountable alone.
Then, help came through the internet
from the residents of Akiba.
You mean that Train Man?
I wonder if they'll ever distribute the royalties
from the book to the forum posters.
I smell an ulterior motive...
This is a pretty fancy place.
I hope we're not under-dressed...
It's fine! It's just a restaurant.
Besides, if we were too fashionable,
it wouldn't feel like Akiba.
Don't worry. They have a space over there where
they hold an event that is 100% pure-grade Akiba.
What kind of event?
Basement Idol.
Hi everyone! Please hate me, but don't hate Akiba!
I've got a song for you. It's called
"Look Forward to Continued Annoyance".
Let's get outta here.
Hey, guys. Do you prefer mochi
simmered in miso or clear soup?
Don't ask such dull questions!
The conversations in this anime
are as inoffensive as possible
so as not to interfere
with your enjoyment of watching cute girls.
Right, that's it. I'm done. I can't eat anymore!
I'm pretty sure we cooked
every kind of mochi imaginable.
I wish we had more actual rice, though.
Check it out!
Huh, rice?! How?
I made it out of mochi!
First, you bake the mochi.
Then you chop it up into tiny, tiny pieces.
Then put it in a rice bowl.
And you're done! Ready to serve!
Woo, rice!
Just eat mochi like a normal person!
Eat it as-is without doing a bunch of weird things to it!
I get it. What you mean, Gan-chan, is...
If you want to read a manga, read a manga.
There's no point making it into an anime!
What's this all of a sudden?
What're you saying?
Why take a perfectly good manga, featuring mostly
conversations that gain nothing from being animated,
where, might I add, we don't even really
ever leave this room, and turn it into an anime?
What's more, enjoy a broadcast as a broadcast!
Why does it need to be turned into a disk?
Taking a perfectly good manga,
featuring conversations that don't need animating,
turning it into an anime, and broadcasting it,
and then selling it as a video is totally unnecessary!
That's what you wanted to say, right?
Stop this! It may be unnecessary, but the hardworking
studio staff are working to a punishing schedule
and going to a lot of trouble
to animate us in incredible detail!
That was a bit much, Gan-chan.
I didn't say that!
Dear God, please make it so Gan-chan is shown
only as rough sketches without any edits.
Hey! Put me back!
Right then, Kigu, I hope that at
your future wedding banquet,
all the dishes are melon with ham.
Starters, mains: ALL HAM MELON.
I just wanna eat melon as melon!
Right?
The bride never gets to eat anyway.
Think about it, Kigu.
Wouldn't you hate it if all the fruit you ever
ate for the rest of your life had ham on it?
I just want to eat bananas and grapes and mandarins
and watermelon without anything extra!
So, you understand what I'm saying.
Yes!
Gan-chan's right!
She's talked you into being a bad person.
At any rate, what I'm trying to say
is don't add unnecessary elements
or inflict bizarre arrangements on things!
It seems like adding extra elements is
a bit of a worldwide fad at the moment.
Adding even a little, and you run the risk of people
yelling "original defiler!" and "new stuff sucks!"
They worked on them,
but were the B parts really necessary?
She says in the last episode!
Anyway, forget ranking extra elements.
I'd say it's more like ranking how unnerving something is.
Take music, for example.
If you come to Japan and sing in Japanese,
it's J-pop, no matter who's singing!
Don't confuse the issue with extra elements!
Don't say that, we can't afford
to have them cancel our sales!
You bespectacled nationalist!
I've found celebs with... extra elements.
There's definitely a little extra.
A little extra on top.
Definitely.
That's more than a little extra, it's a whole pile!
Show your real selves!
That's a little forceful too...
Oh, look, a drama!
They turned this one into a film.
They also made an anime. In Musashi-Sakai.
TV is fine! Why make a movie or an anime?!
It's true that when a drama is turned
into "Such-and-Such: the Movie",
everything gets so big-budget that they lose
what made it special in the first place.
Yeah, like they'll introduce terrorist organizations
and serial killers and whatnot.
I'm not kidding. Give me dramas as dramas!
That's incorrect. A lot of dramas started as manga,
so you should say "give me manga as manga!"
In other words, when it comes to spinoffs,
if the film was originally a drama,
you should watch the drama, and if
the drama was originally a manga, you should—
As long as it's entertaining, who cares?
So what if it's made into an anime, and so
what if they go on to sell that anime in stores?
As long as it's entertaining, who cares?
This feels like too much pressure again.
Who put this dog in clothes?!
Just enjoy a dog as a dog!
Lots of people say that, but even dogs feel the cold.
The number one cause
of doggy deaths in winter is the cold.
Plus, it's a good way to stop them
shedding all over your house.
Nope. I like my dogs naked!
I don't care.
Dogs should be naked! Mutt naked!
Who let you make jokes like that?!
Look, the dog hated being nude after all.
I don't think it cared one way or another;
it just hated the "mutt naked" joke.
I think it's just tough on puns.
Stop!
Gah, dammit!
I feel very supported.
Fanservice in the very last episode?
Anything goes when it's your last episode.
I don't think that's true!
A naked woman... No,
"La Megane"!
"La Megane"? What is that, French?!
Okay, then...
Bespectacled Birthday Suit?
I don't think newborn babies wear glasses.
This won't do, Gan-chan!
Wh-what won't?
Use a washbasin as a washbasin!
Don't rearrange it as a cover for your private parts!
This isn't a rearrangement, it's an emergency situation!
Forgive my intrusion.
That washbasin is made of metal, is it not?
Please donate it.
Why on earth do you need it?
She said it's to make Ospreys.
Use a washbasin as a washbasin! We're not at war!
How are we going to help our brave lads on
the home front if you won't give up a simple washbasin?
I wonder what's going on out there.
It looks like the world's gone to hell.
What did I say to make America mad at us?!
I don't think you angered America.
I don't know about these ladies, though.
We'll take this metal and use it for the greater good!
This is because you tried to use a washbasin as clothes.
The Women's Association weren't monsters.
They left this for you to wear.
My beautiful prince!
We're not worthy to stand in your presence, sir!
So manly and cool!
I'm a woman! Treat women as women!
Don't add any extra elements!
By the way.
What's up, Marii?
I'm the one who's suspected of being
a cross-dressing boy!
She's infringing my character!
Treat a cross-dressing boy as a cross-dressing boy!
Did Marii just come out to us?
I knew it!
It was true!
N-no! It's not about my gender, it's about my character!
Treat Marii as Marii!
Yeah, you're...
not a woman...
not a man...
You're the indefinable Marii.
What's with the soppy tone?
Is this how you're gonna end the last episode?
Miss Marii, you're on next.
Gotcha!
Good luck.
Allow me to take to the stage.
"The world's full of people shoutin' and groanin'
'This is the end! This is the end!'
But the scariest end has gotta
be the end of life, don't ya think?
But then again, that's the only kind of endin'
which comes to everybody, without discrimination.
So I reckon the only thing is to just keep on
laughin' and smilin' right until the very end."