Thank you kindly for your attention
oato ga mata yoroshikute
I hope to have it again and again
osaki mo mae mo yoroshiku ne
Twing-twang twing-twang-twong
chin-ton chin-ton-shan
The theater's full
jounai manjou
Mysteries are fun
nazotoki dokidoki shinan
Tricks are fun as well
shikake ga ariari desu
We can solve girly problems by throwing dice
joshiteki onayami wa sugoroku sai wo futte
(really?)
(hai hai)
It's not one nor six, but nine
ichi de mo roku de mo nain
(really?)
(sou kai)
The stakes are high, but you can get a sign
ichi kake bachi ka de sain
(really?)
(sou kai)
I don't really see how that's related
hanashi no tsunagari ga miemasen ne
See, this looks like it's gonna be fun
oya omoshiroku narisou na yokan wa
(see, see?)
(oya oya desu)
Or am I just seeing things?
me no sakkaku desu ka
I don't even care
iya soredemo kamawanai
Come on, everyone
hai minna
Let's spin!
mawatte
Front and back, let's just turn it around
omote mo ura uragaeshite
You can turn the story upside down too
dondengaeshi mo yoshiyoshi
Let's go on, ladies first
osaki ni ikou saa douzo
I hope to see you around again and again
osaki mo mae mo yoroshiku ne
The backstage is the main stage
ura butai ga hare butai de
That's where we can chat idly
muda uchibanashi mo yokayoka
Thank you kindly for your attention
oato ga mata yoroshikute
I hope it was a good comedy
osaki mo shiroki gokuraku da
A comedy, a comedy
gokuraku da gokuraku da
A comedy from the comedy heaven
arayotto gokuraku joudo ringu
Twing-twang twing-twang-twong
chin-ton chin-ton-shan
"So, it's time to say goodbye?"
"Indeed it is."
Character
Guts
So this is the last episode?
It's time for the new cour.
The season of encounters and goodbyes.
We must treasure each and every encounter.
Each and every one only happens once in a lifetime.
Once in a lifetime?
What do you mean by that?
You might never meet again, so cherish every encounter.
It's attributed to Sen-no-Rikyuu,
who established the tea ceremony.
Excuse me!
Good morning!
Who are you?
The master allowed me to join you for the day!
Only to hang out, though, not to study!
This is so cool!
I'm pleased to make your acquaintances!
Or as the Brits say, "one, please!"
Ah, what a shining beauty!
Do you have a boyfriend?
Annoying.
Who's this girl?
You used to be a real hellraiser, didn't you?
Stop interrogating us!
Is it true that you're divorced?
Do you like to dress up as a goth-loli in your free time?
Someone get rid of her please.
But she's only visiting for today. Just put up with her.
Nope, I'm a new supporting character!
We don't need a new supporting character in the last episode!
You're late!
Don't ruin our last episode!
We wanted to end this nicely.
Come on, all's well that ends well.
This is our last time on screen, so let's just take it easy.
Well, all right.
It's just this once...
Yeah! That's the once-in-a-lifetime spirit!
Laugh or cry, it's the last episode!
Let's treasure this occasion!
Today was the day I finally got to meet you guys!
Thank you!
How annoying!
It's just this once! It's over today!
By the way, shouldn't you at least introduce yourself?!
Ah, that's right! Excuse me!
I'll announce it right away! But first...
It's the "guess my name" quiz!
Who knows? Anyone? Bueller?
She's annoying!
It's just this once!
No hands in the air? You make your teacher sad.
Okay then, everyone raise their hands!
If you know it, paper!
If you aren't sure, then scissors!
If you've got no idea, then rock!
Who knows?
This is no classroom! And you're no Kinpachi!
She's annoying! Seriously annoying!
It's just this once...
Time's up!
Name yourself already!
Let me announce it!
My name is... Iratei Anoingu!
BBBBBBB
Iratei Anoingu
CV: Shin*** ***ko
Nice to meet you!
She's annoying!
It's just this once.
Is her voice actor seriously ***tani Ryou***?!
Iratei Anoingu
CV: Shin*** ***ko
She's annoying!
It's just this once!
By the way, what are your names?
I'm—
Wait, wait! Don't say it just yet!
I'll guess them!
She's annoying!
It's just this once.
Whatever Rikyuu might have said,
in most of the cases,
once is more than enough!
Once in a lifetime
The saying goes that you should treasure every encounter as something that happens once in a lifetime.
But in most cases, once in a lifetime is enough.
Like that ride you waited in line for because you didn't know when it'd be open again...
Once is enough.
Or that pancake you waited in line for because you were in the neighborhood...
And then there's that penpal you finally met after a whole year of exchanges...
Once is enough.
Indeed, once is enough!
Like a certain circus of the sun!
Or rockers who keep singing about simple happiness!
Or the first, second and final round of world cup prelims!
Or movies about a space rocket that keeps returning miraculously!
Or American candies!
Or Hollywood remakes!
Or high school reunions!
Or AVs of former celebrities!
Or second seasons and revivals of anime and movies!
She's annoying! She's too annoying!
It's just this once...
But doesn't this "once is enough" business model work perfectly?!
Think of all of those businesses that don't rely on customer retention!
They're limited time offers...
Or more like one time offers!
Like "Catching them once is enough!"
I've got you now!
million
yen
Like used cars...
Like restaurants at sightseeing spots!
Coffee
Takahara
hamburger
Takahara curry
Like expensive healthcare products!
Green
juice
Soy bar
Black
vinegar
It's not even the buyer, but the seller who thinks so!
Precisely. Once is enough.
What?! She changed!
If I get just one chance, I can mess you all up.
Now that you mention it,
Marii's been bullying her even though she's the one who always gets bullied!
And her strawberry patterned clothes are totally my style!
...are totally my style!
Don't copy me!
See, character balance destroyed.
You let a disrupting element in because "it's just this once,"
just like *** who turned Japan into a complete mess in such a short time!
Proceeding to destruction phase two.
A plastic bomb?
Stop! Now she's copying my style!
Now she's copying my style!
More character balance gone straight to the gutter!
It's true that there are characters who have ruined the balance just by showing up once.
What's your goal?
I'll ruin this show and make it reach its end.
You don't need to! It's ending today anyway!
The anime "Anoingu-chan" starts next week!
Here I am annoying you for attention
oato ga mata uzakute
I hope to annoy you again and again
osaki mo mae mo uzakute
An-noy, an-noy-ing
u-za u-za-nu
The theater's annoying
jounai uzai
Who asked for that?!
You can't have it your way!
But our balance is already ruined! What can we do?
There's a way!
The E**le method!
We'll add so many new characters
that no one will be able to figure out the balance or the characters anymore!
So many new people! This is annoying!
What's that? The annoying character is complaining about something being annoying?
Your character is broken!
I'll remember this!
We win!
Seeing her once is enough.
How was the girls' rakugo?
Once is enough.
She was listening to us.
Once is enough...
Well, you can't expect children to appreciate the traditional arts.
I'm sure that when she grows up... when she grows up...
In the second season, I'll be annoying in 3D!
You're annoying!
So, which way is it?
This way, I think.
Huh? We're back on the platform.
Did we go the wrong way?
Yeah, look!
To the left?
Huh? We were going the right way...
Um...
What's going on here?
I get it!
It must be the other stairs!
That's so confusing...
What?! Now there's no Electric Town exit!
Mighty Akiba
Just getting out was a challenge in itself...
This is the notorious Evil Maze of Akihabara Station.
It's a maze in space, so if you get lost, you can never get out again.
Remember when I said I didn't want to come to a place like this?
"A place like this"?! What do you mean?!
Akiba is a hot-spot for tourists from all around the world!
You can find not only stuff like cameras, computers and high-end audio,
but it's a paradise for hobby, idol, game or anime fans too!
Akiba's a lot more than you'd ever dream of!
Gan's enthusiastic...
She's like a fish back in the water,
or like a fan who got a handshake.
I didn't know she was so much into it.
Now that we're here, let's have Gan guide us around!
Very well!
Then let's begin with the Rajikan!
Ajikan?
No, the Rajikan!
That's the slang name for the Radio Hall!
That's where you can see the true depth of
Deep Akiba!
It's undergoing reconstructions.
Gankyou, you didn't know?
So much for that depth! This's it!
Don't worry, there're two more halls!
It must've been a real shock for her.
She's being questioned!
Yeah, Akiba's famous for that too.
On a good day you might be stopped every 50 meters.
That's a bad day then!
You can be sure to get questioned if you wear a waist pouch.
Why?
You can't tell what's inside.
They're full of hopes and dreams!
There's nothing suspicious!
Ah, Gan's done.
Lucky I didn't have a knife with me...
Nowadays they can take you in even for a cutter knife.
Then what about manga artists?
How would they cut the panels?
And how could animators make peg holes then?
They don't work in Akiba.
This is fun!
I like to walk around just looking at home electronics.
Look at these tempura bowls, boiled egg makers or waffle makers...
Such outlandish things.
I wonder if rice cookers are still the best sellers.
Rice cookers?
For some reason, foreigners buy even 3-4 of them sometimes.
Japanese rice cooking tech is the best in the world.
Some use a vacuum to enrich the rice,
or have a bowl made of copper.
Expensive ones can cost over a hundred thousand.
A hundred thousand? To cook rice that costs a thousand for two kilograms?
I heard some shops are selling them a bit cheaper.
By the way, which shop rules over Akiba?
I heard that LaOX counts as a brand in China.
A brand? It's just a retail store!
I don't know which one's at the top,
but they've got something in common.
Hm?
Their advert songs are so catchy you can't get rid of them.
ikou yo mabushii hikari no sekai
Let's go to the world of shiny lights
haato no suicchi on ni shite
Let's turn on our hearts
goran yo dareka ga kimi wo matteru
Look, someone's waiting for you
onnaji katachi no yume daite
With a dream just like yours
Yay!
Somehow this old bridge calms me down...
This town is very fast in its vicissitudes.
Some of those theme songs earlier aren't played anymore.
There are very few things that last as long as this bridge.
I'm so tired, although we haven't done anything yet.
Akihabara is a fearful town indeed.
They say you shouldn't fight with an empty stomach,
so let's grab something to eat!
Something Akiba-ish would be nice now.
What's Akiba-ish?
Canned veggie broth!
Something different, please...
You can see more and more kebab places too.
I want something else.
That clumsy-looking rice omelette that they serve in maid cafes?
Mongolian
spot
There are those sushi shops where young girls are doing their best.
A bar where an N-gauge is running around the shop.
A cafe where you can order certain lines from voice actors too.
A drag king cafe.
Those are more than I could stomach!
Aren't there any normal places? Like, normal?
Uh-oh, Marii's lost her patience!
Akiba's a nice place and kind to people.
Gan's using police lingo after questioning!
There's a legend in this town.
Once upon a time there was a boy in the first crisis of his life.
His path was blocked by a wall he couldn't overcome alone.
The people who helped him in his distress
were the people of Akiba through the net.
Isn't that the Train Man?
Did they divide the royalties?
That sounds so fishy...
This's such a posh place...
Is it really okay for us to come here?
Sure it is! It's open for everyone!
But it's a bit too posh, so it doesn't feel Akiba-ish at all.
Don't worry.
Down there they're organizing an authentic Akiba event.
An event? What?
Underground idols.
Guys! Even if you hate me, don't hate Akiba!
Now please listen! Annoying you for your attention!
Annoying you for your attention
oato ga mata uzakute
Should we get going?
I hope to annoy you again and-
osaki mo mae mo uzaku-
Extra Lectures
Girls, do you like clear or light brown miso for the New Year's dish?
Don't ask stupid questions!
THIS ANIME IS
This anime is full of ordinary dialogue
A SHOW THAT, FOR THE SAKE OF ENJOYING
HOW CUTE THE GIRLS ARE,
so that viewers can fully enjoy how cute the girls are.
A SHOW THAT, FOR THE SAKE OF ENJOYING
HOW CUTE THE GIRLS ARE,
IS FULL OF UNHINDERING, UNOBSTRUCTIVE DIALOGUE
THAT CAN BE
ENJOYED
I've had enough! I can't eat anymore!
I get that,
but we've already tried all the ways to eat mochi we could think of.
With plain rice we'd have had more options...
That's it!
Huh, plain rice? Where'd this come from?
I made it from mochi.
First you fry the mochi,
then you break it into tiny, tiny pieces and roll them.
Serve it in a rice bowl, and it's done.
Have some!
Yay, it's rice!
Eat mochi as mochi!
Don't pull any cheap tricks, just eat it as it is!
I get it.
What Gan's trying to say is...
You should just read this manga as is.
Why would anyone want to make an anime adaptation?
What's wrong with you?!
Why would you say that?!
This is a dialogue-heavy piece with hardly any action.
Not to mention most of it takes place in a dressing room.
So why would anyone turn a manga like this into an anime?
The same goes for TV broadcasts! Enjoy them as broadcasts!
Why would you burn them onto discs?
Is there really a need to turn this dialogue-heavy piece with hardly any action into an anime,
broadcast it, and then burn it on video discs to sell at a high price?
That's what you wanted to say, isn't it?
Stop that!
The people at the studio are working so hard
to animate way more of us than there is to animate,
all while writing extra jokes for us amidst their horrifying schedules!
Yeah, Gan. You're being too harsh.
I didn't say any of that!
May Gan only be shown as rough sketches without any corrections!
Fix me!
Then imagine, Kigu, how it would feel if on your wedding reception
every plate had melon with a slice of ham and nothing else!
The hors d'oeuvre and the main dish too! Nothing but melon with ham!
I want to have melon as melon!
Right?
But the newlyweds barely eat, right?
Think about it, Kigu!
What if every fruit in your life from now on had a slice of raw ham on it? How would you like that?
I wanna have my bananas, grapes, oranges, and watermelons as they are!
Then you understand what I mean, right?
Yes!
Gan's right!
You've been conned by a wicked adult.
Anyway, my point is: Don't add
unnecessary things or weird twists!
But "adding a little extra" is what's all the rage in the world right now.
But if you add something extra, won't people say "it ruins the original" or "the original's shit"?
Well, we all did our best, but were
all those part Bs really necessary?
Don't bring that up in the last episode!
Anyway, what's with the "Extra Ingredients" ranking?
More like the "Things That Will Terrify You" ranking!
The same goes for music!
If you come to Japan and sing in Japanese,
it doesn't matter who you are! It'll still be J-pop!
Don't add weird extra stuff to it!
Don't say that now! What if they pull us from store shelves?!
Yeah, you nationalist four-eyes!
Hey, look! Extra entertainers!
Yeah, they do add a bit extra! I mean, look at what that guy's wearing!
Yeah, for sure.
This's way beyond "a little extra"!
That's over 9000!
He should perform without it!
You shouldn't force him to...
Look, a drama!
They turned that into a movie, didn't they?
There was an anime too, made in Musashi-Sakai.
Why can't they just air it on TV?
Why does it have to be a movie and an anime?!
Yeah, whenever they make a "The Movie" out of dramas,
they try to stretch the story out into some sweeping epic,
but they kill all the original feel with that.
Yeah, mysterious terrorist organizations and serial killers always show up.
Yeah, show the drama as a drama!
That's not entirely right.
What if the drama is a manga adaptation?
Shouldn't you be saying "read the manga as a manga"?
So if I watch the spin-off and say "watch the movie as a movie,"
but behind that movie it'd be "watch the drama as a drama,"
and behind that drama there's an original manga too...
It doesn't matter as long as you enjoy it.
Even if they make an anime out of it, even if they put that on sale,
it's fine as long as you enjoy it.
Are you trying to put pressure on people again?
Why are you dressing the dog up?!
Keep the dog as a dog!
Many people say that, but you know, even dogs feel cold!
The number one cause of death for dogs in the winter is freezing.
Not to mention that if your dog wears clothes, it won't cover your room in fur.
That's wrong! Dogs are best naked!
I don't care.
I'll make this dog a nakedog!
That's a horrible pun!
No, wait, not that!
See, even the dog doesn't want to undress.
It might've just hated that "nakedog" pun.
Stop, hey, stop!
Stop!
Dammit!
Following in my footsteps, are you?
Ah, some fanservice for the last episode.
You can do whatever you want in the last episode.
No, we can't!
La Nude...
Or rather, La Nude Four-eyes!
Don't say "la nude" like that! It's not French!
Then how about Birthday Suit Foureyes?
I doubt she had glasses on when she was born.
You shouldn't do this, Gan!
Wh-What do you mean?
Washbowls should be used as washbowls!
Don't twist them into hiding your private parts!
I'm not twisting anything! It's an emergency measure!
Excuse us!
That washbowl is made of metal, isn't it?
Hand it over!
What do you want with my washbowl?!
They're using it for Ospreys!
Use washbowls as washbowls! We're not at war!
We can't defend the home front if we reject even washbowls.
I wonder what's going on outside...
Those clouds of depression... There's war a-brewin'.
When did I say anything to anger America?
I don't think we angered America.
I'm not so sure about that other guy, though.
We shall use the metal of this washbowl for the greater good!
That's what you get for trying to wear a washbowl.
But the women's association are no ogres, you know?
They left this here for you to wear.
A true drag king beauty!
I didn't know someone so wonderful was this close to me all the time!
So manly! So cool!
I'm a girl! Treat girls as girls!
Don't add weird extras!
But you know...
What's wrong, Marii?
I thought you suspected me of being a crossdressing boy!
Our characters are overlapping!
Treat crossdressing boys as crossdressing boys!
Marii finally came out of the closet!
Marii, you really...
...were a crossdresser!
That's not it!
The problem isn't our genders, it's our characters!
Treat me as me!
That's right!
Marii's...
neither a girl...
nor a boy.
She's a being called Marii.
What are you so satisfied with?!
Do you really want to end the show like this?
Miss Marii, it's your turn.
Okay!
Good luck!
Marii
Harii
Please allow me to take the stage before you.
Marii
Harii
The world is abuzz with news of the show reaching the end of its run,
but there's an even scarier end that await us: the end of our lives.
Everything without exception has an end,
so I think it'd be best to laugh happily until it's time to close the—
Harii
A
Live long, live long and prosper
jugemu jugemu gokou no surikire
A
May great wealth await you wherever you go
kaijari suigyo no suigyou matsu
A
Even in different lands and under different skies
unrai matsu fuurai matsu
A
May you always have your daily bread
kuuneru tokoro ni sumu tokoro
A
And always be brimming full of life
yaburakouji no burakouji
A
Like the long-lived king Shuringan
paipo paipo paipo no shuuringan
A
And his dear wife Gurindai
shuuringan no guurindai
A
And their children Ponpokopi and Ponpokona
guurindai no ponpokopi no ponpokona no
A
Live a long and blessed life
choukyuumei chousuke
A
Let me have a bit of your time
choi to jikan itadakimasu
Please listen closely
goseichou kudasai
A
We're ready
totonoimashita
A
You write it "laughing"
warau koto to kakemashite
A
You read it "let's party"
omatsuri yarou zo tokemasu
A
And the point of it is, the point of it is...
sono kokoro wa sono kokoro wa
A
That everyone will be happy!
dochira mo happi ni naru deshou
A
Thank you kindly for your attention
oato ga yoroshii you de
Laugh, laugh, hey, let's laugh
waraou waraou sa waraimashou
Life may be hard, but let's laugh
konna jidai koso waraimashou
Laugh (yeah yeah)
waraou (soiya soiya)
If you cry, you lose
naitara make da
So just laugh until your sides ache
yakekuso waraimashou
Life may have its ups and downs,
haranbanjou sui mo amai mo
But great Japanese can get over it
norikoeta appare nipponjin
Laugh, whatever time may bring
waraou donna toki de mo
Laugh until you run out of breath
nanikuso waraimashou
Who cares where you are? Just laugh
kuuki nante yomazu ni warattoke
Smile (smile), smile (smile)
egao (egao) egao (egao)
Smile and the world will smile back at you
warau kado ni wa fuku kitaru
The End