Thank you kindly for your attention
oato ga mata yoroshikute
I hope to have it again and again
osaki mo mae mo yoroshiku ne
Twing-twang twing-twang-twong
chin-ton chin-ton-shan
The theater's full
jounai manjou
Mysteries are fun
nazotoki dokidoki shinan
Tricks are fun as well
shikake ga ariari desu
We can solve girly problems by throwing a dice
joshiteki onayami wa sugoroku sai wo futte
(really?)
(hai hai)
It's not one nor six, but nine
ichi de mo roku de mo nain
(really?)
(sou kai)
The stakes are high, but you can get a sign
ichi kake bachi ka de sain
(really?)
(sou kai)
I don't really see how that's related
hanashi no tsunagari ga miemasen ne
See, this looks like it's gonna be fun
oya omoshiroku narisou na yokan wa
(see, see?)
(oya oya desu)
Or am I just seeing things?
me no sakkaku desu ka
I don't even care
iya soredemo kamawanai
Come on, everyone
hai minna
Let's spin!
mawatte
Front and back, let's just turn it around
omote mo ura uragaeshite
You can turn the story upside down too
dondengaeshi mo yoshiyoshi
Let's go on, ladies first
osaki ni ikou saa douzo
I hope to see you around again and again
osaki mo mae mo yoroshiku ne
The backstage is the main stage
ura butai ga hare butai de
That's where we can chat idly
muda uchibanashi mo yokayoka
Thank you kindly for your attention
oato ga mata yoroshikute
I hope it was a good comedy
osaki mo shiroki gokuraku da
A comedy, a comedy
gokuraku da gokuraku da
A comedy from the comedy heaven
arayotto gokuraku joudo ringu
Twing-twang twing-twang-twong
chin-ton chin-ton-shan
"Where did you get this pike from?"
"From the Nihonbashi riverside fish market, my lord."
Then the lord sa--
"Meguro's pike is really the best.
Thank you... kindly... for your attention...
Ruined
What's wrong, Marii?
They started clapping before I even finished!
They clapped before the punchline!
That should come after the punchline!
Doesn't that mean you're so bad they just wanna get rid of you?
What?!
There are all kinds of guests. Some might not know when to clap.
Did something like that ever happen to you?
Just the other day...
"Live long, live long and prosper. May great wealth await for you..."
"...for you wherever you go, even different lands and skies.
May you always have..."
"have your daily bread and always be brimming full of life.
Like the long-lived king Shuringan and his dear wife Gurindai, and their children..."
Clap when I'm done for Christ's sake!
The other guests felt like they had to clap too!
They missed the most important part of the whole story!
It's the perfect way to mess up a joke!
That's almost like some kind of terrorist attack.
How terrible...
People who do that should just drop dead!
But then you'd end up dead too!
Just the other day, I gave Marii my spare ticket to a classical concert.
But the piece wasn't even over yet! It was so embarrassing!
The main theme comes after those few seconds of silence! She ruined it!
It's not like Marii did it intentionally though. I think you can excuse her.
For example, it's not obvious when to clap while listening to Tchaikovsky.
There are people out there who mislead laughter and feelings.
I learned that the hard way too.
Just the other day, I gave Marii my spare ticket to a baseball game.
She tried to start the wave at the wrong time!
That can get everyone fired up if you do it at the right time! She ruined it!
It's not like Marii did it intentionally though.
Not like that makes it any better.
But there aren't many chances when they can't score points.
For example, it's hard to find the right time to do the wave at a Kyunichi Drag-ons match.
Mind if I butt in?
You're the district organizer.
Just the other day, Marii helped out at the festival.
Then, when it was over...
Thanks for your help today!
Let's close it with a clap!
Ready!
You were way too early!
I was still saying "ready"! You ruined it!
Really?
Mind if I butt in?
It's a neighborhood manga artist.
There was this time...
His hakama's... striped!
You laughed at the wrong part!
That part isn't even funny!
And then at the part where you should have laughed...
His hakama's... striped!
Why are you laughing at that?!
What's funny about his pants?!
Don't laugh when it isn't even funny!
In your case, I'd be happy anyone found it funny at all.
Well, I guess that's one way to look at it.
Oh come on, shut up already.
Who cares if my timing's off a bit?
If only it was just a bit. But what you're doing is like...
Heaven and earth are calling me!
I come to defeat evil, for I am--
It's like attacking the hero during his transformation scene!
I-Is it that bad?!
Yes. That's what it means to mess up the timing.
I'll train Marii to know the right timing and mend her rhythm!
Mend
her
rhythm
Mend
her
rhythm
Pounding time!
It'll hurt a lot if you miss the timing!
I can't even watch this!
Does it have to be so dangerous?
Couldn't you use some cuter method like they do with kids?
We could make her "catch" the rhythm if we were a band or something.
To make Marii mend her rhythm, we must be ready to face even death itself!
Oh how serious and hard the way of the rhythm is!
Here we go!
Don't move your hand when it's safe!
It's not like I'm doing it intentionally...
It's weird that her timing is so off in every way.
There must be a reason for it.
Well, she's also tone deaf.
What if she has no sense of rhythm in the first place?
Metronome!
Improve your sense of rhythm with this!
I see!
She fell into hypnosis before she could improve her rhythm!
Then what if...
Ready!
Perfect timing!
It's not what we were going for, but it worked!
What about manga? Can she read it like a normal person now?
She isn't laughing at random stuff anymore!
Hell, she isn't laughing at all!
That's normal.
Okay, let's pound mochi!
Come on, Marii!
Her timing's perfect!
But what will happen when we wake her up?
Are you okay, Marii?
Thanks to my hospital visit, I know why my timing is always so off!
I noticed that my EKG was totally messed up!
I'm so relieved to know that my timing is messed up because of my heart!
Ah, that's grea--
Wait, Marii, that's arrhythmia!
Luckily, they said it's not that serious and it's stable for now.
We were so worried about you, Marii!
His hakama's... striped!
It's not her arrhythmia, is it?
So this is Jinbocho!
I'm getting vibes of business success!
It's also called the town of students and books.
Grande
There are many publishers, bookstores and universities around here.
Haga Bookstore
Senshu University
I wanna walk around checking out antique bookstores!
That sounds good!
Hold your horses!
One can't fight on an empty stomach!
There are many good restaurants around here.
Tendon, western cuisine, curry...
Also, because publishers work late, the Chinese restaurants stay open late as well.
Having lunch sounds good, but shouldn't we drop in to say hi first?
Say hi to whom?
The publisher that takes care of us.
Got'cha!
That's a showdown.
Three Bookstores
Um, I think it's that way!
Found it!
Hang in there!
Wait, we're wrong here!
Shogakukan Bld.
This's Shogakukan!
Oh, you're right!
Our publisher's Kodansha!
How could you mess that up?
When I looked up that manga artist from the neighborhood, it said his debut was in Sunday!
We should hurry over to Kodansha.
Hold your horses!
Let's not ignore Shogakukan!
Their elementary school textbooks and magazines contribute greatly to the intellectual growth of children!
They teach us everything important in life!
Friendship! Determination! Victory!
Shogakukan teaches and leads children! And that's not all!
You're going overboard with the praise.
Not to mention friendship, determination and victory are Jump.
The Sunday magazine would embody love, youth and Conan, wouldn't it?
Shueisha is that way!
So this is Shueisha!
The building smells of money.
Some people just call it the One Piece building.
Is there a Dragon Ball building and a Seiya building too?
What about the Hunter building?
Is there a Hunter building?
There were holdups, so construction work is probably ongoing.
This business deals in culture! Yeah!
The goal is to publish things that contribute to society!
"Publishing is planting seeds that will bear great fruits in life!"
That's what someone said at Shueisha, which belongs to the Hitotsubashi Group!
Hitotsubashi?
A group of publishing companies led by Shogakukan, including Shueisha, Hakusensha, Shodensha, and so on.
Yeah, that's the Hitotsubashi Group, but weren't we going to Kodansha?
Tokyo, Bunkyo, Otowa 2-12-21
For telephone numbers, please
refer to the table of contents.
That's right.
Let's go!
It's quite unimpressive when compared to Jinbocho.
There aren't any shops, either...
But there's a famous temple!
The Gokoku temple which this station is named after!
And here it is.
They say Tokugawa Tsunayoshi built it because his mother told him so.
Oh, he had an Oedipus complex?
He was a furry too.
He's famous for his Edicts on Compassion for Living Things.
It sure is an impressive, old building, but it's not really one for the 21st century generation.
That's not true!
The funeral of that guy who stole a bike was held here too!
A legendary number of people were attending!
Also this is the final resting place of the number one Karate Maniac, President Oyama Masutatsu,
and of the great Kajiwara Ikki as well!
Mr. Kajiwara basically built a few of the Kodansha buildings!
Let's go to Kodansha!
Kodansha. Formed as the Imperial Japanese Oratorical Society.
They published the Kodan Club entertainment magazine.
Later it was renamed the Imperial Japanese Oratorical Society Kodansha.
Thus is born the name of the company.
That's so long!
So long and so many strokes on the characters!
Great Japan
Oratorical Society
Kodansha
Great Japan
Oratorical Society
Kodansha
Were they misfits or what?!
Makes sense! So that's why Kodansha's misfit mangas are so successful!
They empathized.
It's really worth checking out the paintings of the former company presidents in the great hall.
They're all called Noma.
I've got this faint sense of deja-vu...
What do you mean?
I may be wrong, but it feels like not very long ago we had some event here.
Something about five voice actresses in a talk-show and signing posters...
I remember!
They were attending the funeral of Rikiishi Toru!
Rikiishi? Who's that?
The greatest rival of Tomorrow's Joe!
The funeral was led by Terayama Shuji!
He's the one who sees a foggy ocean the moment he strikes a match!
In more modern terms, the kind of person who'd mourn Mami or Fire Fist Ace?
By the way, how old were you again, Kigu?
Not old enough to get wrinkles! Tee-hee!
I wonder if Mr. Noma's on the top floor now, sipping wine with a cat on his lap?
I can hear him saying "In the spring rain, the scent of Venus's sigh reaches me."
Mr. Kibayashi would do that, not him.
Surprisingly, the president's office is on a lower level, they say.
Huh? Why?
Supposedly its shorter to the fire escape from there.
There's no escape in the magazine's editorial section, by the way.
Hey!
Good afternoon!
Hello.
What's this? Is this some kind of hotel?
There's a café upstairs.
Are they models?
They publish ViVi, and other fashion magazines as well.
That's so classy.
God damn! The building smells of money and it's full of pretty models!
I'm so damn envious!
I hope our editors at Betsu-Maga have some nice offices too!
What the hell's this place?
It's dirty, dangerous and demeaning! The real 3D!
Anoingu
The light and fun Bessatsu Shonen Magazine is built on the daily sacrifice of the editors!
Thank you kindly.
Kumagorou the bear kept walking and walking, but he just couldn't find the place.
"Did I lose my way? I must still be groggy from my long winter sleep."
Then suddenly it came to him in a flash of realization.
"Oh, my! That wasn't winter sleep, it was cold sleep!"
Thank you kindly for your attention.
Surprise Focus
What? The animator ran away?
He wouldn't open his door when you knocked?
Don't give me that!
He just locked himself in!
Break the door down and get in there!
But people say he has a habit of running away from his stress!
Who gives a damn?!
All that matters is that we meet the deadlines!
What's Kigu doing?
She said she's learning a new story.
You shouldn't focus too hard. It's bad for your body.
Don't strain yourself.
I'm training seriously, unlike the rest of you!
Gotta focus!
You're focusing a bit too much...
She focused too much!
Her facial features got all focused together in the middle!
What? How could this be?!
Whoever heard of someone's face getting focused together?!
I see!
So that's how Acchan ended up like that! She focused too much!
One-two! One-two!
Otherwise, she wouldn't have been able to get the center position!
You need that kind of focus to win the election and graduate!
Otherwise Den-O won't take you home!
If you focus that much, Kigu,
your graduation ceremony might exceed the 916 multiplier!
I don't want to graduate or focus or study in New York!
I drew you a shoebill to help lower your focus!
You can't break my focus with something like that!
But it's the coolest bird ever...
Would you prefer one in profile?
But it's famous for catching fish by surprise, so I'll just end up focusing on when it moves!
Try massaging your face to loosen up.
Okay.
Am I still focused?
Your face is back to normal,
but because of all the focusing you did, now you've got focus lines surrounding you.
They won't disappear!
I don't wanna be focused on, but because of the focus lines, everyone focuses on me!
Kigu, let's have a coffee break and relax.
I got some chocolate as a present the other day.
It's so sweet!
This is so calming!
It's not getting any better.
I'm totally relaxed!
It doesn't look like that at all.
The focus lines just won't disappear.
Now it's like a manga by Mr. Shimamoto.
Ah, that style that makes even the most insignificant lines dramatic.
Should we just call ourselves the Rakugo Performers of Fire?
We could be members of a high school or university rakugo club,
working as hard as we can to fulfill our dreams.
Let's not. We're not fiery enough for that.
But this way we'll have to put up with the focus lines no matter what we say!
Even in love...
You know, I think...
I love you!
I don't want to be in a suffocating love story like that!
That was the first time the focus lines really matched the tension!
I'm not happy about that at all!
There's no need to be angry...
I'm not angry! It just looks that way!
And it wouldn't just affect your love.
It'd happen when you read poems,
or cleaned your ears,
or took a bath,
or died...
I don't want such a suffocating life!
It reminds me of Dezaki's work, so I quite like it.
Do you mean stuff like this?!
And this?!
And even this?!
Just give up.
Kigu, you'll never have a background like the one I'm about to show you.
I love you!
That's so unfair!
I want a background like that too!
Is that envy I hear?
That pink, fluffy style doesn't suit you at all, though.
The hell'd you just say?!
I said it doesn't suit you.
I'll kick your ass!
Could it be that Marii can't get rid of hers either?
That's not funny!
Yep, it's still there.
Marii, you might have to live your whole life in that pink, fluffy atmosphere!
What?!
Even if you get beaten up,
or run over by a car,
or something falls and hits you in the head,
or when you die.
That's beyond a joke!
Why would anything fall on my head in the first place?!
Well, I don't think you'd have too much trouble living a pink, fluffy life like that.
The real problem here is Kigu.
Yeah!
Hey! I've got problems too!
You look perfectly at peace to me.
Anyway, the moral of the story is that too much focus is never good.
It's very risky how industries focus themselves in Tokyo or how companies focus on trading
Bid
results
Construction company
Bid
Ishida Constr.
Tanaka Constr.
Hirata Co. Ltd.
Haneishi Assoc.
with only a limited set of partners.
Manga artists shouldn't enter into exclusive contracts either.
So many artists have been ruined by those unreasonable conditions!
When blame is focused on one person, he becomes a scapegoat.
When power is focused in the hands of one person, he becomes a dictator.
When unrequited love is focused too much on one person, that's the birth of a stalker.
Love Love Love Love Love Love
When sales focus too much on one show, it leads to the decline of the industry.
So, Marii, do you understand now how focus can be a problem?
Y-Yeah.
For instance, in prefab bathrooms where the tub and the toilet are focused in one room,
you can't take a leak while someone's using the bath.
And you can't wash yourself off before getting in the tub because the toilet will get wet too.
Yeah, I guess,
though that's a pretty boring, everyday example.
Isn't that great, Marii?
Anyway, the point is that instead of focusing, we need to scatter!
We need you, Marii, since you're so scatterbrained anyway!
Flattery will get you nowhere, you know!
I don't think that was flattery.
Oh, right! We should have separate dressing rooms too!
If we're all in the same room and some rioter breaks in, we're done for!
I'll ask the manager to give us separate rooms!
He said, "Who'd'ya think you are? Shinsuke?!"
Figures.
We've got no choice but to split up this room, then.
This is so boring! I can't take it anymore!
Shut up. This is all for Kigu's sake.
Kigu, are you okay?
It must be rough being in such a cramped space, right?
It's okay!
This cramped space lets me focus like never before!
You mustn't focus!
You have to scatter your thoughts! Unwind!
Yeah! I'm focusing on unwinding!
You mustn't focus on it so intensely!
This has gone beyond the point where we can help her.
Focused Treatment
It all worked out, Kigu.
You're lucky they had focused treatment!
You're much less focused now.
So, can you cure me too?
Sadly, that's beyond the reach of today's medical technology...
Oh, come on! Just cure me!
Marii and the doctor sure do get along well...
I'm terribly sorry, but I can't.
Don't give me that shit!
Yup.
Cure me, you goddamn quack!
A
Live long, live long and prosper
jugemu jugemu gokou no surikire
A
May great wealth await you wherever you go
kaijari suigyo no suigyou matsu
A
Even in different lands and under different skies
unrai matsu fuurai matsu
A
May you always have your daily bread
kuuneru tokoro ni sumu tokoro
A
And always be brimming full of life
yaburakouji no burakouji
A
Like the long-lived king Shuringan
paipo paipo paipo no shuuringan
A
And his dear wife Gurindai
shuuringan no guurindai
A
And their children Ponpokopi and Ponpokona
guurindai no ponpokopi no ponpokona no
A
Live a long and blessed life
choukyuumei chousuke
A
Let me have a bit of your time
choi to jikan itadakimasu
Please listen closely
goseichou kudasai
A
We're ready
totonoimashita
A
You write it "laughing"
warau koto to kakemashite
A
You read it "let's party"
omatsuri yarou zo tokemasu
A
And the point of it is, the point of it is...
sono kokoro wa sono kokoro wa
A
That everyone will be happy!
dochira mo happi ni naru deshou
A
Thank you kindly for your attention
oato ga yoroshii you de
Laugh, laugh, hey, let's laugh
waraou waraou sa waraimashou
Life may be hard, but let's laugh
konna jidai koso waraimashou
Laugh (yeah yeah)
waraou (soiya soiya)
If you cry, you lose
naitara make da
So just laugh until your sides ache
yakekuso waraimashou
Life may have its ups and downs,
haranbanjou sui mo amai mo
But great Japanese can get over it
norikoeta appare nipponjin
Laugh, whatever time may bring
waraou donna toki de mo
Laugh until you run out of breath
nanikuso waraimashou
Who cares where you are? Just laugh
kuuki nante yomazu ni warattoke
Smile (smile), smile (smile)
egao (egao) egao (egao)
Smile and the world will smile back at you
warau kado ni wa fuku kitaru