"Where in the heavens did you procure this pike from?"
"From the Nihonbashi riverside fish market, My Lord!"
And to that, the lord replied w—
"Nothing can beat Meguro's pikes!"
Thank you for your continued appreciation....
What's wrong, Marii?
They started clapping before I could even finish!
I didn't even get to the punchline yet!
The applause is supposed to come after!
Sounds to me like they wanted you out already.
Why?!
There are all kinds of audiences.
Some may simply not know when to clap.
Have you ever had any?
Just the other day.
"Live long, live long and prosper.
May great wealth await you..."
"...wherever you go, be it on unknown soil
or under foreign skies."
"May you always have..."
"...have your daily bread and
always be brimming full of life."
"Like the long-lived king, Shuringan,
and his dear wife Gurindai, and their children..."
Clap when I'm done, for Christ's sake!
The rest of the audience
succumbed to peer pressure!
I just finished all the build-up, too!
It was the perfect way to ruin the joke!
Literally a coup! Yikes.
There's a special place in Hell for those people!
Then you'll be going straight there with them, Marii!
Just the other day, I gave Marii my spare ticket
to come see a classical concert with me!
Bravo!
But the piece wasn't even over yet!
I was so embarrassed!
Woohoo! That was kick-ass!
The main theme comes after
those few seconds of silence!
She ruined it!
It's not like she knew any better,
so it's not really fair to hold it against her.
You get this with composers like Tchaikovsky as well.
Some people have no idea
when they're supposed to cheer.
I learned that the hard way.
Just the other day, I gave Marii my spare ticket
to come see a baseball game with me.
She tried to start a wave at the completely wrong time!
Timing it just right can fire up
an entire stadium! She ruined it!
It's not like she knew any better, though.
As if that made it any bloody better!
But it's easy to miss your chance
if your team rarely scores.
Take for example Kyunichi Drag-on matches.
It's hard to prepare for the right time.
Mind if I butt in?
You're the district organiser.
Just the other day, Marii helped us out
at the festival, she did.
Then, when we got together after...
Thanks y'all for helpin' out!
Now, a round o' applause if I may!
Ready—
Your timing was awful!
I only got two syllables in! You ruined it!
Really?
Mind if I butt in?
It's a neighbourhood manga artist.
There was this time...
He's got... He's got a striped hakama!
You laughed before you hit the punchline!
What's so funny about that?!
And then once you did reach the punchline...
He's got... He's got a striped hakama!
What's so funny about his trousers?!
Laugh at something that's funny!
In your case, I'd be happy anyone found it funny at all.
Well, I guess that's one way to look at it.
Oh, come on. Get off my ass.
Who gives a damn if my timing's a tiny bit off?
If only it was just a bit.
But what you're doing is akin to...
Heaven and earth are calling me!
I come to defeat evil, for I am—
It's akin to attacking the hero
during his transformation scene!
I-Is it that bad?!
Yes, that's what happens when your timing is awful.
I'll drill the right timing into her
and mend her rhythm!
Pounding time!
You'll be in a world of pain if your timing's off!
Gotcha!
I can't stand to watch!
Does it have to be so dangerous?
Couldn't you use a safer method
like they do with kids?
Like trying to sing along to Fluffy Time,
that one light music club song!
No! If we want to mend her rhythm,
she must be willing to face Death itself!
Oh, how treacherous the road to true rhythm is.
Ready or not, here I come!
Don't wait until after it's safe!
It's not like I'm doing it intentionally...
It's weird that her timing is so off
in every which way.
There must be a cause behind it.
Well, she's also tone deaf.
What if she has no sense of rhythm in the first place?
Metronome!
Improve your sense of rhythm with this!
Sure thing!
The consistent rhythm made her
fall into a state of hypnosis!
Then what if...
Ready!
Perfect timing!
It's not what we were going for,
but it worked!
What about manga?
Can she read it like a normal person now?
She isn't laughing at random stuff anymore!
Heck, she isn't laughing at all!
That's normal.
Okay, let's try this again!
Come on, Marii!
Her timing's perfect!
But what will happen when we wake her up?
Are you okay, Marii?
While at the hospital,
I learned why my timing's always off!
I noticed that my EKG was totally messed up!
I'm so relieved it's just 'cuz
my heart rate's all messed up!
Ah, that's grea—
Wait, Marii, that's arrhythmia!
They said it wasn't serious and it has stabilised now.
You had us worried sick, Marii!
He's got... He's got a striped hakama!
It's not her arrhythmia, is it?
So this is Jinbocho!
You can feel the business success in the air!
It's also called the town of students and books.
There are many publishers, bookshops,
and universities around here.
I wanna check out the antique bookshops!
Sounds good to me!
Hold your horses!
An army marches on its stomach!
There's a lot of good restaurants around here.
Tendon, western cuisine, curry...
Also, because publishers work late,
Chinese restaurants stay open late as well.
Having lunch sounds good,
but shouldn't we drop in to say hi first?
Say hi to whom?
The publisher that takes care of us.
Let's gettem, G!
For a simple visit, not a showdown.
Um, I think it's that way!
Found it!
Thank you so much!
Thank you.
Thanks for everything!
Ey, thanks bro!
Keep it up, fella!
Wait, wrong place! This is Shogakukan!
Oh, you're right!
Our publisher's Kodansha!
How could you mess that up?
When I looked up that manga artist from
the neighbourhood, it said his debut was in Sunday!
We should hurry over to Kodansha.
Hold your horses!
Let's not do Shogakukan dirty now!
Their elementary school textbooks and magazines
contribute greatly to the intellectual growth of children!
They teach us everything important in life!
Friendship! Determination! Victory!
Shogakukan teaches and leads children! And that's not all!
Cool it with the over-praising.
Not to mention friendship, determination,
and victory are all very Jump.
The Sunday magazine would embody love,
youth, and Conan, wouldn't it?
Shueisha is that way!
So this is Shueisha!
The building smells of money.
Some people just call it the One Piece building.
Is there a Dragon Ball building and a Seiya building too?
What about the Hunter×Building?
Is there a Hunter×Building?
There were hold-ups,
so construction work is probably ongoing.
This business deals in culture! Yeah!
The goal is to publish things that contribute to society!
"It is the task of publications to sow seeds
that bear fruit in our lives and bloom as flowers."
That's what someone said at Shueisha,
which belongs to the Hitotsubashi Group!
Hitotsubashi?
A group of publishing companies led by Shogakukan,
including Shueisha, Hakusensha, Shodensha, you name it.
Yeah, that's the Hitotsubashi Group,
but weren't we going to Kodansha?
That's right.
Let's go!
Leaves a lot to be desired when compared to Jinbocho.
There aren't any shops, either...
But there's a famous temple!
The Gokoku temple which this station is named after!
And here it is.
They say Tokugawa Tsunayoshi built it
because his mother told him so.
Oh, he had an Oedipus complex?
And he was a furry, too.
He's famous for his Edicts on
Compassion for Living Things.
It sure is an impressive, old building,
but it doesn't really mesh well with Gen Z.
That's not true!
They held the funeral of that guy
who stole a bike here, too!
A legendary number of people attended!
Also this is the final resting place of the number one
Karate Maniac, President Oyama Masutatsu,
and the great Kajiwara Ikki rests here as well!
Kajiwara practically built a few
of the Kodansha buildings himself!
Let's go to Kodansha!
Kodansha. Formed as the
Imperial Japanese Oratorical Society.
They published the Kodan Club entertainment magazine.
They then renamed it to the
Imperial Japanese Oratorical Society Kodansha.
Thus is born the name of the company.
Way too freakin' long!
And why use so many kanji with so many damn strokes?
Were they a buncha delinquents or what?!
Makes sense! That's why Kodansha's
delinquent manga are so successful!
They empathised.
It's really worth checking out the paintings
of the former company presidents in the great hall.
They're all called Noma.
I'm getting a faint sense of déjà vu...
What do you mean?
I may be wrong, but it feels like we had
some kind of event here not long ago.
Something, something, five voice actresses,
some kinda talk show, posters being signed...
I remember!
They were attending the funeral of Rikiishi Toru!
Rikiishi who?
The greatest rival of Tomorrow's Joe!
The funeral was led by Terayama Shuji!
He's the one who sees a foggy ocean
the moment he strikes a match!
In more modern terms, the kind of person
who'd mourn Mami or Fire Fist Ace?
By the way, how old were you again, Kigu?
Too young to get wrinkles! Tee-hee!
I wonder if Noma's on the top floor now,
sipping wine with a cat on his lap?
I can hear him saying "In the spring rain,
the scent of Venus's sigh reaches me."
That's Kibayashi you're thinking of.
Surprisingly, the president's office
is apparently on the lower level.
Huh? Why?
It's supposedly much closer to the fire exit.
There's no escape in the magazine's
editorial section, by the way.
Waddup!
Good afternoon!
Good day.
Hello.
This really the right place?
We didn't walk into some hotel, did we?
There's a café upstairs.
Are they models?
They publish ViVi, and other fashion magazines as well.
That's so classy.
God damn! The building smells of money
and it's full of pretty models!
God, I wish that were me!
I hope our editors at Betsu-Maga
have some nice offices too!
What pigsty did we waltz into?
It's dirty, dangerous, and demeaning! The real 3D!
The light and fun Bessatsu Shonen Magazine
is built on the daily sacrifice of the editors!
Thank you kindly.
Teddiursa the bear kept walking and walking,
but he just couldn't find the place.
"Did I lose my way? I must still
be groggy from my winter sleep."
And then suddenly, the realisation hit him.
"Oh, dear! That wasn't my winter sleep,
I was just sleeping off a cold!"
Thank you for your continued appreciation.
What? The animator ran off?
He wouldn't open his door when you knocked?
Don't give me that!
He just locked himself in!
Break the door down and get in there!
But people say he has a habit of
running away from his stress!
Who gives a damn?!
All that matters is that we meet the deadlines!
But I think what he needs is rest!
What's Kigu doing?
Rest won't pay the bills!
She said she's learning a new story.
You shouldn't focus too hard.
It's bad for your body.
Don't stress yourself out.
I'm training seriously, unlike the rest of you!
Gotta focus!
You're focusing a bit too much...
She focused too much!
Her facial features got all
focused together in the centre!
What? How could this be?!
Whoever heard of someone's face
getting focused together?!
I see!
So that's how Atsuko ended up like that!
She focused too much!
One-two! One-two!
That must've been how she got to centre position!
You need that kind of focus to win
the election and graduate!
Otherwise Den-O won't take you home!
If you focus that much, Kigu,
your graduation ceremony
might exceed the 916 multiplier!
I don't want to graduate or focus
or study in New York!
I drew you a shoebill to help lower your focus!
You can't break my focus with something like that!
But it's the coolest bird ever...
Would you prefer one in profile?
But it's famous for catching fish by surprise,
so I'll just end up focusing on when it moves!
Try massaging your face to loosen up.
Okay.
Am I still focused?
Your face is back to normal,
but because of all the focusing you did,
you've now got focus lines surrounding you.
They won't disappear!
I don't wanna be focused on, but because of
the focus lines, everyone focuses on me!
Kigu, let's have a coffee break and relax.
Someone gifted me some chocolates
the other day!
It's so sweet!
This is so calming!
It's not getting any better.
I'm totally relaxed!
Doesn't look that way whatsoever.
The focus lines just aren't fading.
Now it's like a manga by Shimamoto.
Ah, that style that makes even
the most insignificant lines overly dramatic.
Should we just call ourselves
the Rakugo Performers of Fire?
We could be members of a high school or university rakugo club,
working as hard as we can to fulfil our dreams.
Let's not. We're not fiery enough for that.
But this way we'll have to put up with
the focus lines no matter what we say!
Even in love...
You know, I think...
I love you!
I don't want to be in a suffocating love story like that!
That was the first time the focus lines
really matched the tension!
That doesn't make me happy!
There's no need to be angry...
I'm not angry! It just looks that way!
And it wouldn't just affect your love life.
It'd happen when you read poems,
cleaned your ears,
took a bath,
even your passing...
I don't want such a suffocating life!
It reminds me of Dezaki's work, so I quite like it.
Do you mean stuff like this?!
And this?!
And even this?!
Just give up.
You'll never have a background like
the one I'm about to show you.
I love you!
That's so unfair!
I want a background like that too!
Is that envy I hear?
That pink, cutesy style is really un-Marii, though.
The hell'd you just say?!
That it doesn't suit you.
I'll kick your ass!
Could it be that Marii can't get rid of hers either?
That's not funny!
Yep, it's still there.
Marii, you might have to live your whole life
in that pink, cutesy atmosphere!
What?!
Even if you get beaten up,
or you get run over by a car,
or something drops and hits you on the head,
or when you get snuffed out.
If that's supposed to be a joke,
I ain't laughing!
What kinda sick prank would it be
to drop something on my head?!
Well, I don't think you'd have too much trouble
living a pink, cutesy life like that.
The real problem here is Kigu.
Yeah!
Hey! I've got problems too!
You look perfectly at peace to me.
Anyway, the moral of the story is that
too much focus is never a good thing.
It's very risky how industries focus themselves in Tokyo,
or how companies focus on trading with only a limited set of partners.
Manga artists shouldn't enter into
exclusive contracts either.
So many artists have been ruined by
those unreasonable conditions!
When blame is focused on one person,
he becomes a scapegoat.
When power is focused in the hands of
one person, he becomes a dictator.
When unrequited love is focused too much
on one person, a stalker is born.
When sales focus too much on one show,
it leads to the decline of the industry.
So, Marii, do you understand now
how focus can be a problem?
Y-Yeah.
For instance, in prefab bathrooms where the tub
and the toilet are focused in one room,
you can't take a leak while someone's using the bath.
And you can't wash yourself off before getting in
the tub because the toilet will get wet too.
Yeah, I guess,
though that's a pretty boring, everyday example.
Hear that? You nailed it, Marii!
Anyway, the point is that instead of focusing,
we need to scatter!
We need you, Marii,
since you're so scatterbrained anyway!
Flattery will get you nowhere, y'know!
That wasn't flattery.
Oh, right! We should have separate dressing rooms, too!
If we're all in the same room and
some rioter breaks in, we're done for!
I'll ask the manager to give us separate rooms!
He said, "Who'd'ya think you are? Shinsuke?!"
Figures.
We'll just have to split up this room, then.
I'm so bored! I can't take it anymore!
Shut up. This is all for Kigu's sake.
Kigu, are you hanging in there?
Must be rough being so cramped up, ye?
It's okay!
This cramped space lets me focus like never before!
You mustn't focus!
You have to scatter your thoughts! Unwind!
Yeah! I'm focusing on unwinding!
You mustn't focus on it so intensely!
We're at the point where nothing we do
can help her anymore.
It all worked out, Kigu.
You're lucky they had focused treatment!
You're much less focused now.
So?
Can you cure me too?
I'm afraid that's beyond modern-day technology.
Don't pull my leg! Just cure me!
They sure get along well...
I'm terribly sorry, but I can't.
Don't give me that shit!
Yup.
Cure me, you goddamn quack!